[{"question":"Which of the following would be most likely to result in the creation of net financial value for a firm over the long term?","choices":["A. Reinvest a sizable portion of profits into R\u0026D, upgrades, and automation. ","  B. Get labor cost concessions from employees and distribute these gains to all stakeholders evenly. ","  C. Use increased market leverage to gain price concessions from suppliers. ","  D. Transfer all gains from the company to price discounts to consumers to gain market share. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"While squeezing excess costs out of an enterprise certainly has the potential to provide value to one or more stakeholders, it has to be done carefully. Any manager can reduce costs by reducing staff, cutting outlays for research or training, and delaying expenditures on equipment, but that's generally a recipe for immediate stagnation and eventual failure.  "},{"question":"A design engineer is creating a product that conforms to customer needs according to the supply chain's market intelligence. Which of the following is the most important secondary design element that the engineer should include in the design?","choices":["A. Has a lower price than the competitor's product ","  B. Can reach the market quickly ","  C. Can be sold for a positive return ","  D. Has more features than the competitor's product "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Serving the end-user customer is the primary driver of supply chain decisions. And, second, the organizations in the supply chain have to make a profit and stay in business to serve the customer. Design engineers, or better yet, design teams from across the network design products that are right for the end customer (and can be sold profitably).  "},{"question":"Selection of processes for improvement, according to quality methodology, should be done at which of the following levels?","choices":["A. Middle management ","  B. Teams comprising all levels from top management to regular employees ","  C. Top management ","  D. Regular employees (shop-floor labor, service workers, etc.) "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Quality initiatives are to be directed from the top down and implemented from the bottom up. Top management selects processes to improve. "},{"question":"Which of the following decisions should include a consideration of landed costs?","choices":["A. Real property acquisitions ","  B. Purchase of a component domestically or offshore ","  C. Transfer cost decisions ","  D. Warehouse location decision"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Landed costs include the purchase price of goods plus all other costs involved in getting the goods from the seller to the place where they will be used, such as a manufacturing facility. Landed cost provides a more accurate means of comparing the real costs of goods purchased in different geographic locations for use in the same facility.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is true advice for ensuring that one's supply chain is agile and flexible?","choices":["A. Mixing products to achieve full truckload shipments may be highly inefficient for high-dollar, lightweight items. ","  B. A manufacturer's trends in demand are best monitored through visibility with Tier 1 customers. ","  C. When designing products for maximum supply chain flexibility, putting customers on the design team will help create modular designs. ","  D. Cost efficiencies and velocity must take precedence in the supply chain such as always requiring that full truckloads are used. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Develop multiple supply chains that are appropriate to each product line. Some companies, to achieve those full truckload shipments, will mix products. While that's a good strategy for speeding up delivery of some products in the mix, it may be highly inefficient for others. Take the high-dollar, lightweight items out of the truck, train, or container and fly them to their destinations.  "},{"question":"As a general rule, instituting JIT in a manufacturing facility affects employees' jobs in which of the following ways?","choices":["A. Jobs are not a focus of change. ","  B. Job responsibilities expand. ","  C. Jobs become more specialized. ","  D. Job tasks are simplified. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"JIT generally requires employees who institute the process to take on more responsibility and learn new skills to become more flexible.  "},{"question":"A kaizen event would bring stakeholders together to design which of the following?","choices":["A. A new supply chain ","  B. A new product ","  C. A new corporate organization chart ","  D. A short-term project to improve a process of limited scale "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Kaizen events, also called kaizen blitzes, are used to design small-scale process improvement projects. They are particularly useful at the beginning of large-scale TQM projects to achieve a quick success and thus build credibility for the larger change initiative.  "},{"question":"Developing a JIT supply chain generally implies adopting which of the following strategies with suppliers?","choices":["A. Short-term contracts with revolving suppliers ","  B. Competitive bidding among the widest possible number of suppliers ","  C. Open bidding for flexibility supported by frequent inspection of incoming shipments ","  D. Long-term relationships with a limited number of suppliers "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"JIT supply chains generally thrive on long-term contracts with a limited number of suppliers who are willing to adapt JIT principles in their organizations. JIT systems make demands upon suppliers, so contracts need to apportion benefits fairly. Bidding wars among many potential suppliers don't tend to allow for these special relationships. Inspections take up time without adding value, and they are no substitute for trusting relationships with suppliers who have proven their ability to provide quality deliveries without inspection. "},{"question":"Members of a supply chain want to become demand-driven to reduce the bullwhip effect they are experiencing. Which of the following should each partner in the supply chain do?","choices":["A. Adopt new enterprise software systems that match current operating processes as closely as possible. ","  B. Improve their forecasting by basing the information on actual Tier 1 customer orders. ","  C. Reduce their contracted or owned transportation modes to match the new lowered transport needs. ","  D. Develop agility for more frequent changeovers, staffing, or process switching.  "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Demand-driven supply chains require access to real demand data along the chain (visibility), trust and collaboration (including changing processes as needed) among partners, and agility. There will be no room for long changeover times between runs of different products; therefore, equipment, processes, work center layouts, or staffing may have to change.  "},{"question":"In a supply chain context, measurable key performance indicators (KPIs) should be identified for which of the following?","choices":["A. Objectives of all key personnel in related functional areas ","  B. A limited number of top-level corporate and supply chain strategies ","  C. A limited number of essential supply chain processes ","  D. Performance of all products or services from a customer perspective"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Since measuring and monitoring all supply chain activities would be overwhelming, the more useful approach is to identify key performance indicators for a manageable number of supply chain strategic objectives. It is performance of the supply chain that KPIs measure, not employee or product performance.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is true of the Supply-Chain Operations Reference (SCOR) model?","choices":["A. SCOR applies to all product transactions (physical material and service). ","  B. SCOR applies to all areas of postdelivery customer support including returns. ","  C. SCOR applies to product development. ","  D. SCOR applies to demand generation in sales and marketing. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"SCOR can be applied to all product transactions, including services as well as material products. SCOR does not apply to any of the incorrect answers. (It does cover returns, but not all of postdelivery customer support.) SCOR is developed and maintained by the Supply-Chain Council.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is true of collaborative relationships in the supply chain?","choices":["A. Companies will always have a good reason to treat competitors in a different class from other types of supply chain members. ","  B. Incompatible hardware or legacy systems are no longer a barrier to collaboration due to new methods of integration. ","  C. The most technologically advanced supply chain partner will determine the level of supply chain development for the network. ","  D. Power-based relationships place long-term gains ahead of short-term results. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Competitors can often find a way to collaborate with each other for mutual gain, but since each competitor is actively trying to gain market share from the other, the relationships should be kept at arm's length to ensure fairness, and extra caution must be devoted to sharing information. Companies may pretend to embrace collaboration when they really only want access to information for their own benefit. Companies will always have a good reason to treat competitors warily.  "},{"question":"In a TQM initiative, the definition of \"defect\" is determined by which of the following?","choices":["A. Customer ","  B. Top management ","  C. Project team ","  D. Supply chain manager"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"According to TQM methodology, defects are defined from the customer's point of view.  "},{"question":"In an electrical generation supply chain, which of the following is a Tier 1 service supplier?","choices":["A. Electric power utility ","  B. Manufacturer connected to electric grid ","  C. Facility maintenance ","  D. Fuel supplier "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The electric power utility is the producer in this supply chain, with fuel suppliers and facility maintenance as Tier 1 suppliers, but only facility maintenance is a service supplier. The manufacturer on the grid is a customer. "},{"question":"A supply chain that produces and sells cigarettes using traditional forecasting at each stage has been experiencing the bullwhip effect. Which of the following has the strongest influence on this effect?","choices":["A. Announced promotions ","  B. Seasonal fluctuations ","  C. Safety stock ","  D. Excess supply liquidation "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Because cigarettes have relatively steady demand, the small variations in demand seen in the forecasting at the retail stage of the supply chain are padded by safety stock. Forecasting at each successive level uses the quantities ordered for forecasting rather than the actual sale amount, resulting in extremely variable demand at the other end of the supply chain. "},{"question":"In a JIT system, reduction in lot sizes may result in which of the following tradeoffs?","choices":["A. Increased cumulative setup time ","  B. Increased inventory accumulation ","  C. Increased holding costs ","  D. Increased handling costs"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"JIT reduces lot sizes to bring down inventory accumulation and the costs of holding and handling inventory. However, smaller lot sizes require more frequent orders, and that means more setups. As a consequence, JIT participants need to find ways to reduce setup time.  "},{"question":"According to SCOR Level 1 metrics, which of the following attributes of an organization is measured by the increase in production it can achieve and sustain in 30 days' time?","choices":["A. Sustainability ","  B. Reliability ","  C. Adaptability ","  D. Responsiveness"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"An organization's adaptability depends upon the degree to which it can increase and sustain production within 30 days after an unexpected change in the market. "},{"question":"With the theory of supply chain versus supply chain in competition, which of the following is true?","choices":["A. Industries with a small number of dominant suppliers are not ideal but are best coordinated using horizontal supply chains. ","  B. Use of common suppliers in competing chains may work to the advantage of both competitors at a risk of losing proprietary data. ","  C. When supply chains share suppliers, alignment of business strategies with supply chain strategies is facilitated. ","  D. Investments in suppliers shared by a competitor will increase the partnership with that supplier to the detriment of the competitor."],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Use of common suppliers in competing chains may work to the advantage of both competitors, but at the very least the situation invites conflict of interest. Insofar as manufacturers want to keep their designs and processes proprietary, they take a risk when they link up with competing component suppliers.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following approaches to production scheduling accurately incorporates the theory of constraints?","choices":["A. Speed up production in front of the bottleneck. ","  B. Decrease inventory at the front of the bottleneck. ","  C. Slow the process down to the bottleneck's speed. ","  D. Speed up production after the bottleneck. "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The theory of constraints focuses attention on slowest-moving part of a manufacturing process because it determines the maximum output of the process. Speeding up production before the constraint only produces an oversupply of inventory in front of the constraint, while speeding up the process after the constraint will result only in a lack of inventory after the constraint. Avoiding either of these problems requires running the process at the speed of the constraint. "},{"question":"The Japanese term \"kaizen\" refers to which of the following business processes?","choices":["A. Display cards used as production signals ","  B. Root cause ","  C. Interlocking business ownership ","  D. Continuous process improvement"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"\"Kaizen\" is the Japanese term for continuous improvement. The total quality management and continuous improvement ideas were brought to Japan from the United States and then returned here after the Japanese established their practical value in business.  "},{"question":"If customer demand is running at 500 units per day and available production time is 300 minutes per day, what is the takt time?","choices":["A. 6 seconds per unit ","  B. 16.7 second per unit ","  C. 36 seconds per unit ","  D. 1.67 minutes per unit "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"When a system is producing goods at takt time, the rate of goods produced exactly equals the rate of customer demand for the goods. It is calculated as available production divided by rate of customer demand.  "},{"question":"According to total quality theory, which of the following would be of primary importance to document during the analysis phase of a continuous improvement initiative?","choices":["A. Customer attitudes toward the product produced by the process ","  B. Staff-level views of the practical difficulties involved in carrying out the process ","  C. Executive-level positions on the importance of the process ","  D. A thorough, factual description of the process "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Quality theory emphasizes the importance of data; therefore, improvement initiatives begin with a complete, unbiased, factual description of the process.  "},{"question":"Which of the following cost-cutting measures will be most likely to create net financial value?","choices":["A. Eliminating retail locations and selling direct to customers ","  B. Eliminating partial truckload shipments and sending only full truckload shipments to retail outlets to save on shipping ","  C. Eliminating local storage facilities to save on warehousing costs ","  D. Eliminating inventory holding costs by having suppliers carry more inventory and ship on demand"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Only the correct answer removes an element of the supply chain without lowering the net value for the customer. Cost cutting must aim for net gains at the bottom line, and the incorrect answers all create new costs for other areas of the company or supply chain. If a leaner supply chain can deliver the same customer satisfaction with a greater profit, then cost cutting is fully justified. "},{"question":"Slip sheets can be used in place of which of the following?","choices":["A. Conveyers ","  B. Shipping containers ","  C. Pallets ","  D. Protective packaging "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Slip sheets are square plastic or corrugated sheets that can be used in place of pallets for transporting and storing inventory. "},{"question":"Which of the following is true of the processes or information technology (IT) that comprises supply chain management strategy?","choices":["A. A virtual network describes a network composed solely of IT linkages that a single entity runs. ","  B. Orders in the delivery chain should be pulled through by manufacturer capacity. ","  C. Having two supply chains helps when order timing and fulfillment is crucial in one supply chain but secondary in another. ","  D. The most significant barrier to the use of IT for collaboration and networking among firms is the cost of the IT. "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Order fulfillment is the delivery of the right product in the amounts at the right time and place and in the right condition. All of these \"rights\" should be determined in alignment with the supply chain strategy. Different types of order fulfillment processes are needed for different markets, which justifies having more than a single supply chain.  "},{"question":"If a firm locates a centralized procurement and processing facility in a low-tax foreign country, which of the following tax rates will apply to income generated at the facility?","choices":["A. The rate in the country of the headquarters ","  B. A compromise rate between the local and home country rates ","  C. The local country rate ","  D. A special international rate "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"In general, income streams are separately taxed, so a company can lower its global tax liability by moving facilities to low-tax regions. "},{"question":"Measures of success and incentives for a supply chain improvement initiative should be linked to which of the following?","choices":["A. Four quadrants of the balanced scorecard ","  B. Approval of top management ","  C. Outcome of the change initiative ","  D. Judgment of each participant's direct supervisor"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Change management suggests that success should be measured by mutually supporting indicators drawn from the four quadrants of the balanced scorecard (business process, the customer perspective, financial impact, and growth and learning). "},{"question":"Which of the following would a material be that was tightly linked to the company's brand equity even though it was basically a cheap but branded plastic toy that didn't require much quality?","choices":["A. Direct/core competency materials ","  B. Commodity materials ","  C. Bottleneck materials ","  D. Leveragable materials "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Leveragable materials are of high strategic importance but of low supply chain difficulty, so they are key areas where supply chain leverage can be applied to increase efficiencies and lower costs.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is the best way for top management to show commitment in cross-enterprise collaboration activities?","choices":["A. Focus on future strategy and delegate the task of maintaining the current focus on supply chain interactions. ","  B. Enforce collaborative agreements within their internal staff and discipline counterproductive actions. ","  C. Give frequent motivational speeches to internal and external managers. ","  D. Set the collaboration agreement and strictly enforce it without allowing the plan to be changed due to circumstances brought up by lower managers. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Top management commitment is demonstrated by actions and relationship building, not just words. Top management is responsible for keeping the focus on supply chain interactions and cannot abdicate this duty. If they do not provide proactive and enthusiastic support, their company will quickly fall back to its old ways of doing things. "},{"question":"According to the Supply-Chain Operations Reference (SCOR) model, if a refrigerator manufacturing company is at the center of the model, the supplier of materials to the sheet metal supplier has only which of the following processes to perform in relation to the manufacturer?","choices":["A. Make, source, deliver ","  B. Plan, deliver, return ","  C. Plan, source, make, deliver, return ","  D. Plan, source, return"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"From the perspective of the manufacturer, the supplier of metal to the sheet metal suppliers is on the second tier and may join in planning, but the manufacturer is otherwise concerned only with its ability to deliver and return goods as needed. SCOR is developed and maintained by the Supply-Chain Council.  "},{"question":"An organization sets a goal of reducing its lead time from four days to two days because another firm in its industry can offer two-day lead time. This is an example of which of the following?","choices":["A. Process benchmarking ","  B. Competitive benchmarking ","  C. Best-in-class benchmarking ","  D. Oliver Wight benchmarking"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Setting a competitor's performance on a process as your goal for the process in your organization is an example of competitive benchmarking.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is likely when a retailer of children's toys uses traditional forecasting to anticipate demand (as does their wholesaler) and adds some safety stock to orders both to smooth out the inevitable variations from the forecast and to replenish supplies after a promotion (not communicated to their suppliers) that the retailer plans to have to liquidate excess inventory?","choices":["A. High inventory holding costs for the retailer and high variability of demand for the wholesaler ","  B. Low inventory holding costs for the retailer and low variability of demand for the wholesaler ","  C. Low inventory holding costs for the retailer and high variability of demand for the wholesaler ","  D. High inventory holding costs for the retailer and low variability of demand for the wholesaler "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"The retailer will have high inventory holding costs even though they are having a promotion to liquidate excess inventory because they are perpetuating a cycle of overordering inventory due to uncertain demand forecasts. The wholesaler will have high variability of demand because traditional forecasting and lack of communication about promotions will cause each stage of the supply chain to compensate with greater safety stock. In short, the situation describes the bullwhip effect. "},{"question":"Which of the following usually implicitly exists in very simple supply chains such as a lemonade stand but must be explicitly managed in a complex supply chain of massive scale?","choices":["A. Supplier management ","  B. Collection and accounting for sales taxes ","  C. Collaboration between manufacturer and retailer ","  D. Compliance with government regulations"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A lemonade stand may not include any of the items in the incorrect answers, but it will generally have a good deal of collaborative planning in regard to demand forecasts and replenishment between the manufacturer and retailers (mother and children). Some of the problems that supply chain management strives to overcome are implicit in a simple model but must be explicitly managed in a complex supply chain because they arise as a direct result of the massive scale of modern supply chains.  "},{"question":"A sporting goods store sells some items at a low margin and steady demand, such as tennis balls, some items at a high margin and unpredictable demand, such as jogging outfits, and some items only during certain seasons, such as snowboarding equipment. Which of the following would provide the simplest and most effective supply chain solution for this company?","choices":["A. One supply chain for steady low-margin goods and one for exceptions ","  B. One supply chain for seasonal goods and one for the remaining goods ","  C. One supply chain for all goods ","  D. One supply chain for steady low-margin goods, one for unpredictable high-margin goods, and one for seasonal goods "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"According to Jonathan Byrnes, one supply chain is not enough; two, three, or more would be preferable. \"One size fits all\" supply chains may have been sufficient in the past, but new information technology makes it possible to have multiple, dynamic chains that can accommodate different product and information flows. Byrnes breaks products into three categories: staples, seasonal products, and fashion. Separating the flows into these categories can better allocate shipping, response time, and other resources to the appropriate areas.  "},{"question":"A firm that is always claiming it has the best processes and highest quality has recently suffered losses because even though they dictate these processes to their long-term Asian suppliers, several of them have, without any explanation, recently had a string of additional costs and quality problems. Which of the following would best help this firm resolve its problems?","choices":["A. Enforce the provisions of the suppliers' contracts through litigation. ","  B. Move production so that it is once again performed correctly in-house. ","  C. Find new suppliers who can follow the firm's process more closely. ","  D. Increase visibility with the suppliers and allow the suppliers to suggest processes that work for them.  "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Cultures tend to be egocentric and thus tend to resist external collaboration. They feel that their ways are the best ways of doing things and will often reject a different way without even considering it. Culture conflicts are increased when each company relies on its own sources of information and is unable to see the impact of its choices on other areas of the network. When companies don't see the negative results of their actions, they can't learn from their mistakes. Increasing visibility will correct some of these problems, but processes may need to be adaptable to the area in which they are performed, such as that litigation is seen as a betrayal of a relationship in many Asian countries. "},{"question":"Which of the following is a significant risk to consider when selecting a complex, enterprisewide software system?","choices":["A. Decreased synchronicity of functions automated by the software ","  B. Decreased velocity of processes because of software complexity ","  C. Lack of flexibility to improve processes automated by the software ","  D. Lack of future upgrade potential for the software "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The downside of complex, enterprisewide software systems is their potential to lock the enterprise into their assumptions and make process improvement difficult without simultaneous modifications to the complex system. The software would be chosen to increase synchronicity and velocity. Upgrades are generally part of the product and can always be purchased on a custom basis. "},{"question":"Which of the following categories would a precision spring for an expensive clock fit into if it was the key component that made the clock tell time reliably and needed to be of exacting dimensions and quality?","choices":["A. Direct/core competency material ","  B. Commodity material ","  C. Bottleneck material ","  D. Leveragable material"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A material that is both of high strategic importance and of high supply chain difficulty due to its complexity and need for low variance would be a core competency or direct material. These items must be produced in-house or through as close a partnership as possible.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is the technique of using visual signals to \"pull\" components through the manufacturing process?","choices":["A. JIT ","  B. Kanban ","  C. Six-sigma ","  D. Lean "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Kanban systems provide a visual signal to indicate when a workstation needs a component. Kanban is a Japanese term, and the system originated among Japanese manufacturers.  "},{"question":"Which of the following identifies the emphasis of the Global Reporting Initiative?","choices":["A. Monitoring terrorist activities ","  B. Enforcing UN trade sanctions ","  C. Policing corporate and supply chain activities ","  D. Developing and publishing environmentally sustainable trade practices "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"The Global Reporting Initiative (GRI) is an independent group of organizations, including corporations, that develops and publishes sustainable corporate trade practices in regard to such environmental concerns as emissions, energy and resource consumption, and waste. It works with the UN and is entirely voluntary. "},{"question":"A manager wants to move to the Supply-Chain Operations Reference (SCOR) model because their current strategy emphasizes reducing inventory costs by eliminating warehouses and increasing volume through sales promotions rather than innovation. Which of the following orientations is the manager moving from and which is he moving to by adopting SCOR?","choices":["A. From oriented to functional area to oriented to entity collaboration ","  B. From oriented to process to oriented to product or service ","  C. From oriented to functional area to oriented to process ","  D. From oriented to entity manufacturing to oriented to entity collaboration "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"SCOR organizes the model as a set of linked processes rather than as the links between specific entities. SCOR is developed and maintained by the Supply-Chain Council.  "},{"question":"A manager decides to source their key Just-in-Time (JIT) manufacturing goods from a local producer even though an overseas producer sells identical goods for less, even with the added cost of shipping. Which of the following is this manager most likely emphasizing?","choices":["A. Availability ","  B. Positive supply chain contribution ","  C. Quality ","  D. Affordability "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"The availability of the good is being emphasized because the manager needs a reliable supply of goods even if it costs more to get the good when it is needed for the JIT process.  "},{"question":"Which of the following phrases best characterizes the approach to change in total quality management initiatives?","choices":["A. Tight focus on the improvement of end-item features ","  B. \"Big step\" overhaul of whole systems ","  C. Short-term initiatives with precisely defined endpoints ","  D. Successive approximations of a perfected process "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Total quality management (TQM) is associated with the strategy of continuous improvement, which focuses on small-stem changes in processes (not products). Continuous process improvement (as it is also called) defines itself as \"the never-ending search for perfection,\" not short-term initiatives with definite endpoints. "},{"question":"Strategic objectives and KPIs for supplier relationship management would be developed during which stage of the SCOR model?","choices":["A. Planning ","  B. Making ","  C. Delivering ","  D. Sourcing  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Strategic objectives for all high-level processes are set in the planning stage.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is a benefit of a vertical supply chain rather than a lateral supply chain?","choices":["A. Improved business focus and expertise ","  B. Complete control and visibility of operations ","  C. Technology to handle the increased complexity ","  D. Economies of scale and scope for individual functions"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The benefit of vertical integration is control. A department or wholly owned subsidiary's operations are completely visible to the parent company (at least in theory) and can be synchronized with other company functions by directives from the top. "},{"question":"According to the functional and innovative product categories designated by Marshall L. Fisher, which of the following would be a proper performance indicator for a typical innovative product?","choices":["A. Inventory reduction ","  B. Aggressively reducing lead times ","  C. Design for maximum performance at minimal cost ","  D. High inventory turns "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The key performance indicators for each supply chain differ because of the product characteristics. Aggressively reducing lead times, for example, is appropriate for innovative products but would be irrelevant for functional products that can be manufactured and delivered on predictable schedules in high volumes.  "},{"question":"When measuring the success of a supply chain management strategy by the balanced scorecard approach, each key performance indicator (KPI) should be linked to which one of the following?","choices":["A. Internal business process improvement ","  B. Financials ","  C. Customer perspective ","  D. Employee learning and growth "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"All four measurement categories on the balanced scorecard (financial, customer, business process, and learning and growth) should be taken into account and balanced against one another, but all measures must ultimately contribute to the bottom line.  "},{"question":"According to the product categories designated by Marshall L. Fisher, which of the following categories would be the most likely classification for a product that has a six-month lead time?","choices":["A. Make-to-stock innovative product ","  B. Make-to-order functional product ","  C. Make-to-order innovative product ","  D. Make-to-stock functional product"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"An item with a very long lead time is likely a functional product that is not normally made-to-order but is in this case, such as a custom-sized pair of expensive boots. Innovative products stress aggressive reduction of lead times and generally have lead times of no more than two weeks. "},{"question":"In the SCOR model, which performance attribute is associated with the Level 1 metric, perfect order fulfillment?","choices":["A. Supply chain flexibility ","  B. Supply chain responsiveness ","  C. Supply chain reliability ","  D. Supply chain adaptability"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Reliability is the supply chain attribute measured by perfect order fulfillment. The customer considers the organization to be reliable if it delivers orders perfectly a high percentage of the time.  "},{"question":"What is the minimum level of enterprise evolution in which a firm might use a logistics supplier to integrate with external members and also internally combine warehousing and transportation activities to optimize cost versus customer service?","choices":["A. Stage 1: Multiple dysfunction ","  B. Stage 2: Semifunctional enterprise ","  C. Stage 3: Integrated enterprise ","  D. Stage 4: Extended enterprise "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A company at Stage 3 will make advances such as carrying out warehousing and transportation decisions in tandem to achieve the optimal balance of cost-effectiveness and customer service. At this point, the nucleus firm may begin to take a step toward integration with the external members of the chain by contracting with a logistics supplier.  "},{"question":"In SCOR Level 1, if you divide the sum of the cycle times for all orders delivered by the total number of orders delivered, you are using a metric for which of the following supply chain attributes?","choices":["A. Adaptability ","  B. Flexibility ","  C. Responsiveness ","  D. Reliability "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Average actual cycle time (sum of cycle times divided by number of deliveries) measures the responsiveness of the supply chain. It doesn't tell you if the deliveries were on time, which would be a reliability metric.  "},{"question":"Company A has installed supply chain management (SCM) software to achieve cross-functional integration. However, some members of the overall value chain that are not directly part of the supply chain itself have not provided the desired level of support for SCM initiatives. Which of the following departments is most likely to be the one lacking in support?","choices":["A. Human resources ","  B. Inbound logistics ","  C. Customer service ","  D. Marketing and sales "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Human resources is part of the value chain support activities that sustain the supply chain. The incorrect answers are all directly part of the supply chain. Managers from outside the supply chain often don't understand the requirements of supply chain management, can't distinguish value chain from supply chain, and consequently don't provide the SCM support required from their areas. "},{"question":"Which of the following scenarios is most likely to occur at the Stage 3 (integrated enterprise) level of supply chain evolution or higher?","choices":["A. Sales rep finds a market opportunity but is unable to bring it to the attention of new product development. ","  B. Dominant partner coerces others to force price concessions. ","  C. Manager provides a broad mission and backs it up with threats for nonconformance. ","  D. Warehouses are located near each market and have more than enough inventory to handle the next big sale"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"When firms first move past internal integration into external collaboration, the first collaboration can also be the last one if the arrangement fails to produce positive results for the weaker partner as well as for the channel master. Early manufacturer-supplier linkages, for example, were too often the result of coercion by the dominant partner, who was looking for guaranteed on-time delivery of quality items at a relatively low price.  "},{"question":"The Global Supply Chain Forum (GSCF) defines supply chain management as \"the integration of key business processes from end user through original suppliers that provides products, services, and information that add value for customers and other stakeholders.\" Which two processes are considered to constitute the core of supply chain management in the GSCF model?","choices":["A. Customer service management and manufacturing flow management ","  B. Order management and supplier relationship management ","  C. Demand management and supplier management ","  D. Customer and supplier management"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"At the heart of the GSCF model is the combination of customer relationship management and supplier relationship management, because these two processes create and manage the link between adjacent partners in the supply chain. "},{"question":"Which of the following results from having a firm's enterprise resources planning (ERP) software designed for automatic calculation of corporate taxes?","choices":["A. The software will most likely fail to take legally available deductions. ","  B. The firms will risk violating Sarbanes-Oxley (SOX) reporting requirements. ","  C. The software will earn a tax deduction based on its use in tax planning. ","  D. The firm will most likely underreport income."],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"ERP software can be programmed to determine the firm's exact tax liability and, at the same time, comply with Sarbanes-Oxley and earn a deduction for itself.  "},{"question":"JIT \"cells\" are laid out to accommodate which of the following?","choices":["A. One type of machine ","  B. One production process ","  C. One product family with similar manufacturing processes ","  D. One specialized type of worker"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Cells are arranged to allow for the most efficient production of a product family manufactured with similar production processes. Workers and machines are grouped to provide all the skills and equipment required for that product family in an efficiently arranged layout.  "},{"question":"The Sarbanes-Oxley Act (SOX) of 2002 focuses on which of the following areas?","choices":["A. Terrorism ","  B. Financial reporting and controls ","  C. Hazardous materials ","  D. Material content reporting"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Sarbanes-Oxley focuses on financial reporting and controls, including reporting on supply chain controls. Plans to respond to events such as terrorism are included in the reporting requirements, but they are not the focus of the legislation, which was drafted in response to corporate corruption "},{"question":"If a firm has 25 days of accounts payables outstanding and 30 days invested in inventory and their cash-to-cash cycle time is 80 days, how many days of accounts receivables do they have?","choices":["A. 105 days ","  B. 80 days ","  C. 75 days ","  D. 50 days "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The correct answer is 75 days: 80 days (cash to cash) + 25 days (payables) - 30 days (inventory) = 75 days receivables. The cash-to-cash cycle (or cash conversion cycle) is the number of days between the time a firm pays for raw materials and the time it receives payment for finished goods. The equation for calculating the cash-to-cash cycle is Cash-to-Cash Cycle Time = Average Inventory Collection Period + Average Receivables Processing Period - Average Payables Period; therefore, Days of Accounts Receivable = Cash-to-Cash Cycle Time + Days of Accounts Payable - Days of Inventory.  "},{"question":"Benchmarking is a tool used to carry out which function of a quality initiative?","choices":["A. Determine the roles in an initiative. ","  B. Assess process performance. ","  C. Analyze the steps in a process. ","  D. Implement a process improvement initiative."],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Benchmarks provide a point of comparison that allows a project team to assess the relative effectiveness of a process and set a goal for its improvement.  "},{"question":"When preparing for a potential business disruption, which of the following is valid advice for contingency planners?","choices":["A. Having extra stores of inventory is inadequate protection against a disruption in production. ","  B. After assessing all potential risks, ensure that each one has a plan for continued functioning regardless of the cost. ","  C. Create contingency plans for yourself and for your supply chain partners. ","  D. Contingency plans are the responsibility of each departmental manager in addition to their regular duties."],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Don't rely only on extra stores of inventory. There can never be enough of it to cover all potential problems, and it, too, is vulnerable. You need alternate processes to keep functioning after a disaster. "},{"question":"When setting supply chain strategy at a firm that isn't the nucleus firm, which of the following is the most important to focus on?","choices":["A. What's good for one's own firm ","  B. What's good for the nucleus firm ","  C. What's good for extended supply chain partners ","  D. What's good for the final customer "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"When it comes to supply chains, it's what's good for the final customer that counts, not what's good for the nucleus company or even what seems to be good for the supply chain itself. Supply chain management ought to be all about giving the final customer the right product at the right time and place for the right price. "},{"question":"According to the product categories designated by Marshall L. Fisher, which of the following categories would be the most likely classification for a product that has a six-month lead time?","choices":["A. Make-to-stock innovative product ","  B. Make-to-order functional product ","  C. Make-to-stock functional product ","  D. Make-to-order innovative product "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"An item with a very long lead time is likely a functional product that is not normally made-to-order but is in this case, such as a custom-sized pair of expensive boots. Innovative products stress aggressive reduction of lead times and generally have lead times of no more than two weeks.   "},{"question":"Which one of the following authorities has issued directives mandating reporting, reduction, and recycling of heavy metals in end-of-life electronics products?","choices":["A. Chinese government ","  B. United Nations ","  C. European Union ","  D. United States government"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The European Union has issued several directives regarding hazardous components of electronics products, including the Waste from Electronic Equipment directive (WEEE) and the directive restricting the use of heavy metals and retardants in electrical and electronic equipment (RoHS). "},{"question":"As a general rule, instituting JIT in a manufacturing facility affects employees' jobs in which of the following ways?","choices":["A. Job responsibilities expand. ","  B. Jobs are not a focus of change. ","  C. Jobs become more specialized. ","  D. Job tasks are simplified. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"JIT generally requires employees who institute the process to take on more responsibility and learn new skills to become more flexible.  "},{"question":"According to total quality theory, which of the following would be of primary importance to document during the analysis phase of a continuous improvement initiative?","choices":["A. A thorough, factual description of the process ","  B. Staff-level views of the practical difficulties involved in carrying out the process ","  C. Customer attitudes toward the product produced by the process ","  D. Executive-level positions on the importance of the process "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Quality theory emphasizes the importance of data; therefore, improvement initiatives begin with a complete, unbiased, factual description of the process.  "},{"question":"A channel master is finding that many of its current partners have begun finding ways of bypassing the firm, while others are performing redundant functions that cause unnecessary competition among supply chain members. Which of the following is a likely cause of this behavior?","choices":["A. Individual incentives conflicting with organizational goals ","  B. Working with competitors as peers ","  C. Weakest collaborative links becoming bottlenecks ","  D. Exploitation of power-based relationships "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Power-based relationships occur where a nucleus firm dictates the terms of the relationship to the other members. While its profits increase, other members of the network may suffer losses. When this occurs, the disadvantaged partners may rebel. Resistance may result in redundancy, loss of overall profitability for the chain, or an actual reversal of the power relationship.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is true of the people or the metrics involved in supply chain management?","choices":["A. Supply chain management must be the responsibility of a department-level manager who is equal in hierarchy to other department heads. ","  B. Current supply chain performance is better quantitatively benchmarked against the firm's desired performance than qualitatively benchmarked. ","  C. Performance must be measured by ratios of profitability and velocity, not by a checklist. ","  D. Supply chain strategy and control of the related processes depend on having people educated in functional rather than department thinking."],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Numbers (quantitative) generally provide the most convincing supporting evidence in the boardroom and investment analyst's office. If you're bragging about your cash-to-cash cycle, for instance, you might say, \"We've got it down from 50 days to 20, and that's below the industry average.\"  "},{"question":"Which one of the following tools provides a visual method for tracking process variance as part of an improvement initiative?","choices":["A. Pareto diagram ","  B. Process map ","  C. Oliver Wight checklist ","  D. Control chart "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"A control chart tracks process variance, allowing a project team to see quickly when defects have spiked to unacceptable levels. It can be used to manage as well as improve a process.  . "},{"question":"Which of the following is likely when a retailer of children's toys uses traditional forecasting to anticipate demand (as does their wholesaler) and adds some safety stock to orders both to smooth out the inevitable variations from the forecast and to replenish supplies after a promotion (not communicated to their suppliers) that the retailer plans to have to liquidate excess inventory?","choices":["A. Low inventory holding costs for the retailer and high variability of demand for the wholesaler ","  B. High inventory holding costs for the retailer and high variability of demand for the wholesaler ","  C. Low inventory holding costs for the retailer and low variability of demand for the wholesaler ","  D. High inventory holding costs for the retailer and low variability of demand for the wholesaler"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The retailer will have high inventory holding costs even though they are having a promotion to liquidate excess inventory because they are perpetuating a cycle of overordering inventory due to uncertain demand forecasts. The wholesaler will have high variability of demand because traditional forecasting and lack of communication about promotions will cause each stage of the supply chain to compensate with greater safety stock. In short, the situation describes the bullwhip effect.  "},{"question":"According to SCOR Level 1 metrics, which of the following attributes of an organization is measured by the increase in production it can achieve and sustain in 30 days' time?","choices":["A. Responsiveness ","  B. Sustainability ","  C. Adaptability ","  D. Reliability "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"An organization's adaptability depends upon the degree to which it can increase and sustain production within 30 days after an unexpected change in the market.   "},{"question":"A manager wants to move to the Supply-Chain Operations Reference (SCOR) model because their current strategy emphasizes reducing inventory costs by eliminating warehouses and increasing volume through sales promotions rather than innovation. Which of the following orientations is the manager moving from and which is he moving to by adopting SCOR?","choices":["A. From oriented to functional area to oriented to entity collaboration ","  B. From oriented to process to oriented to product or service ","  C. From oriented to functional area to oriented to process ","  D. From oriented to entity manufacturing to oriented to entity collaboration"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"SCOR organizes the model as a set of linked processes rather than as the links between specific entities. SCOR is developed and maintained by the Supply-Chain Council.   "},{"question":"Which of the following is true regarding supply chain organizations?","choices":["A. A raw material producer has no Tier 1 suppliers. ","  B. Service supplier considerations are important only after a manufacturing site has been selected. ","  C. Supply chains can loop back on themselves, making suppliers into customers. ","  D. There is a long but always finite number of tiers of suppliers in any supply chain."],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"No matter how far you travel toward the supply end of a supply chain, you will never run out of new tiers of suppliers. A coal mine may ship coal to a generating plant that supplies power to the manufacturer that produces a machine that is shipped to a distributor that sells mining equipment to the same mine that began the process: supply chains can double back on themselves.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is the technique of using visual signals to \"pull\" components through the manufacturing process?","choices":["A. JIT ","  B. Lean ","  C. Six-sigma ","  D. Kanban "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Kanban systems provide a visual signal to indicate when a workstation needs a component. Kanban is a Japanese term, and the system originated among Japanese manufacturers.  . "},{"question":"According to a noted Japanese approach to analyzing business process problems, why is it necessary to ask \"Why?\" as many as five times when seeking the cause of a process defect?","choices":["A. Most defects tend to have multiple causes, not just one. ","  B. First responses tend to name superficial causes rather than the root causes. ","  C. Most employees won't admit making an error the first few times they are asked. ","  D. There may be more than one cause for the defect. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"A Japanese method of root cause analysis referred to as \"Why? Why? Why? Why? Why?\" is based on the idea that it's not always easy to identify the root cause of a customer complaint or other process failure; the first suggestion is likely to be the result of bias or superficial analysis.   "},{"question":"A kaizen event would bring stakeholders together to design which of the following?","choices":["A. A new supply chain ","  B. A short-term project to improve a process of limited scale ","  C. A new corporate organization chart ","  D. A new product "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Kaizen events, also called kaizen blitzes, are used to design small-scale process improvement projects. They are particularly useful at the beginning of large-scale TQM projects to achieve a quick success and thus build credibility for the larger change initiative. "},{"question":"Which of the following is a true prerequisite for developing collaborative relationships central to supply chain strategy?","choices":["A. Deterrence-based arrangements such as aligning sales and management goals to collaborative objectives ","  B. The most advanced communications hardware and software ","  C. Sharing some benefits but none of the burdens of collaboration with partners ","  D. Auditable information exchange to share knowledge, not just data "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Auditable information exchange and technology for connectivity should allow sharing of knowledge, not mere data. The required technology itself may not have to be the most powerful, but it must be compatible to allow information exchange.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is a benefit of a vertical supply chain rather than a lateral supply chain?","choices":["A. Complete control and visibility of operations ","  B. Technology to handle the increased complexity ","  C. Economies of scale and scope for individual functions ","  D. Improved business focus and expertise "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"The benefit of vertical integration is control. A department or wholly owned subsidiary's operations are completely visible to the parent company (at least in theory) and can be synchronized with other company functions by directives from the top.  "},{"question":"If customer demand is running at 500 units per day and available production time is 300 minutes per day, what is the takt time?","choices":["A. 6 seconds per unit ","  B. 16.7 second per unit ","  C. 36 seconds per unit ","  D. 1.67 minutes per unit "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"When a system is producing goods at takt time, the rate of goods produced exactly equals the rate of customer demand for the goods. It is calculated as available production divided by rate of customer demand.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is the best way for top management to show commitment in cross-enterprise collaboration activities?","choices":["A. Set the collaboration agreement and strictly enforce it without allowing the plan to be changed due to circumstances brought up by lower managers. ","  B. Give frequent motivational speeches to internal and external managers. ","  C. Enforce collaborative agreements within their internal staff and discipline counterproductive actions. ","  D. Focus on future strategy and delegate the task of maintaining the current focus on supply chain interactions."],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Top management commitment is demonstrated by actions and relationship building, not just words. Top management is responsible for keeping the focus on supply chain interactions and cannot abdicate this duty. If they do not provide proactive and enthusiastic support, their company will quickly fall back to its old ways of doing things.  "},{"question":"Which of the following usually implicitly exists in very simple supply chains such as a lemonade stand but must be explicitly managed in a complex supply chain of massive scale?","choices":["A. Compliance with government regulations ","  B. Collection and accounting for sales taxes ","  C. Collaboration between manufacturer and retailer ","  D. Supplier management "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A lemonade stand may not include any of the items in the incorrect answers, but it will generally have a good deal of collaborative planning in regard to demand forecasts and replenishment between the manufacturer and retailers (mother and children). Some of the problems that supply chain management strives to overcome are implicit in a simple model but must be explicitly managed in a complex supply chain because they arise as a direct result of the massive scale of modern supply chains.  "},{"question":"The Japanese term \"kaizen\" refers to which of the following business processes?","choices":["A. Interlocking business ownership ","  B. Continuous process improvement ","  C. Display cards used as production signals ","  D. Root cause "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"\"Kaizen\" is the Japanese term for continuous improvement. The total quality management and continuous improvement ideas were brought to Japan from the United States and then returned here after the Japanese established their practical value in business.  "},{"question":"The developers of the balanced scorecard approach to performance were concerned that traditional metrics placed too much emphasis on which of the following considerations?","choices":["A. Past financial performance ","  B. Current profitability ","  C. Future performance objectives ","  D. Customer complaints"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"The developers of the balanced scorecard, Robert S. Kaplan and David Norton, believed that the traditional reliance on financial measures of performance placed too much emphasis on the past and too little on the present and future and, in addition, ignored other types of measures that contribute to success.  "},{"question":"Slip sheets can be used in place of which of the following?","choices":["A. Shipping containers ","  B. Pallets ","  C. Conveyers ","  D. Protective packaging "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Slip sheets are square plastic or corrugated sheets that can be used in place of pallets for transporting and storing inventory.  "},{"question":"A supply chain that produces and sells cigarettes using traditional forecasting at each stage has been experiencing the bullwhip effect. Which of the following has the strongest influence on this effect?","choices":["A. Excess supply liquidation ","  B. Announced promotions ","  C. Safety stock ","  D. Seasonal fluctuations "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Because cigarettes have relatively steady demand, the small variations in demand seen in the forecasting at the retail stage of the supply chain are padded by safety stock. Forecasting at each successive level uses the quantities ordered for forecasting rather than the actual sale amount, resulting in extremely variable demand at the other end of the supply chain.  "},{"question":"In a supply chain context, measurable key performance indicators (KPIs) should be identified for which of the following?","choices":["A. Performance of all products or services from a customer perspective ","  B. A limited number of top-level corporate and supply chain strategies ","  C. Objectives of all key personnel in related functional areas ","  D. A limited number of essential supply chain processes "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Since measuring and monitoring all supply chain activities would be overwhelming, the more useful approach is to identify key performance indicators for a manageable number of supply chain strategic objectives. It is performance of the supply chain that KPIs measure, not employee or product performance.  "},{"question":"What enforcement authority does the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission bring to its role in regard to the provisions of the Sarbanes-Oxley Act?","choices":["A. Authority to impose jail sentences on executives ","  B. Investigative authority only ","  C. Authority to bring civil court actions ","  D. Authority to bring cases to criminal court "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The SEC has the authority to bring civil suits against corporations and individuals it believes to be out of compliance with securities regulations, including the Sarbanes-Oxley Act. It can refer cases to law enforcement agencies, which can institute criminal proceedings.  "},{"question":"Which of the following phrases best characterizes the approach to change in total quality management initiatives?","choices":["A. Short-term initiatives with precisely defined endpoints ","  B. Tight focus on the improvement of end-item features ","  C. \"Big step\" overhaul of whole systems ","  D. Successive approximations of a perfected process "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Total quality management (TQM) is associated with the strategy of continuous improvement, which focuses on small-stem changes in processes (not products). Continuous process improvement (as it is also called) defines itself as \"the never-ending search for perfection,\" not short-term initiatives with definite endpoints.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is true of the processes or information technology (IT) that comprises supply chain management strategy?","choices":["A. A virtual network describes a network composed solely of IT linkages that a single entity runs. ","  B. Orders in the delivery chain should be pulled through by manufacturer capacity. ","  C. The most significant barrier to the use of IT for collaboration and networking among firms is the cost of the IT. ","  D. Having two supply chains helps when order timing and fulfillment is crucial in one supply chain but secondary in another. "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Order fulfillment is the delivery of the right product in the amounts at the right time and place and in the right condition. All of these \"rights\" should be determined in alignment with the supply chain strategy. Different types of order fulfillment processes are needed for different markets, which justifies having more than a single supply chain.  "},{"question":"Which of the following identifies the emphasis of the Global Reporting Initiative?","choices":["A. Enforcing UN trade sanctions ","  B. Monitoring terrorist activities ","  C. Developing and publishing environmentally sustainable trade practices ","  D. Policing corporate and supply chain activities "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The Global Reporting Initiative (GRI) is an independent group of organizations, including corporations, that develops and publishes sustainable corporate trade practices in regard to such environmental concerns as emissions, energy and resource consumption, and waste. It works with the UN and is entirely voluntary.  "},{"question":"Consider a simplified supply chain in which Lucy sells psychiatric advice from a booth to her classmates for five cents. Subconsciously, she gets her information from her psychiatrist parent and from her pastor. Which of the following are Tier 2 suppliers in this model?","choices":["A. Lucy ","  B. Parent/pastor ","  C. Higher education/seminary ","  D. There are no Tier 2 suppliers in this situation."],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Lucy's parent and pastor are the Tier 1 suppliers to Lucy, the service producer. They owe their supply of information to either higher education or a seminary, so these sources are the Tier 2 suppliers.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is true advice for ensuring that one's supply chain is agile and flexible?","choices":["A. Mixing products to achieve full truckload shipments may be highly inefficient for high-dollar, lightweight items. ","  B. When designing products for maximum supply chain flexibility, putting customers on the design team will help create modular designs. ","  C. A manufacturer's trends in demand are best monitored through visibility with Tier 1 customers. ","  D. Cost efficiencies and velocity must take precedence in the supply chain such as always requiring that full truckloads are used."],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Develop multiple supply chains that are appropriate to each product line. Some companies, to achieve those full truckload shipments, will mix products. While that's a good strategy for speeding up delivery of some products in the mix, it may be highly inefficient for others. Take the high-dollar, lightweight items out of the truck, train, or container and fly them to their destinations. "},{"question":"An organization sets a goal of reducing its lead time from four days to two days because another firm in its industry can offer two-day lead time. This is an example of which of the following?","choices":["A. Competitive benchmarking ","  B. Oliver Wight benchmarking ","  C. Best-in-class benchmarking ","  D. Process benchmarking"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Setting a competitor's performance on a process as your goal for the process in your organization is an example of competitive benchmarking.  "},{"question":"Which of the following members of the firm are typically involved in continuous process improvement initiatives?","choices":["A. Executives ","  B. All members of the firm, including executives, managers, and labor ","  C. Shop-floor workers and supervisors ","  D. Middle managers"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Continuous process improvement requires the participation of everyone involved in the targeted processes, the executives who are accountable for the process, the managers responsible for directing it, and the workers who carry it out.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following constitutes the range of acceptable variability on a six-sigma control chart?","choices":["A. Zero variability ","  B. Mean defects plus/minus 3 sigmas ","  C. Mean defects plus 6 sigmas ","  D. Mean defects plus/minus 6 sigmas "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"The acceptable range of variability is the number of defects within a range of six sigmas (standard deviations) above and below the mean number of defects. The chart helps control the variability in a process.  "},{"question":"Developing a JIT supply chain generally implies adopting which of the following strategies with suppliers?","choices":["A. Short-term contracts with revolving suppliers ","  B. Open bidding for flexibility supported by frequent inspection of incoming shipments ","  C. Long-term relationships with a limited number of suppliers ","  D. Competitive bidding among the widest possible number of suppliers "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"JIT supply chains generally thrive on long-term contracts with a limited number of suppliers who are willing to adapt JIT principles in their organizations. JIT systems make demands upon suppliers, so contracts need to apportion benefits fairly. Bidding wars among many potential suppliers don't tend to allow for these special relationships. Inspections take up time without adding value, and they are no substitute for trusting relationships with suppliers who have proven their ability to provide quality deliveries without inspection. "},{"question":"Six-sigma emphasizes the importance of training at which of the following levels?","choices":["A. Top management only ","  B. All levels ","  C. Customer-facing employees only ","  D. All management levels "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Six-sigma emphasizes the importance of all process participants, from top management to basic service or shop-floor employees, and it includes training at all levels.  "},{"question":"Which of the following continuous improvement methodologies focuses on reduction of defects to statistical insignificance?","choices":["A. Just-in-Time (JIT) ","  B. Lean ","  C. Six-sigma ","  D. Theory of constraints"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Six-sigma seeks to limit defects to no more than 3.4 per million opportunities. Of course, no initiative sets out to increase defects, but six-sigma makes defect reduction its specific objective.  "},{"question":"Which of the following decisions should include a consideration of landed costs?","choices":["A. Warehouse location decisions ","  B. Transfer cost decisions ","  C. Real property acquisitions ","  D. Purchase of a component domestically or offshore "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Landed costs include the purchase price of goods plus all other costs involved in getting the goods from the seller to the place where they will be used, such as a manufacturing facility. Landed cost provides a more accurate means of comparing the real costs of goods purchased in different geographic locations for use in the same facility.  "},{"question":"Which of the following categories would a precision spring for an expensive clock fit into if it was the key component that made the clock tell time reliably and needed to be of exacting dimensions and quality?","choices":["A. Direct/core competency material ","  B. Bottleneck material ","  C. Leveragable material ","  D. Commodity material"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A material that is both of high strategic importance and of high supply chain difficulty due to its complexity and need for low variance would be a core competency or direct material. These items must be produced in-house or through as close a partnership as possible.  "},{"question":"When measuring the success of a supply chain management strategy by the balanced scorecard approach, each key performance indicator (KPI) should be linked to which one of the following?","choices":["A. Customer perspective ","  B. Internal business process improvement ","  C. Financials ","  D. Employee learning and growth"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"All four measurement categories on the balanced scorecard (financial, customer, business process, and learning and growth) should be taken into account and balanced against one another, but all measures must ultimately contribute to the bottom line. "},{"question":"Which of the following cost-cutting measures will be most likely to create net financial value?","choices":["A. Eliminating local storage facilities to save on warehousing costs ","  B. Eliminating inventory holding costs by having suppliers carry more inventory and ship on demand ","  C. Eliminating retail locations and selling direct to customers ","  D. Eliminating partial truckload shipments and sending only full truckload shipments to retail outlets to save on shipping "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Only the correct answer removes an element of the supply chain without lowering the net value for the customer. Cost cutting must aim for net gains at the bottom line, and the incorrect answers all create new costs for other areas of the company or supply chain. If a leaner supply chain can deliver the same customer satisfaction with a greater profit, then cost cutting is fully justified. "},{"question":"Which of the following could be a key performance indicator (KPI) for replenishment?","choices":["A. Inventory turns ","  B. Introduction lead time ","  C. Order fill rate ","  D. Volume growth"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Order fill rate provides a measure of the success of the key process of replenishment. A high fill rate indicates good performance.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is true regarding a supply chain?","choices":["A. Cash flows downstream while materials flow upstream. ","  B. Information flows upstream, downstream, and between network members and external entities. ","  C. An electrical power producer that powers a manufacturer's plant is downstream from the manufacturer. ","  D. Services may be part of a manufacturing supply chain but do not have a distinct supply chain themselves."],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The information in a supply chain flows upstream toward the supplier end, downstream toward the customer end, and also back and forth within the entities and between the chain and external entities, such as governments, markets, and competitors.  "},{"question":"In a JIT system, reduction in lot sizes may result in which of the following tradeoffs?","choices":["A. Increased inventory accumulation ","  B. Increased holding costs ","  C. Increased handling costs ","  D. Increased cumulative setup time"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"JIT reduces lot sizes to bring down inventory accumulation and the costs of holding and handling inventory. However, smaller lot sizes require more frequent orders, and that means more setups. As a consequence, JIT participants need to find ways to reduce setup time.  "},{"question":"A sporting goods store sells some items at a low margin and steady demand, such as tennis balls, some items at a high margin and unpredictable demand, such as jogging outfits, and some items only during certain seasons, such as snowboarding equipment. Which of the following would provide the simplest and most effective supply chain solution for this company?","choices":["A. One supply chain for steady low-margin goods and one for exceptions ","  B. One supply chain for all goods ","  C. One supply chain for seasonal goods and one for the remaining goods ","  D. One supply chain for steady low-margin goods, one for unpredictable high-margin goods, and one for seasonal goods "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"According to Jonathan Byrnes, one supply chain is not enough; two, three, or more would be preferable. \"One size fits all\" supply chains may have been sufficient in the past, but new information technology makes it possible to have multiple, dynamic chains that can accommodate different product and information flows. Byrnes breaks products into three categories: staples, seasonal products, and fashion. Separating the flows into these categories can better allocate shipping, response time, and other resources to the appropriate areas.  "},{"question":"A manager decides to source their key Just-in-Time (JIT) manufacturing goods from a local producer even though an overseas producer sells identical goods for less, even with the added cost of shipping. Which of the following is this manager most likely emphasizing?","choices":["A. Affordability ","  B. Positive supply chain contribution ","  C. Quality ","  D. Availability "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"The availability of the good is being emphasized because the manager needs a reliable supply of goods even if it costs more to get the good when it is needed for the JIT process.  "},{"question":"Strategic objectives and KPIs for supplier relationship management would be developed during which stage of the SCOR model?","choices":["A. Sourcing ","  B. Making ","  C. Planning ","  D. Delivering "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Strategic objectives for all high-level processes are set in the planning stage.  "},{"question":"If a firm locates a centralized procurement and processing facility in a low-tax foreign country, which of the following tax rates will apply to income generated at the facility?","choices":["A. A compromise rate between the local and home country rates ","  B. A special international rate ","  C. The local country rate ","  D. The rate in the country of the headquarters "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"In general, income streams are separately taxed, so a company can lower its global tax liability by moving facilities to low-tax regions.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following approaches to production scheduling accurately incorporates the theory of constraints?","choices":["A. Speed up production after the bottleneck. ","  B. Decrease inventory at the front of the bottleneck. ","  C. Speed up production in front of the bottleneck. ","  D. Slow the process down to the bottleneck's speed."],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"The theory of constraints focuses attention on slowest-moving part of a manufacturing process because it determines the maximum output of the process. Speeding up production before the constraint only produces an oversupply of inventory in front of the constraint, while speeding up the process after the constraint will result only in a lack of inventory after the constraint. Avoiding either of these problems requires running the process at the speed of the constraint.   "},{"question":"A focus on quality, affordability, or availability indicates a focus on which of the following?","choices":["A. Social value ","  B. Financial value ","  C. Customer value ","  D. Collaborative value"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Depending upon the market being served, a supply chain may be managed with an eye to delivering one or more of the following values to its end customers: quality, affordability, availability, or service. "},{"question":"A nucleus firm in the banking industry uses independent brokers to market new stock issues and has been successful in this channel. After investing some profits in the firm itself, they choose to reward their stockholders by distributing all remaining profits in a special dividend even though independent brokers are prohibited from owning these shares. Which of the following has this firm forgotten to account for in its creation of financial value?","choices":["A. Gains must be fairly distributed among stakeholders. ","  B. Tradeoffs must not be self-defeating. ","  C. Independent brokers should be rewarded through social incentives and reminded that shareholders must come first. ","  D. It takes money to make money. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Possibly the most common mistake in this regard is to send all cost savings all the way to the consumers' end of the chain, which in this case is the shareholders. And perhaps most challenging of all in a lateral supply chain is the need for productive sharing of any financial gains. As noted earlier, a powerful nucleus firm can gather in the benefits of an alteration in the placement of inventory (or any other process change) at the expense of other stakeholders such as the independent brokers. "},{"question":"With the theory of supply chain versus supply chain in competition, which of the following is true?","choices":["A. Investments in suppliers shared by a competitor will increase the partnership with that supplier to the detriment of the competitor. ","  B. Industries with a small number of dominant suppliers are not ideal but are best coordinated using horizontal supply chains. ","  C. When supply chains share suppliers, alignment of business strategies with supply chain strategies is facilitated. ","  D. Use of common suppliers in competing chains may work to the advantage of both competitors at a risk of losing proprietary data"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Use of common suppliers in competing chains may work to the advantage of both competitors, but at the very least the situation invites conflict of interest. Insofar as manufacturers want to keep their designs and processes proprietary, they take a risk when they link up with competing component suppliers.  "},{"question":"Many Japanese companies use keiretsu to avoid which of the following?","choices":["A. The semifunctional enterprise stage (Stage 2) ","  B. Lacking specialization and focus in a network of independent firms ","  C. Needing to abandon the control and full integration of a vertical environment ","  D. The challenges of synchronizing a network of independent firms "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Keiretsu is an intermediate form of integration that differs from vertical integration or horizontal integration in that suppliers and customers are not completely independent but instead own significant stakes in one another. This helps the network of firms be more willing to consider each other's needs.  "},{"question":"Selection of processes for improvement, according to quality methodology, should be done at which of the following levels?","choices":["A. Regular employees (shop-floor labor, service workers, etc.) ","  B. Top management ","  C. Teams comprising all levels from top management to regular employees ","  D. Middle management "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Quality initiatives are to be directed from the top down and implemented from the bottom up. Top management selects processes to improve.  "},{"question":"Volume growth is a key performance indicator for which of the following?","choices":["A. Product merchandizing ","  B. Customer service ","  C. Supply chain variability ","  D. Replenishment "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Volume growth measures the success of merchandizing efforts.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is a significant risk to consider when selecting a complex, enterprisewide software system?","choices":["A. Decreased velocity of processes because of software complexity ","  B. Decreased synchronicity of functions automated by the software ","  C. Lack of flexibility to improve processes automated by the software ","  D. Lack of future upgrade potential for the software  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The downside of complex, enterprisewide software systems is their potential to lock the enterprise into their assumptions and make process improvement difficult without simultaneous modifications to the complex system. The software would be chosen to increase synchronicity and velocity. Upgrades are generally part of the product and can always be purchased on a custom basis.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is among the Global Supply Chain Forum's eight essential supply chain management processes?","choices":["A. Production ","  B. Purchasing ","  C. Logistics ","  D. Order fulfillment"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Order fulfillment is one of the GSCF's essential processes. The other answers identify activities that contribute to the supply chain processes, but they are not among the processes identified in the GSCF's model. "},{"question":"Measures of success and incentives for a supply chain improvement initiative should be linked to which of the following?","choices":["A. Four quadrants of the balanced scorecard ","  B. Judgment of each participant's direct supervisor ","  C. Approval of top management ","  D. Outcome of the change initiative "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Change management suggests that success should be measured by mutually supporting indicators drawn from the four quadrants of the balanced scorecard (business process, the customer perspective, financial impact, and growth and learning).  "},{"question":"The antiterrorism measures developed by the Customs-Trade Partnership against Terrorism (C-TPAT) apply to which of the following entities?","choices":["A. C-TPAT corporate participants ","  B. All U.S. importers ","  C. All U.S. exporters ","  D. All domestic and foreign firms involved in U.S. supply chains "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Participation in the Customs-Trade Partnership against Terrorism is voluntary, and compliance with its regulations is required only of participants. Failure to comply can lead to suspension of privileges or cancellation of partnership.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is true of collaborative relationships in the supply chain?","choices":["A. The most technologically advanced supply chain partner will determine the level of supply chain development for the network. ","  B. Companies will always have a good reason to treat competitors in a different class from other types of supply chain members. ","  C. Power-based relationships place long-term gains ahead of short-term results. ","  D. Incompatible hardware or legacy systems are no longer a barrier to collaboration due to new methods of integration. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Competitors can often find a way to collaborate with each other for mutual gain, but since each competitor is actively trying to gain market share from the other, the relationships should be kept at arm's length to ensure fairness, and extra caution must be devoted to sharing information. Companies may pretend to embrace collaboration when they really only want access to information for their own benefit. Companies will always have a good reason to treat competitors warily.  "},{"question":"A design engineer is creating a product that conforms to customer needs according to the supply chain's market intelligence. Which of the following is the most important secondary design element that the engineer should include in the design?","choices":["A. Has a lower price than the competitor's product ","  B. Can reach the market quickly ","  C. Has more features than the competitor's product ","  D. Can be sold for a positive return"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Serving the end-user customer is the primary driver of supply chain decisions. And, second, the organizations in the supply chain have to make a profit and stay in business to serve the customer. Design engineers, or better yet, design teams from across the network design products that are right for the end customer (and can be sold profitably).  "},{"question":"Which of the following would be most likely to result in the creation of net financial value for a firm over the long term?","choices":["A. Transfer all gains from the company to price discounts to consumers to gain market share. ","  B. Reinvest a sizable portion of profits into R\u0026D, upgrades, and automation. ","  C. Get labor cost concessions from employees and distribute these gains to all stakeholders evenly. ","  D. Use increased market leverage to gain price concessions from suppliers."],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"While squeezing excess costs out of an enterprise certainly has the potential to provide value to one or more stakeholders, it has to be done carefully. Any manager can reduce costs by reducing staff, cutting outlays for research or training, and delaying expenditures on equipment, but that's generally a recipe for immediate stagnation and eventual failure.  "},{"question":"Which of the following scenarios is most likely to occur at the Stage 3 (integrated enterprise) level of supply chain evolution or higher?","choices":["A. Sales rep finds a market opportunity but is unable to bring it to the attention of new product development. ","  B. Warehouses are located near each market and have more than enough inventory to handle the next big sale. ","  C. Manager provides a broad mission and backs it up with threats for nonconformance. ","  D. Dominant partner coerces others to force price concessions. "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"When firms first move past internal integration into external collaboration, the first collaboration can also be the last one if the arrangement fails to produce positive results for the weaker partner as well as for the channel master. Early manufacturer-supplier linkages, for example, were too often the result of coercion by the dominant partner, who was looking for guaranteed on-time delivery of quality items at a relatively low price.  "},{"question":"A firm that is always claiming it has the best processes and highest quality has recently suffered losses because even though they dictate these processes to their long-term Asian suppliers, several of them have, without any explanation, recently had a string of additional costs and quality problems. Which of the following would best help this firm resolve its problems?","choices":["A. Increase visibility with the suppliers and allow the suppliers to suggest processes that work for them. ","  B. Find new suppliers who can follow the firm's process more closely. ","  C. Move production so that it is once again performed correctly in-house. ","  D. Enforce the provisions of the suppliers' contracts through litigation."],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Cultures tend to be egocentric and thus tend to resist external collaboration. They feel that their ways are the best ways of doing things and will often reject a different way without even considering it. Culture conflicts are increased when each company relies on its own sources of information and is unable to see the impact of its choices on other areas of the network. When companies don't see the negative results of their actions, they can't learn from their mistakes. Increasing visibility will correct some of these problems, but processes may need to be adaptable to the area in which they are performed, such as that litigation is seen as a betrayal of a relationship in many Asian countries.  "},{"question":"Which of the following best describes the potential for different quality methods to work together?","choices":["A. JIT and lean are compatible with each other but not with six-sigma. ","  B. JIT, lean, and six-sigma work best when combined. ","  C. JIT and six-sigma are compatible with each other but not with lean. ","  D. Six-sigma and lean are compatible with each other but not with JIT. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The three quality-based systems are mutually compatible and give the best results when combined to eliminate wasted materials, wasted time, defects, and variability.  "},{"question":"Which of the following would a material be that was tightly linked to the company's brand equity even though it was basically a cheap but branded plastic toy that didn't require much quality?","choices":["A. Direct/core competency materials ","  B. Bottleneck materials ","  C. Leveragable materials ","  D. Commodity materials "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Leveragable materials are of high strategic importance but of low supply chain difficulty, so they are key areas where supply chain leverage can be applied to increase efficiencies and lower costs. "},{"question":"Which of the following is true of the Supply-Chain Operations Reference (SCOR) model?","choices":["A. SCOR applies to demand generation in sales and marketing. ","  B. SCOR applies to product development. ","  C. SCOR applies to all product transactions (physical material and service). ","  D. SCOR applies to all areas of postdelivery customer support including returns."],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"SCOR can be applied to all product transactions, including services as well as material products. SCOR does not apply to any of the incorrect answers. (It does cover returns, but not all of postdelivery customer support.) SCOR is developed and maintained by the Supply-Chain Council.  "},{"question":"In the SCOR model, which performance attribute is associated with the Level 1 metric, perfect order fulfillment?","choices":["A. Supply chain responsiveness ","  B. Supply chain reliability ","  C. Supply chain flexibility ","  D. Supply chain adaptability "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Reliability is the supply chain attribute measured by perfect order fulfillment. The customer considers the organization to be reliable if it delivers orders perfectly a high percentage of the time.  "},{"question":"In an electrical generation supply chain, which of the following is a Tier 1 service supplier?","choices":["A. Fuel supplier ","  B. Electric power utility ","  C. Manufacturer connected to electric grid ","  D. Facility maintenance"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"The electric power utility is the producer in this supply chain, with fuel suppliers and facility maintenance as Tier 1 suppliers, but only facility maintenance is a service supplier. The manufacturer on the grid is a customer.  "},{"question":"In the Global Supply Chain Forum supply chain management model, which of the following combine to create a link between adjacent partners and form a context for the other six processes?","choices":["A. Manufacturing flow management and order fulfillment ","  B. Product development and commercialization and manufacturing flow management ","  C. Supplier relationship management and demand management ","  D. Customer relationship management and supplier relationship management "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Customer relationship management (CRM) and supplier relationship management (SRM) are at the heart of the eight processes. Their combination creates and manages the link between adjacent partners in the chain and provides the context for the other processes.  "},{"question":"Members of a supply chain want to become demand-driven to reduce the bullwhip effect they are experiencing. Which of the following should each partner in the supply chain do?","choices":["A. Develop agility for more frequent changeovers, staffing, or process switching. ","  B. Adopt new enterprise software systems that match current operating processes as closely as possible. ","  C. Reduce their contracted or owned transportation modes to match the new lowered transport needs. ","  D. Improve their forecasting by basing the information on actual Tier 1 customer orders."],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Demand-driven supply chains require access to real demand data along the chain (visibility), trust and collaboration (including changing processes as needed) among partners, and agility. There will be no room for long changeover times between runs of different products; therefore, equipment, processes, work center layouts, or staffing may have to change.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is a tool that helps visually identify the 20 percent of causes responsible for 80 percent of problems (using those percentages as approximations)?","choices":["A. Process map ","  B. Pareto diagram ","  C. Checklist ","  D. Focus group"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"A Pareto diagram applies the Pareto principle that 80 percent of results tend to be the result of 20 percent of causes. The diagram helps visually distinguish the small number of causes that result in the largest number of process flaws. Focus groups are useful in gathering customer complaints: the flaws in the diagram.  "},{"question":"China has restricted U.S. imports of wood pallets for which of the following reasons?","choices":["A. Lack of Chinese wood content in pallets ","  B. Excessive weight of soft wood pallets ","  C. Risk of insect pests in the wood ","  D. Pallets weren't being properly recycled "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"China, the European Union, and other destinations have placed restrictions on wood pallets coming from the United States because of possible infestation by harmful insects. "},{"question":"Benchmarking is a tool used to carry out which function of a quality initiative?","choices":["A. Implement a process improvement initiative. ","  B. Analyze the steps in a process. ","  C. Assess process performance. ","  D. Determine the roles in an initiative."],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Benchmarks provide a point of comparison that allows a project team to assess the relative effectiveness of a process and set a goal for its improvement.  "},{"question":"A design engineer is creating a product that conforms to customer needs according to the supply chain's market intelligence. Which of the following is the most important secondary design element that the engineer should include in the design?","choices":["A. Has more features than the competitor's product ","  B. Has a lower price than the competitor's product ","  C. Can be sold for a positive return ","  D. Can reach the market quickly"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Serving the end-user customer is the primary driver of supply chain decisions. And, second, the organizations in the supply chain have to make a profit and stay in business to serve the customer. Design engineers, or better yet, design teams from across the network design products that are right for the end customer (and can be sold profitably).  "},{"question":"Which of the following is among the Global Supply Chain Forum's eight essential supply chain management processes?","choices":["A. Purchasing ","  B. Logistics ","  C. Production ","  D. Order fulfillment "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Order fulfillment is one of the GSCF's essential processes. The other answers identify activities that contribute to the supply chain processes, but they are not among the processes identified in the GSCF's model.  "},{"question":"Corporate participants in C-TPAT (Customs-Trade Partnership against Terrorism) receive which one of the following benefits?","choices":["A. Increased protection for overseas shipments ","  B. Exemption from border inspections ","  C. Reduced tariffs ","  D. Greater reliance on self-policing "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Corporate partners in C-TPAT benefit from a greater emphasis on self-policing rather than customs verification and other benefits. "},{"question":"Which of the following phrases best characterizes the approach to change in total quality management initiatives?","choices":["A. Short-term initiatives with precisely defined endpoints ","  B. Successive approximations of a perfected process ","  C. Tight focus on the improvement of end-item features ","  D. \"Big step\" overhaul of whole systems "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Total quality management (TQM) is associated with the strategy of continuous improvement, which focuses on small-stem changes in processes (not products). Continuous process improvement (as it is also called) defines itself as \"the never-ending search for perfection,\" not short-term initiatives with definite endpoints.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is likely when a retailer of children's toys uses traditional forecasting to anticipate demand (as does their wholesaler) and adds some safety stock to orders both to smooth out the inevitable variations from the forecast and to replenish supplies after a promotion (not communicated to their suppliers) that the retailer plans to have to liquidate excess inventory?","choices":["A. High inventory holding costs for the retailer and low variability of demand for the wholesaler ","  B. High inventory holding costs for the retailer and high variability of demand for the wholesaler ","  C. Low inventory holding costs for the retailer and low variability of demand for the wholesaler ","  D. Low inventory holding costs for the retailer and high variability of demand for the wholesaler "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The retailer will have high inventory holding costs even though they are having a promotion to liquidate excess inventory because they are perpetuating a cycle of overordering inventory due to uncertain demand forecasts. The wholesaler will have high variability of demand because traditional forecasting and lack of communication about promotions will cause each stage of the supply chain to compensate with greater safety stock. In short, the situation describes the bullwhip effect.  "},{"question":"Measures of success and incentives for a supply chain improvement initiative should be linked to which of the following?","choices":["A. Four quadrants of the balanced scorecard ","  B. Judgment of each participant's direct supervisor ","  C. Outcome of the change initiative ","  D. Approval of top management "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Change management suggests that success should be measured by mutually supporting indicators drawn from the four quadrants of the balanced scorecard (business process, the customer perspective, financial impact, and growth and learning).  "},{"question":"A nucleus firm in the banking industry uses independent brokers to market new stock issues and has been successful in this channel. After investing some profits in the firm itself, they choose to reward their stockholders by distributing all remaining profits in a special dividend even though independent brokers are prohibited from owning these shares. Which of the following has this firm forgotten to account for in its creation of financial value?","choices":["A. It takes money to make money. ","  B. Tradeoffs must not be self-defeating. ","  C. Independent brokers should be rewarded through social incentives and reminded that shareholders must come first. ","  D. Gains must be fairly distributed among stakeholders"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Possibly the most common mistake in this regard is to send all cost savings all the way to the consumers' end of the chain, which in this case is the shareholders. And perhaps most challenging of all in a lateral supply chain is the need for productive sharing of any financial gains. As noted earlier, a powerful nucleus firm can gather in the benefits of an alteration in the placement of inventory (or any other process change) at the expense of other stakeholders such as the independent brokers.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is true of the Supply-Chain Operations Reference (SCOR) model?","choices":["A. SCOR applies to product development. ","  B. SCOR applies to demand generation in sales and marketing. ","  C. SCOR applies to all product transactions (physical material and service). ","  D. SCOR applies to all areas of postdelivery customer support including returns."],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"SCOR can be applied to all product transactions, including services as well as material products. SCOR does not apply to any of the incorrect answers. (It does cover returns, but not all of postdelivery customer support.) SCOR is developed and maintained by the Supply-Chain Council.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is a benefit of a vertical supply chain rather than a lateral supply chain?","choices":["A. Improved business focus and expertise ","  B. Economies of scale and scope for individual functions ","  C. Complete control and visibility of operations ","  D. Technology to handle the increased complexity "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The benefit of vertical integration is control. A department or wholly owned subsidiary's operations are completely visible to the parent company (at least in theory) and can be synchronized with other company functions by directives from the top.  "},{"question":"Which of the following results from having a firm's enterprise resources planning (ERP) software designed for automatic calculation of corporate taxes?","choices":["A. The software will earn a tax deduction based on its use in tax planning. ","  B. The firm will most likely underreport income. ","  C. The firms will risk violating Sarbanes-Oxley (SOX) reporting requirements. ","  D. The software will most likely fail to take legally available deductions."],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"ERP software can be programmed to determine the firm's exact tax liability and, at the same time, comply with Sarbanes-Oxley and earn a deduction for itself.  "},{"question":"Where on a balanced scorecard would you enter a seminar on financial management for nonfinancial managers developed for the sales managers?","choices":["A. Financial perspective ","  B. Innovation and learning perspective ","  C. Business process perspective ","  D. Customer perspective "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Regardless of the content of the seminar, training belongs in the innovation and learning quadrant of the balanced scorecard.  "},{"question":"When setting supply chain strategy at a firm that isn't the nucleus firm, which of the following is the most important to focus on?","choices":["A. What's good for the nucleus firm ","  B. What's good for one's own firm ","  C. What's good for extended supply chain partners ","  D. What's good for the final customer"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"When it comes to supply chains, it's what's good for the final customer that counts, not what's good for the nucleus company or even what seems to be good for the supply chain itself. Supply chain management ought to be all about giving the final customer the right product at the right time and place for the right price.  "},{"question":"In the SCOR model, which performance attribute is associated with the Level 1 metric, perfect order fulfillment?","choices":["A. Supply chain adaptability ","  B. Supply chain reliability ","  C. Supply chain responsiveness ","  D. Supply chain flexibility "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Reliability is the supply chain attribute measured by perfect order fulfillment. The customer considers the organization to be reliable if it delivers orders perfectly a high percentage of the time.  "},{"question":"The antiterrorism measures developed by the Customs-Trade Partnership against Terrorism (C-TPAT) apply to which of the following entities?","choices":["A. All domestic and foreign firms involved in U.S. supply chains ","  B. C-TPAT corporate participants ","  C. All U.S. importers ","  D. All U.S. exporters"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Participation in the Customs-Trade Partnership against Terrorism is voluntary, and compliance with its regulations is required only of participants. Failure to comply can lead to suspension of privileges or cancellation of partnership.  "},{"question":"A value stream map is associated with which of the following improvement methods?","choices":["A. Lean ","  B. Focus groups ","  C. Job redesign ","  D. Six-sigma "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Value stream maps are paper-and-pencil sketches of the steps in a process overlaid with supporting information flows. They are used in lean projects to identify non-value-adding steps for elimination. (The first map shows all steps; a second map shows the process with all non-value-adding steps eliminated.)  "},{"question":"If a firm locates a centralized procurement and processing facility in a low-tax foreign country, which of the following tax rates will apply to income generated at the facility?","choices":["A. A special international rate ","  B. The local country rate ","  C. A compromise rate between the local and home country rates ","  D. The rate in the country of the headquarters "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"In general, income streams are separately taxed, so a company can lower its global tax liability by moving facilities to low-tax regions.  "},{"question":"A channel master is finding that many of its current partners have begun finding ways of bypassing the firm, while others are performing redundant functions that cause unnecessary competition among supply chain members. Which of the following is a likely cause of this behavior?","choices":["A. Working with competitors as peers ","  B. Exploitation of power-based relationships ","  C. Weakest collaborative links becoming bottlenecks ","  D. Individual incentives conflicting with organizational goals "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Power-based relationships occur where a nucleus firm dictates the terms of the relationship to the other members. While its profits increase, other members of the network may suffer losses. When this occurs, the disadvantaged partners may rebel. Resistance may result in redundancy, loss of overall profitability for the chain, or an actual reversal of the power relationship.  "},{"question":"JIT \"cells\" are laid out to accommodate which of the following?","choices":["A. One product family with similar manufacturing processes ","  B. One specialized type of worker ","  C. One type of machine ","  D. One production process"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Cells are arranged to allow for the most efficient production of a product family manufactured with similar production processes. Workers and machines are grouped to provide all the skills and equipment required for that product family in an efficiently arranged layout.  "},{"question":"Which of the following illustrates an emphasis on the affordability aspect of customer value?","choices":["A. A cement-mixing tub of greater durability and flexibility than similar offerings ","  B. No-hassle, no-negotiation sales price on new cars at a dealership ","  C. A luxury boat priced lower than other luxury boats of similar size and feature ","  D. Same-day delivery of goods via courier-to-air-to-courier "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Affordability does not refer solely to discount goods but to goods that have a price at the lower end of an appropriate price level for the value received.  "},{"question":"According to SCOR Level 1 metrics, which of the following attributes of an organization is measured by the increase in production it can achieve and sustain in 30 days' time?","choices":["A. Adaptability ","  B. Responsiveness ","  C. Reliability ","  D. Sustainability "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"An organization's adaptability depends upon the degree to which it can increase and sustain production within 30 days after an unexpected change in the market.  "},{"question":"A sporting goods store sells some items at a low margin and steady demand, such as tennis balls, some items at a high margin and unpredictable demand, such as jogging outfits, and some items only during certain seasons, such as snowboarding equipment. Which of the following would provide the simplest and most effective supply chain solution for this company?","choices":["A. One supply chain for steady low-margin goods, one for unpredictable high-margin goods, and one for seasonal goods ","  B. One supply chain for seasonal goods and one for the remaining goods ","  C. One supply chain for all goods ","  D. One supply chain for steady low-margin goods and one for exceptions "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"According to Jonathan Byrnes, one supply chain is not enough; two, three, or more would be preferable. \"One size fits all\" supply chains may have been sufficient in the past, but new information technology makes it possible to have multiple, dynamic chains that can accommodate different product and information flows. Byrnes breaks products into three categories: staples, seasonal products, and fashion. Separating the flows into these categories can better allocate shipping, response time, and other resources to the appropriate areas.  "},{"question":"According to research by Rice and Hoppe, the theory that supply chains of companies allied as partners in supply networks may compete directly with other similar supply chain networks in reality exists only with which of the following?","choices":["A. Individual companies such as an automobile manufacturer based on their supply chain management capabilities ","  B. Horizontal supply chains such as PC sales ","  C. Channel masters such as retail consumer good giants ","  D. Vertical supply chains such as poultry sellers "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Groups of companies allied as partners in supply networks will compete with other groups of companies allied in supply networks. The networks will be distinct from one another in all ways. The head-to-head supply chain competitors tend toward the vertically integrated company rather than the extended enterprise. The fashion and poultry industries are suggested as arenas in which supply chains compete with supply chains.  "},{"question":"A midsize manufacturing firm works with a large retailer as its primary customer and has several sources of supply for each of its key materials. The firm is trying to align its supply chain strategy with corporate strategy. Which of the following must be the primary consideration when this firm is setting corporate strategy?","choices":["A. Setting the firm's own strategic objectives to leverage a more profitable margin from their customers ","  B. The objectives of the ultimate end customer regardless of what any intermediaries may interject ","  C. Alignment with the strategic objectives of their suppliers to generate long-term stability of supply ","  D. Alignment with the retailer's corporate strategy to holistically maintain a profitable relationship "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Because the retailer in this situation appears to be the nucleus firm, alignment of the retailer's corporate strategy with the firm's own corporate strategy must take precedence over other considerations.  "},{"question":"When defining roles for each party in a collaboration, how should these interactions be structured and why?","choices":["A. Reciprocal interdependence; redundancy of effort is minimized. ","  B. Sequential interdependence; both parties become dependent upon one another. ","  C. Sequential interdependence; redundancy of effort is minimized. ","  D. Reciprocal interdependence; both parties become dependent upon one another. "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Conflicts can occur when defining roles for each party if the roles make one party more dependent upon another than they wish to be. To alleviate this common problem, networks should avoid sequential interdependence, in which the second party cannot begin work until the first party is done; instead, they should establish reciprocal independence, in which the exchange of tasks and services occurs in both directions. "},{"question":"When measuring the success of a supply chain management strategy by the balanced scorecard approach, each key performance indicator (KPI) should be linked to which one of the following?","choices":["A. Employee learning and growth ","  B. Customer perspective ","  C. Internal business process improvement ","  D. Financials"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"All four measurement categories on the balanced scorecard (financial, customer, business process, and learning and growth) should be taken into account and balanced against one another, but all measures must ultimately contribute to the bottom line.  "},{"question":"The Japanese term \"kaizen\" refers to which of the following business processes?","choices":["A. Root cause ","  B. Interlocking business ownership ","  C. Continuous process improvement ","  D. Display cards used as production signals"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"\"Kaizen\" is the Japanese term for continuous improvement. The total quality management and continuous improvement ideas were brought to Japan from the United States and then returned here after the Japanese established their practical value in business.  "},{"question":"The Level 2 SCOR measure for cost of goods sold includes which of the following supply chain costs?","choices":["A. Costs of sourcing and making ","  B. Costs of sourcing, making, and delivering ","  C. Costs of planning, sourcing, making, and delivering ","  D. Total costs of planning, sourcing, making, delivering, and returning "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"The SCOR Level 2 metric for cost of goods sold includes all the costs related to the five SCOR supply chain processes (plan, source, make, deliver, and return).  "},{"question":"The developers of the balanced scorecard approach to performance were concerned that traditional metrics placed too much emphasis on which of the following considerations?","choices":["A. Current profitability ","  B. Past financial performance ","  C. Future performance objectives ","  D. Customer complaints"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The developers of the balanced scorecard, Robert S. Kaplan and David Norton, believed that the traditional reliance on financial measures of performance placed too much emphasis on the past and too little on the present and future and, in addition, ignored other types of measures that contribute to success. "},{"question":"Many Japanese companies use keiretsu to avoid which of the following?","choices":["A. Needing to abandon the control and full integration of a vertical environment ","  B. The semifunctional enterprise stage (Stage 2) ","  C. Lacking specialization and focus in a network of independent firms ","  D. The challenges of synchronizing a network of independent firms "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Keiretsu is an intermediate form of integration that differs from vertical integration or horizontal integration in that suppliers and customers are not completely independent but instead own significant stakes in one another. This helps the network of firms be more willing to consider each other's needs.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is the technique of using visual signals to \"pull\" components through the manufacturing process?","choices":["A. Six-sigma ","  B. JIT ","  C. Kanban ","  D. Lean "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Kanban systems provide a visual signal to indicate when a workstation needs a component. Kanban is a Japanese term, and the system originated among Japanese manufacturers.  "},{"question":"According to the functional and innovative product categories designated by Marshall L. Fisher, which of the following would be a proper performance indicator for a typical innovative product?","choices":["A. Aggressively reducing lead times ","  B. Inventory reduction ","  C. High inventory turns ","  D. Design for maximum performance at minimal cost"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"The key performance indicators for each supply chain differ because of the product characteristics. Aggressively reducing lead times, for example, is appropriate for innovative products but would be irrelevant for functional products that can be manufactured and delivered on predictable schedules in high volumes.  "},{"question":"According to the product categories designated by Marshall L. Fisher, which of the following categories would be the most likely classification for a product that has a six-month lead time?","choices":["A. Make-to-order innovative product ","  B. Make-to-stock innovative product ","  C. Make-to-stock functional product ","  D. Make-to-order functional product"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"An item with a very long lead time is likely a functional product that is not normally made-to-order but is in this case, such as a custom-sized pair of expensive boots. Innovative products stress aggressive reduction of lead times and generally have lead times of no more than two weeks.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is true of supply chains?","choices":["A. Supply chains run in only one direction, toward the customer. ","  B. Competition is an outside stakeholder to a supply chain that threatens or energizes it. ","  C. Supply chain processes are entirely contained within each entity within a supply chain. ","  D. There are two flows that can be engineered in a chain, products and cash. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Competitors affect the functioning of a supply chain in more ways than one: They can threaten or energize the chain. Sometimes competing businesses directly foster each other's growth by participation in trade associations and joint ventures. Whenever a competitor creates an improved product or business process, the entire marketplace is enriched by the new ideas.  "},{"question":"When an enterprise buys new technology, which one of the following should be the primary selection criterion?","choices":["A. Appropriateness to supply chain strategy ","  B. Features representing the very latest designs ","  C. Processing power ","  D. Low cost "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Strategy should govern choice of technology. Features and processing power should be right for the strategic needs of the enterprise. Low cost is not always the right cost in any purchase. Even a small amount of money is wasted if it doesn't purchase what you need.  "},{"question":"The Sarbanes-Oxley Act (SOX) of 2002 focuses on which of the following areas?","choices":["A. Hazardous materials ","  B. Terrorism ","  C. Financial reporting and controls ","  D. Material content reporting "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Sarbanes-Oxley focuses on financial reporting and controls, including reporting on supply chain controls. Plans to respond to events such as terrorism are included in the reporting requirements, but they are not the focus of the legislation, which was drafted in response to corporate corruption.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is the best way for top management to show commitment in cross-enterprise collaboration activities?","choices":["A. Give frequent motivational speeches to internal and external managers. ","  B. Focus on future strategy and delegate the task of maintaining the current focus on supply chain interactions. ","  C. Enforce collaborative agreements within their internal staff and discipline counterproductive actions. ","  D. Set the collaboration agreement and strictly enforce it without allowing the plan to be changed due to circumstances brought up by lower managers."],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Top management commitment is demonstrated by actions and relationship building, not just words. Top management is responsible for keeping the focus on supply chain interactions and cannot abdicate this duty. If they do not provide proactive and enthusiastic support, their company will quickly fall back to its old ways of doing things.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is true regarding supply chain organizations?","choices":["A. There is a long but always finite number of tiers of suppliers in any supply chain. ","  B. A raw material producer has no Tier 1 suppliers. ","  C. Supply chains can loop back on themselves, making suppliers into customers. ","  D. Service supplier considerations are important only after a manufacturing site has been selected"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"No matter how far you travel toward the supply end of a supply chain, you will never run out of new tiers of suppliers. A coal mine may ship coal to a generating plant that supplies power to the manufacturer that produces a machine that is shipped to a distributor that sells mining equipment to the same mine that began the process: supply chains can double back on themselves.  "},{"question":"Which of the following cost-cutting measures will be most likely to create net financial value?","choices":["A. Eliminating retail locations and selling direct to customers ","  B. Eliminating local storage facilities to save on warehousing costs ","  C. Eliminating partial truckload shipments and sending only full truckload shipments to retail outlets to save on shipping ","  D. Eliminating inventory holding costs by having suppliers carry more inventory and ship on demand"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Only the correct answer removes an element of the supply chain without lowering the net value for the customer. Cost cutting must aim for net gains at the bottom line, and the incorrect answers all create new costs for other areas of the company or supply chain. If a leaner supply chain can deliver the same customer satisfaction with a greater profit, then cost cutting is fully justified.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is true of the processes or information technology (IT) that comprises supply chain management strategy?","choices":["A. The most significant barrier to the use of IT for collaboration and networking among firms is the cost of the IT. ","  B. A virtual network describes a network composed solely of IT linkages that a single entity runs. ","  C. Having two supply chains helps when order timing and fulfillment is crucial in one supply chain but secondary in another. ","  D. Orders in the delivery chain should be pulled through by manufacturer capacity. "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Order fulfillment is the delivery of the right product in the amounts at the right time and place and in the right condition. All of these \"rights\" should be determined in alignment with the supply chain strategy. Different types of order fulfillment processes are needed for different markets, which justifies having more than a single supply chain.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is a true prerequisite for developing collaborative relationships central to supply chain strategy?","choices":["A. Auditable information exchange to share knowledge, not just data ","  B. Deterrence-based arrangements such as aligning sales and management goals to collaborative objectives ","  C. Sharing some benefits but none of the burdens of collaboration with partners ","  D. The most advanced communications hardware and software "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Auditable information exchange and technology for connectivity should allow sharing of knowledge, not mere data. The required technology itself may not have to be the most powerful, but it must be compatible to allow information exchange.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following constitutes the range of acceptable variability on a six-sigma control chart?","choices":["A. Zero variability ","  B. Mean defects plus/minus 3 sigmas ","  C. Mean defects plus 6 sigmas ","  D. Mean defects plus/minus 6 sigmas"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"The acceptable range of variability is the number of defects within a range of six sigmas (standard deviations) above and below the mean number of defects. The chart helps control the variability in a process.  "},{"question":"According to total quality theory, which of the following would be of primary importance to document during the analysis phase of a continuous improvement initiative?","choices":["A. Staff-level views of the practical difficulties involved in carrying out the process ","  B. A thorough, factual description of the process ","  C. Executive-level positions on the importance of the process ","  D. Customer attitudes toward the product produced by the process "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Quality theory emphasizes the importance of data; therefore, improvement initiatives begin with a complete, unbiased, factual description of the process.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following approaches to production scheduling accurately incorporates the theory of constraints?","choices":["A. Speed up production after the bottleneck. ","  B. Speed up production in front of the bottleneck. ","  C. Slow the process down to the bottleneck's speed. ","  D. Decrease inventory at the front of the bottleneck. "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The theory of constraints focuses attention on slowest-moving part of a manufacturing process because it determines the maximum output of the process. Speeding up production before the constraint only produces an oversupply of inventory in front of the constraint, while speeding up the process after the constraint will result only in a lack of inventory after the constraint. Avoiding either of these problems requires running the process at the speed of the constraint.  "},{"question":"In an electrical generation supply chain, which of the following is a Tier 1 service supplier?","choices":["A. Facility maintenance ","  B. Electric power utility ","  C. Fuel supplier ","  D. Manufacturer connected to electric grid "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"The electric power utility is the producer in this supply chain, with fuel suppliers and facility maintenance as Tier 1 suppliers, but only facility maintenance is a service supplier. The manufacturer on the grid is a customer.  "},{"question":"A manager wants to move to the Supply-Chain Operations Reference (SCOR) model because their current strategy emphasizes reducing inventory costs by eliminating warehouses and increasing volume through sales promotions rather than innovation. Which of the following orientations is the manager moving from and which is he moving to by adopting SCOR?","choices":["A. From oriented to process to oriented to product or service ","  B. From oriented to functional area to oriented to process ","  C. From oriented to functional area to oriented to entity collaboration ","  D. From oriented to entity manufacturing to oriented to entity collaboration "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"SCOR organizes the model as a set of linked processes rather than as the links between specific entities. SCOR is developed and maintained by the Supply-Chain Council.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following tools provides a visual method for tracking process variance as part of an improvement initiative?","choices":["A. Control chart ","  B. Pareto diagram ","  C. Process map ","  D. Oliver Wight checklist "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A control chart tracks process variance, allowing a project team to see quickly when defects have spiked to unacceptable levels. It can be used to manage as well as improve a process.  "},{"question":"Which of the following continuous improvement methodologies focuses on reduction of defects to statistical insignificance?","choices":["A. Six-sigma ","  B. Theory of constraints ","  C. Just-in-Time (JIT) ","  D. Lean"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Six-sigma seeks to limit defects to no more than 3.4 per million opportunities. Of course, no initiative sets out to increase defects, but six-sigma makes defect reduction its specific objective.  "},{"question":"Company A has installed supply chain management (SCM) software to achieve cross-functional integration. However, some members of the overall value chain that are not directly part of the supply chain itself have not provided the desired level of support for SCM initiatives. Which of the following departments is most likely to be the one lacking in support?","choices":["A. Marketing and sales ","  B. Human resources ","  C. Inbound logistics ","  D. Customer service "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Human resources is part of the value chain support activities that sustain the supply chain. The incorrect answers are all directly part of the supply chain. Managers from outside the supply chain often don't understand the requirements of supply chain management, can't distinguish value chain from supply chain, and consequently don't provide the SCM support required from their areas.  "},{"question":"When the APICS Dictionary, 11th edition, refers to a supply chain as a \"global network,\" which of the following correctly indicates what could comprise this network?","choices":["A. Entities and processes of any size or configuration ","  B. Only international entities or global processes ","  C. Processes of any size or configuration but only international entities ","  D. Entities of any size or configuration but not processes "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"The global network referred to in the definition of a supply chain comprises a network of both entities and processes (the engineered flow). A supply chain doesn't have to be global.  "},{"question":"A manager decides to source their key Just-in-Time (JIT) manufacturing goods from a local producer even though an overseas producer sells identical goods for less, even with the added cost of shipping. Which of the following is this manager most likely emphasizing?","choices":["A. Positive supply chain contribution ","  B. Availability ","  C. Affordability ","  D. Quality "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The availability of the good is being emphasized because the manager needs a reliable supply of goods even if it costs more to get the good when it is needed for the JIT process.  "},{"question":"What is the minimum level of enterprise evolution in which a firm might use a logistics supplier to integrate with external members and also internally combine warehousing and transportation activities to optimize cost versus customer service?","choices":["A. Stage 1: Multiple dysfunction ","  B. Stage 2: Semifunctional enterprise ","  C. Stage 3: Integrated enterprise ","  D. Stage 4: Extended enterprise"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A company at Stage 3 will make advances such as carrying out warehousing and transportation decisions in tandem to achieve the optimal balance of cost-effectiveness and customer service. At this point, the nucleus firm may begin to take a step toward integration with the external members of the chain by contracting with a logistics supplier.  "},{"question":"Which of the following decisions should include a consideration of landed costs?","choices":["A. Warehouse location decisions ","  B. Transfer cost decisions ","  C. Real property acquisitions ","  D. Purchase of a component domestically or offshore "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Landed costs include the purchase price of goods plus all other costs involved in getting the goods from the seller to the place where they will be used, such as a manufacturing facility. Landed cost provides a more accurate means of comparing the real costs of goods purchased in different geographic locations for use in the same facility. "},{"question":"A kaizen event would bring stakeholders together to design which of the following?","choices":["A. A new supply chain ","  B. A new product ","  C. A new corporate organization chart ","  D. A short-term project to improve a process of limited scale "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Kaizen events, also called kaizen blitzes, are used to design small-scale process improvement projects. They are particularly useful at the beginning of large-scale TQM projects to achieve a quick success and thus build credibility for the larger change initiative. "},{"question":"Six-sigma emphasizes the importance of training at which of the following levels?","choices":["A. Customer-facing employees only ","  B. Top management only ","  C. All management levels ","  D. All levels "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Six-sigma emphasizes the importance of all process participants, from top management to basic service or shop-floor employees, and it includes training at all levels.  "},{"question":"Slip sheets can be used in place of which of the following?","choices":["A. Pallets ","  B. Protective packaging ","  C. Shipping containers ","  D. Conveyers"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Slip sheets are square plastic or corrugated sheets that can be used in place of pallets for transporting and storing inventory.  "},{"question":"In a TQM initiative, the definition of \"defect\" is determined by which of the following?","choices":["A. Supply chain manager ","  B. Top management ","  C. Project team ","  D. Customer"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"According to TQM methodology, defects are defined from the customer's point of view.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is true of contracts for partnerships?","choices":["A. Contracts should always be used in the negotiation process to keep relationships true to the agreement. ","  B. Cultural differences in contracts and problem resolution styles should be a primary consideration when arranging formal contracts. ","  C. Contracts should be fixed at the start of the relationship because alterations are difficult to enact between multiple parties. ","  D. Courts can become involved in conflicts in most Asian countries without long-term detriment to a relationship. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Contracts, policies and procedures, and informal conflict resolution must be sensitive to cultural differences. While courts can become involved in conflicts in the United States without long-term detriment, the opposite is true in most Asian countries.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following authorities has issued directives mandating reporting, reduction, and recycling of heavy metals in end-of-life electronics products?","choices":["A. United States government ","  B. Chinese government ","  C. United Nations ","  D. European Union"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"The European Union has issued several directives regarding hazardous components of electronics products, including the Waste from Electronic Equipment directive (WEEE) and the directive restricting the use of heavy metals and retardants in electrical and electronic equipment (RoHS). "},{"question":"Which of the following members of the firm are typically involved in continuous process improvement initiatives?","choices":["A. Middle managers ","  B. Executives ","  C. All members of the firm, including executives, managers, and labor ","  D. Shop-floor workers and supervisors "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Continuous process improvement requires the participation of everyone involved in the targeted processes, the executives who are accountable for the process, the managers responsible for directing it, and the workers who carry it out.  "},{"question":"Strategic objectives and KPIs for supplier relationship management would be developed during which stage of the SCOR model?","choices":["A. Making ","  B. Planning ","  C. Sourcing ","  D. Delivering "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Strategic objectives for all high-level processes are set in the planning stage.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is true of collaborative relationships in the supply chain?","choices":["A. Companies will always have a good reason to treat competitors in a different class from other types of supply chain members. ","  B. Incompatible hardware or legacy systems are no longer a barrier to collaboration due to new methods of integration. ","  C. The most technologically advanced supply chain partner will determine the level of supply chain development for the network. ","  D. Power-based relationships place long-term gains ahead of short-term results."],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Competitors can often find a way to collaborate with each other for mutual gain, but since each competitor is actively trying to gain market share from the other, the relationships should be kept at arm's length to ensure fairness, and extra caution must be devoted to sharing information. Companies may pretend to embrace collaboration when they really only want access to information for their own benefit. Companies will always have a good reason to treat competitors warily.  "},{"question":"Consider a simplified supply chain in which Lucy sells psychiatric advice from a booth to her classmates for five cents. Subconsciously, she gets her information from her psychiatrist parent and from her pastor. Which of the following are Tier 2 suppliers in this model?","choices":["A. Lucy ","  B. Parent/pastor ","  C. Higher education/seminary ","  D. There are no Tier 2 suppliers in this situation. "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Lucy's parent and pastor are the Tier 1 suppliers to Lucy, the service producer. They owe their supply of information to either higher education or a seminary, so these sources are the Tier 2 suppliers.  "},{"question":"If a firm has 25 days of accounts payables outstanding and 30 days invested in inventory and their cash-to-cash cycle time is 80 days, how many days of accounts receivables do they have?","choices":["A. 105 days ","  B. 80 days ","  C. 75 days ","  D. 50 days "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The correct answer is 75 days: 80 days (cash to cash) + 25 days (payables) - 30 days (inventory) = 75 days receivables. The cash-to-cash cycle (or cash conversion cycle) is the number of days between the time a firm pays for raw materials and the time it receives payment for finished goods. The equation for calculating the cash-to-cash cycle is Cash-to-Cash Cycle Time = Average Inventory Collection Period + Average Receivables Processing Period - Average Payables Period; therefore, Days of Accounts Receivable = Cash-to-Cash Cycle Time + Days of Accounts Payable - Days of Inventory.  "},{"question":"In SCOR Level 1, if you divide the sum of the cycle times for all orders delivered by the total number of orders delivered, you are using a metric for which of the following supply chain attributes?","choices":["A. Reliability ","  B. Adaptability ","  C. Flexibility ","  D. Responsiveness "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Average actual cycle time (sum of cycle times divided by number of deliveries) measures the responsiveness of the supply chain. It doesn't tell you if the deliveries were on time, which would be a reliability metric.  "},{"question":"Which of the following categories would a precision spring for an expensive clock fit into if it was the key component that made the clock tell time reliably and needed to be of exacting dimensions and quality?","choices":["A. Bottleneck material ","  B. Commodity material ","  C. Leveragable material ","  D. Direct/core competency material"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"A material that is both of high strategic importance and of high supply chain difficulty due to its complexity and need for low variance would be a core competency or direct material. These items must be produced in-house or through as close a partnership as possible.  "},{"question":"At which of the following stages would a company be if it has multiple uncoordinated improvement efforts occurring sequentially instead of in concurrence, such as inventory reduction, better forecasting techniques, and lower cost procurement?","choices":["A. Stage 1: Multiple dysfunction ","  B. Stage 2: Semifunctional enterprise ","  C. Stage 3: Integrated enterprise ","  D. Stage 4: Extended enterprise"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"A company at Stage 2 will have multiple initiatives to improve individual functional areas, but these will not generally be coordinated with one another and will therefore fall short of their potential for reducing costs, improving margins, expanding markets, or delivering better service.  "},{"question":"In a supply chain context, measurable key performance indicators (KPIs) should be identified for which of the following?","choices":["A. Objectives of all key personnel in related functional areas ","  B. Performance of all products or services from a customer perspective ","  C. A limited number of essential supply chain processes ","  D. A limited number of top-level corporate and supply chain strategies "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Since measuring and monitoring all supply chain activities would be overwhelming, the more useful approach is to identify key performance indicators for a manageable number of supply chain strategic objectives. It is performance of the supply chain that KPIs measure, not employee or product performance.  "},{"question":"Which of the following usually implicitly exists in very simple supply chains such as a lemonade stand but must be explicitly managed in a complex supply chain of massive scale?","choices":["A. Collaboration between manufacturer and retailer ","  B. Collection and accounting for sales taxes ","  C. Compliance with government regulations ","  D. Supplier management"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A lemonade stand may not include any of the items in the incorrect answers, but it will generally have a good deal of collaborative planning in regard to demand forecasts and replenishment between the manufacturer and retailers (mother and children). Some of the problems that supply chain management strives to overcome are implicit in a simple model but must be explicitly managed in a complex supply chain because they arise as a direct result of the massive scale of modern supply chains.  "},{"question":"Developing a JIT supply chain generally implies adopting which of the following strategies with suppliers?","choices":["A. Long-term relationships with a limited number of suppliers ","  B. Competitive bidding among the widest possible number of suppliers ","  C. Open bidding for flexibility supported by frequent inspection of incoming shipments ","  D. Short-term contracts with revolving suppliers "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"JIT supply chains generally thrive on long-term contracts with a limited number of suppliers who are willing to adapt JIT principles in their organizations. JIT systems make demands upon suppliers, so contracts need to apportion benefits fairly. Bidding wars among many potential suppliers don't tend to allow for these special relationships. Inspections take up time without adding value, and they are no substitute for trusting relationships with suppliers who have proven their ability to provide quality deliveries without inspection.  "},{"question":"As a general rule, instituting JIT in a manufacturing facility affects employees' jobs in which of the following ways?","choices":["A. Job tasks are simplified. ","  B. Job responsibilities expand. ","  C. Jobs become more specialized. ","  D. Jobs are not a focus of change. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"JIT generally requires employees who institute the process to take on more responsibility and learn new skills to become more flexible.  "},{"question":"Volume growth is a key performance indicator for which of the following?","choices":["A. Product merchandizing ","  B. Supply chain variability ","  C. Customer service ","  D. Replenishment"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Volume growth measures the success of merchandizing efforts.  "},{"question":"A manufacturer, distributor, wholesaler, and retailer all agree to base their orders on actual consumer orders instead of performing detailed forecasts based on each party's Tier 1 customer's actual orders. Which of the following will result, and what are the likely risks of this method?","choices":["A. Pull moves back and push takes its place at the manufacturer but at the risk of inventory obsolescence or the bullwhip effect. ","  B. Pull moves back and push takes its place at the manufacturer but at the risk of greater overtime or rush orders. ","  C. Push moves back and pull takes its place at the manufacturer but at the risk of greater overtime or rush orders. ","  D. Push moves back and pull takes its place at the manufacturer but at the risk of inventory obsolescence or the bullwhip effect"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The firms have decided to move to a make-to-order environment, moving the push/pull frontier back to the manufacturer, which will reduce the bullwhip effect and the risk of inventory obsolescence, but at the risk of greater overtime and rush orders if there is a sudden spike in demand.  "},{"question":"According to the Supply-Chain Operations Reference (SCOR) model, if a refrigerator manufacturing company is at the center of the model, the supplier of materials to the sheet metal supplier has only which of the following processes to perform in relation to the manufacturer?","choices":["A. Plan, source, make, deliver, return  ","  B. Plan, source, return ","  C. Make, source, deliver ","  D. Plan, deliver, return"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"From the perspective of the manufacturer, the supplier of metal to the sheet metal suppliers is on the second tier and may join in planning, but the manufacturer is otherwise concerned only with its ability to deliver and return goods as needed. SCOR is developed and maintained by the Supply-Chain Council.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is a significant risk to consider when selecting a complex, enterprisewide software system?","choices":["A. Decreased velocity of processes because of software complexity ","  B. Decreased synchronicity of functions automated by the software ","  C. Lack of flexibility to improve processes automated by the software ","  D. Lack of future upgrade potential for the software "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The downside of complex, enterprisewide software systems is their potential to lock the enterprise into their assumptions and make process improvement difficult without simultaneous modifications to the complex system. The software would be chosen to increase synchronicity and velocity. Upgrades are generally part of the product and can always be purchased on a custom basis.  "},{"question":"Which of the following would a material be that was tightly linked to the company's brand equity even though it was basically a cheap but branded plastic toy that didn't require much quality?","choices":["A. Direct/core competency materials ","  B. Commodity materials ","  C. Bottleneck materials ","  D. Leveragable materials"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Leveragable materials are of high strategic importance but of low supply chain difficulty, so they are key areas where supply chain leverage can be applied to increase efficiencies and lower costs.  "},{"question":"Which of the following would be most likely to result in the creation of net financial value for a firm over the long term?","choices":["A. Get labor cost concessions from employees and distribute these gains to all stakeholders evenly. ","  B. Reinvest a sizable portion of profits into R\u0026D, upgrades, and automation. ","  C. Use increased market leverage to gain price concessions from suppliers. ","  D. Transfer all gains from the company to price discounts to consumers to gain market share."],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"While squeezing excess costs out of an enterprise certainly has the potential to provide value to one or more stakeholders, it has to be done carefully. Any manager can reduce costs by reducing staff, cutting outlays for research or training, and delaying expenditures on equipment, but that's generally a recipe for immediate stagnation and eventual failure.  "},{"question":"If customer demand is running at 500 units per day and available production time is 300 minutes per day, what is the takt time?","choices":["A. 6 seconds per unit ","  B. 16.7 second per unit ","  C. 36 seconds per unit ","  D. 1.67 minutes per unit"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"When a system is producing goods at takt time, the rate of goods produced exactly equals the rate of customer demand for the goods. It is calculated as available production divided by rate of customer demand.  "},{"question":"In a JIT system, reduction in lot sizes may result in which of the following tradeoffs?","choices":["A. Increased handling costs ","  B. Increased cumulative setup time ","  C. Increased holding costs ","  D. Increased inventory accumulation"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"JIT reduces lot sizes to bring down inventory accumulation and the costs of holding and handling inventory. However, smaller lot sizes require more frequent orders, and that means more setups. As a consequence, JIT participants need to find ways to reduce setup time.  "},{"question":"Members of a supply chain want to become demand-driven to reduce the bullwhip effect they are experiencing. Which of the following should each partner in the supply chain do?","choices":["A. Adopt new enterprise software systems that match current operating processes as closely as possible. ","  B. Improve their forecasting by basing the information on actual Tier 1 customer orders. ","  C. Develop agility for more frequent changeovers, staffing, or process switching. ","  D. Reduce their contracted or owned transportation modes to match the new lowered transport needs."],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Demand-driven supply chains require access to real demand data along the chain (visibility), trust and collaboration (including changing processes as needed) among partners, and agility. There will be no room for long changeover times between runs of different products; therefore, equipment, processes, work center layouts, or staffing may have to change. "},{"question":"Which of the following is true advice for ensuring that one's supply chain is agile and flexible?","choices":["A. Mixing products to achieve full truckload shipments may be highly inefficient for high-dollar, lightweight items. ","  B. Cost efficiencies and velocity must take precedence in the supply chain such as always requiring that full truckloads are used. ","  C. A manufacturer's trends in demand are best monitored through visibility with Tier 1 customers. ","  D. When designing products for maximum supply chain flexibility, putting customers on the design team will help create modular designs. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Develop multiple supply chains that are appropriate to each product line. Some companies, to achieve those full truckload shipments, will mix products. While that's a good strategy for speeding up delivery of some products in the mix, it may be highly inefficient for others. Take the high-dollar, lightweight items out of the truck, train, or container and fly them to their destinations.  "},{"question":"Selection of processes for improvement, according to quality methodology, should be done at which of the following levels?","choices":["A. Regular employees (shop-floor labor, service workers, etc.) ","  B. Top management ","  C. Middle management ","  D. Teams comprising all levels from top management to regular employees"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Quality initiatives are to be directed from the top down and implemented from the bottom up. Top management selects processes to improve.  "},{"question":"An organization sets a goal of reducing its lead time from four days to two days because another firm in its industry can offer two-day lead time. This is an example of which of the following?","choices":["A. Process benchmarking ","  B. Oliver Wight benchmarking ","  C. Competitive benchmarking ","  D. Best-in-class benchmarking "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Setting a competitor's performance on a process as your goal for the process in your organization is an example of competitive benchmarking.  "},{"question":"A focus on quality, affordability, or availability indicates a focus on which of the following?","choices":["A. Social value ","  B. Collaborative value ","  C. Customer value ","  D. Financial value"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Depending upon the market being served, a supply chain may be managed with an eye to delivering one or more of the following values to its end customers: quality, affordability, availability, or service.  "},{"question":"The developers of the balanced scorecard approach to performance were concerned that traditional metrics placed too much emphasis on which of the following considerations?","choices":["A. Current profitability ","  B. Customer complaints ","  C. Future performance objectives ","  D. Past financial performance"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"The developers of the balanced scorecard, Robert S. Kaplan and David Norton, believed that the traditional reliance on financial measures of performance placed too much emphasis on the past and too little on the present and future and, in addition, ignored other types of measures that contribute to success.  "},{"question":"According to a noted Japanese approach to analyzing business process problems, why is it necessary to ask \"Why?\" as many as five times when seeking the cause of a process defect?","choices":["A. There may be more than one cause for the defect. ","  B. Most employees won't admit making an error the first few times they are asked. ","  C. Most defects tend to have multiple causes, not just one. ","  D. First responses tend to name superficial causes rather than the root causes. "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"A Japanese method of root cause analysis referred to as \"Why? Why? Why? Why? Why?\" is based on the idea that it's not always easy to identify the root cause of a customer complaint or other process failure; the first suggestion is likely to be the result of bias or superficial analysis.  "},{"question":"The Global Supply Chain Forum (GSCF) defines supply chain management as \"the integration of key business processes from end user through original suppliers that provides products, services, and information that add value for customers and other stakeholders.\" Which two processes are considered to constitute the core of supply chain management in the GSCF model?","choices":["A. Customer and supplier management ","  B. Demand management and supplier management ","  C. Customer service management and manufacturing flow management ","  D. Order management and supplier relationship management "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"At the heart of the GSCF model is the combination of customer relationship management and supplier relationship management, because these two processes create and manage the link between adjacent partners in the supply chain.  "},{"question":"Volume growth is a key performance indicator for which of the following?","choices":["A. Customer service ","  B. Supply chain variability ","  C. Product merchandizing ","  D. Replenishment"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Volume growth measures the success of merchandizing efforts.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following constitutes the range of acceptable variability on a six-sigma control chart?","choices":["A. Zero variability ","  B. Mean defects plus/minus 3 sigmas ","  C. Mean defects plus 6 sigmas ","  D. Mean defects plus/minus 6 sigmas "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"The acceptable range of variability is the number of defects within a range of six sigmas (standard deviations) above and below the mean number of defects. The chart helps control the variability in a process. "},{"question":"Selection of processes for improvement, according to quality methodology, should be done at which of the following levels?","choices":["A. Top management ","  B. Teams comprising all levels from top management to regular employees ","  C. Regular employees (shop-floor labor, service workers, etc.) ","  D. Middle management"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Quality initiatives are to be directed from the top down and implemented from the bottom up. Top management selects processes to improve.  "},{"question":"Which of the following could be a key performance indicator (KPI) for replenishment?","choices":["A. Inventory turns ","  B. Volume growth ","  C. Introduction lead time ","  D. Order fill rate "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Order fill rate provides a measure of the success of the key process of replenishment. A high fill rate indicates good performance.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is true regarding a supply chain?","choices":["A. Services may be part of a manufacturing supply chain but do not have a distinct supply chain themselves. ","  B. Information flows upstream, downstream, and between network members and external entities. ","  C. An electrical power producer that powers a manufacturer's plant is downstream from the manufacturer. ","  D. Cash flows downstream while materials flow upstream."],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The information in a supply chain flows upstream toward the supplier end, downstream toward the customer end, and also back and forth within the entities and between the chain and external entities, such as governments, markets, and competitors.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is true of the Supply-Chain Operations Reference (SCOR) model?","choices":["A. SCOR applies to all product transactions (physical material and service). ","  B. SCOR applies to product development. ","  C. SCOR applies to all areas of postdelivery customer support including returns. ","  D. SCOR applies to demand generation in sales and marketing. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"SCOR can be applied to all product transactions, including services as well as material products. SCOR does not apply to any of the incorrect answers. (It does cover returns, but not all of postdelivery customer support.) SCOR is developed and maintained by the Supply-Chain Council.  "},{"question":"Which of the following phrases best characterizes the approach to change in total quality management initiatives?","choices":["A. Successive approximations of a perfected process ","  B. Short-term initiatives with precisely defined endpoints ","  C. \"Big step\" overhaul of whole systems ","  D. Tight focus on the improvement of end-item features "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Total quality management (TQM) is associated with the strategy of continuous improvement, which focuses on small-stem changes in processes (not products). Continuous process improvement (as it is also called) defines itself as \"the never-ending search for perfection,\" not short-term initiatives with definite endpoints.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following authorities has issued directives mandating reporting, reduction, and recycling of heavy metals in end-of-life electronics products?","choices":["A. European Union ","  B. United States government ","  C. Chinese government ","  D. United Nations"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"The European Union has issued several directives regarding hazardous components of electronics products, including the Waste from Electronic Equipment directive (WEEE) and the directive restricting the use of heavy metals and retardants in electrical and electronic equipment (RoHS). "},{"question":"Which of the following would a material be that was tightly linked to the company's brand equity even though it was basically a cheap but branded plastic toy that didn't require much quality?","choices":["A. Direct/core competency materials ","  B. Leveragable materials ","  C. Bottleneck materials ","  D. Commodity materials"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Leveragable materials are of high strategic importance but of low supply chain difficulty, so they are key areas where supply chain leverage can be applied to increase efficiencies and lower costs.  "},{"question":"A nucleus firm in the banking industry uses independent brokers to market new stock issues and has been successful in this channel. After investing some profits in the firm itself, they choose to reward their stockholders by distributing all remaining profits in a special dividend even though independent brokers are prohibited from owning these shares. Which of the following has this firm forgotten to account for in its creation of financial value?","choices":["A. It takes money to make money. ","  B. Gains must be fairly distributed among stakeholders. ","  C. Independent brokers should be rewarded through social incentives and reminded that shareholders must come first. ","  D. Tradeoffs must not be self-defeating."],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Possibly the most common mistake in this regard is to send all cost savings all the way to the consumers' end of the chain, which in this case is the shareholders. And perhaps most challenging of all in a lateral supply chain is the need for productive sharing of any financial gains. As noted earlier, a powerful nucleus firm can gather in the benefits of an alteration in the placement of inventory (or any other process change) at the expense of other stakeholders such as the independent brokers.  "},{"question":"What is the minimum level of enterprise evolution in which a firm might use a logistics supplier to integrate with external members and also internally combine warehousing and transportation activities to optimize cost versus customer service?","choices":["A. Stage 1: Multiple dysfunction ","  B. Stage 2: Semifunctional enterprise ","  C. Stage 3: Integrated enterprise ","  D. Stage 4: Extended enterprise"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A company at Stage 3 will make advances such as carrying out warehousing and transportation decisions in tandem to achieve the optimal balance of cost-effectiveness and customer service. At this point, the nucleus firm may begin to take a step toward integration with the external members of the chain by contracting with a logistics supplier.  "},{"question":"If a firm has 25 days of accounts payables outstanding and 30 days invested in inventory and their cash-to-cash cycle time is 80 days, how many days of accounts receivables do they have?","choices":["A. 105 days ","  B. 80 days ","  C. 75 days ","  D. 50 days"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The correct answer is 75 days: 80 days (cash to cash) + 25 days (payables) - 30 days (inventory) = 75 days receivables. The cash-to-cash cycle (or cash conversion cycle) is the number of days between the time a firm pays for raw materials and the time it receives payment for finished goods. The equation for calculating the cash-to-cash cycle is Cash-to-Cash Cycle Time = Average Inventory Collection Period + Average Receivables Processing Period - Average Payables Period; therefore, Days of Accounts Receivable = Cash-to-Cash Cycle Time + Days of Accounts Payable - Days of Inventory.  "},{"question":"In the Global Supply Chain Forum supply chain management model, which of the following combine to create a link between adjacent partners and form a context for the other six processes?","choices":["A. Manufacturing flow management and order fulfillment ","  B. Supplier relationship management and demand management ","  C. Product development and commercialization and manufacturing flow management ","  D. Customer relationship management and supplier relationship management "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Customer relationship management (CRM) and supplier relationship management (SRM) are at the heart of the eight processes. Their combination creates and manages the link between adjacent partners in the chain and provides the context for the other processes.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is true of contracts for partnerships?","choices":["A. Courts can become involved in conflicts in most Asian countries without long-term detriment to a relationship. ","  B. Contracts should be fixed at the start of the relationship because alterations are difficult to enact between multiple parties. ","  C. Cultural differences in contracts and problem resolution styles should be a primary consideration when arranging formal contracts. ","  D. Contracts should always be used in the negotiation process to keep relationships true to the agreement. "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Contracts, policies and procedures, and informal conflict resolution must be sensitive to cultural differences. While courts can become involved in conflicts in the United States without long-term detriment, the opposite is true in most Asian countries.  "},{"question":"When defining roles for each party in a collaboration, how should these interactions be structured and why?","choices":["A. Reciprocal interdependence; both parties become dependent upon one another. ","  B. Reciprocal interdependence; redundancy of effort is minimized. ","  C. Sequential interdependence; both parties become dependent upon one another. ","  D. Sequential interdependence; redundancy of effort is minimized."],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Conflicts can occur when defining roles for each party if the roles make one party more dependent upon another than they wish to be. To alleviate this common problem, networks should avoid sequential interdependence, in which the second party cannot begin work until the first party is done; instead, they should establish reciprocal independence, in which the exchange of tasks and services occurs in both directions.  "},{"question":"Which of the following decisions should include a consideration of landed costs?","choices":["A. Real property acquisitions ","  B. Transfer cost decisions ","  C. Warehouse location decisions ","  D. Purchase of a component domestically or offshore"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Landed costs include the purchase price of goods plus all other costs involved in getting the goods from the seller to the place where they will be used, such as a manufacturing facility. Landed cost provides a more accurate means of comparing the real costs of goods purchased in different geographic locations for use in the same facility.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is a benefit of a vertical supply chain rather than a lateral supply chain?","choices":["A. Improved business focus and expertise ","  B. Complete control and visibility of operations ","  C. Economies of scale and scope for individual functions ","  D. Technology to handle the increased complexity "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The benefit of vertical integration is control. A department or wholly owned subsidiary's operations are completely visible to the parent company (at least in theory) and can be synchronized with other company functions by directives from the top.  "},{"question":"According to the Supply-Chain Operations Reference (SCOR) model, if a refrigerator manufacturing company is at the center of the model, the supplier of materials to the sheet metal supplier has only which of the following processes to perform in relation to the manufacturer?","choices":["A. Plan, deliver, return ","  B. Make, source, deliver ","  C. Plan, source, make, deliver, return ","  D. Plan, source, return "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"From the perspective of the manufacturer, the supplier of metal to the sheet metal suppliers is on the second tier and may join in planning, but the manufacturer is otherwise concerned only with its ability to deliver and return goods as needed. SCOR is developed and maintained by the Supply-Chain Council.  "},{"question":"A midsize manufacturing firm works with a large retailer as its primary customer and has several sources of supply for each of its key materials. The firm is trying to align its supply chain strategy with corporate strategy. Which of the following must be the primary consideration when this firm is setting corporate strategy?","choices":["A. Setting the firm's own strategic objectives to leverage a more profitable margin from their customers ","  B. Alignment with the strategic objectives of their suppliers to generate long-term stability of supply ","  C. The objectives of the ultimate end customer regardless of what any intermediaries may interject ","  D. Alignment with the retailer's corporate strategy to holistically maintain a profitable relationship "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Because the retailer in this situation appears to be the nucleus firm, alignment of the retailer's corporate strategy with the firm's own corporate strategy must take precedence over other considerations.  "},{"question":"In a TQM initiative, the definition of \"defect\" is determined by which of the following?","choices":["A. Customer ","  B. Project team ","  C. Supply chain manager ","  D. Top management"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"According to TQM methodology, defects are defined from the customer's point of view.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is true of the people or the metrics involved in supply chain management?","choices":["A. Supply chain management must be the responsibility of a department-level manager who is equal in hierarchy to other department heads. ","  B. Supply chain strategy and control of the related processes depend on having people educated in functional rather than department thinking. ","  C. Performance must be measured by ratios of profitability and velocity, not by a checklist. ","  D. Current supply chain performance is better quantitatively benchmarked against the firm's desired performance than qualitatively benchmarked."],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Numbers (quantitative) generally provide the most convincing supporting evidence in the boardroom and investment analyst's office. If you're bragging about your cash-to-cash cycle, for instance, you might say, \"We've got it down from 50 days to 20, and that's below the industry average.\"   "},{"question":"A manufacturer, distributor, wholesaler, and retailer all agree to base their orders on actual consumer orders instead of performing detailed forecasts based on each party's Tier 1 customer's actual orders. Which of the following will result, and what are the likely risks of this method?","choices":["A. Push moves back and pull takes its place at the manufacturer but at the risk of greater overtime or rush orders. ","  B. Pull moves back and push takes its place at the manufacturer but at the risk of inventory obsolescence or the bullwhip effect. ","  C. Pull moves back and push takes its place at the manufacturer but at the risk of greater overtime or rush orders. ","  D. Push moves back and pull takes its place at the manufacturer but at the risk of inventory obsolescence or the bullwhip effect."],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"The firms have decided to move to a make-to-order environment, moving the push/pull frontier back to the manufacturer, which will reduce the bullwhip effect and the risk of inventory obsolescence, but at the risk of greater overtime and rush orders if there is a sudden spike in demand.  "},{"question":"A supply chain that produces and sells cigarettes using traditional forecasting at each stage has been experiencing the bullwhip effect. Which of the following has the strongest influence on this effect?","choices":["A. Announced promotions ","  B. Excess supply liquidation ","  C. Safety stock ","  D. Seasonal fluctuations "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Because cigarettes have relatively steady demand, the small variations in demand seen in the forecasting at the retail stage of the supply chain are padded by safety stock. Forecasting at each successive level uses the quantities ordered for forecasting rather than the actual sale amount, resulting in extremely variable demand at the other end of the supply chain.  "},{"question":"Which of the following members of the firm are typically involved in continuous process improvement initiatives?","choices":["A. Middle managers ","  B. All members of the firm, including executives, managers, and labor ","  C. Shop-floor workers and supervisors ","  D. Executives"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Continuous process improvement requires the participation of everyone involved in the targeted processes, the executives who are accountable for the process, the managers responsible for directing it, and the workers who carry it out.  "},{"question":"Slip sheets can be used in place of which of the following?","choices":["A. Protective packaging ","  B. Shipping containers ","  C. Conveyers ","  D. Pallets"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Slip sheets are square plastic or corrugated sheets that can be used in place of pallets for transporting and storing inventory.  "},{"question":"In the SCOR model, which performance attribute is associated with the Level 1 metric, perfect order fulfillment?","choices":["A. Supply chain flexibility ","  B. Supply chain adaptability ","  C. Supply chain reliability ","  D. Supply chain responsiveness"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Reliability is the supply chain attribute measured by perfect order fulfillment. The customer considers the organization to be reliable if it delivers orders perfectly a high percentage of the time.  "},{"question":"In an electrical generation supply chain, which of the following is a Tier 1 service supplier?","choices":["A. Manufacturer connected to electric grid ","  B. Facility maintenance ","  C. Electric power utility ","  D. Fuel supplier "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The electric power utility is the producer in this supply chain, with fuel suppliers and facility maintenance as Tier 1 suppliers, but only facility maintenance is a service supplier. The manufacturer on the grid is a customer.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is a significant risk to consider when selecting a complex, enterprisewide software system?","choices":["A. Decreased synchronicity of functions automated by the software ","  B. Decreased velocity of processes because of software complexity ","  C. Lack of flexibility to improve processes automated by the software ","  D. Lack of future upgrade potential for the software "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The downside of complex, enterprisewide software systems is their potential to lock the enterprise into their assumptions and make process improvement difficult without simultaneous modifications to the complex system. The software would be chosen to increase synchronicity and velocity. Upgrades are generally part of the product and can always be purchased on a custom basis.  "},{"question":"According to SCOR Level 1 metrics, which of the following attributes of an organization is measured by the increase in production it can achieve and sustain in 30 days' time?","choices":["A. Responsiveness ","  B. Reliability ","  C. Adaptability ","  D. Sustainability "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"An organization's adaptability depends upon the degree to which it can increase and sustain production within 30 days after an unexpected change in the market.  "},{"question":"According to the functional and innovative product categories designated by Marshall L. Fisher, which of the following would be a proper performance indicator for a typical innovative product?","choices":["A. Design for maximum performance at minimal cost ","  B. Aggressively reducing lead times ","  C. High inventory turns ","  D. Inventory reduction"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The key performance indicators for each supply chain differ because of the product characteristics. Aggressively reducing lead times, for example, is appropriate for innovative products but would be irrelevant for functional products that can be manufactured and delivered on predictable schedules in high volumes.  "},{"question":"The Level 2 SCOR measure for cost of goods sold includes which of the following supply chain costs?","choices":["A. Costs of sourcing and making ","  B. Costs of sourcing, making, and delivering ","  C. Costs of planning, sourcing, making, and delivering ","  D. Total costs of planning, sourcing, making, delivering, and returning "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"The SCOR Level 2 metric for cost of goods sold includes all the costs related to the five SCOR supply chain processes (plan, source, make, deliver, and return).  "},{"question":"What enforcement authority does the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission bring to its role in regard to the provisions of the Sarbanes-Oxley Act?","choices":["A. Authority to impose jail sentences on executives ","  B. Authority to bring cases to criminal court ","  C. Investigative authority only ","  D. Authority to bring civil court actions"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"The SEC has the authority to bring civil suits against corporations and individuals it believes to be out of compliance with securities regulations, including the Sarbanes-Oxley Act. It can refer cases to law enforcement agencies, which can institute criminal proceedings.  "},{"question":"When measuring the success of a supply chain management strategy by the balanced scorecard approach, each key performance indicator (KPI) should be linked to which one of the following?","choices":["A. Financials ","  B. Internal business process improvement ","  C. Customer perspective ","  D. Employee learning and growth"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"All four measurement categories on the balanced scorecard (financial, customer, business process, and learning and growth) should be taken into account and balanced against one another, but all measures must ultimately contribute to the bottom line.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following approaches to production scheduling accurately incorporates the theory of constraints?","choices":["A. Speed up production in front of the bottleneck. ","  B. Slow the process down to the bottleneck's speed. ","  C. Speed up production after the bottleneck. ","  D. Decrease inventory at the front of the bottleneck"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The theory of constraints focuses attention on slowest-moving part of a manufacturing process because it determines the maximum output of the process. Speeding up production before the constraint only produces an oversupply of inventory in front of the constraint, while speeding up the process after the constraint will result only in a lack of inventory after the constraint. Avoiding either of these problems requires running the process at the speed of the constraint.  "},{"question":"The Japanese term \"kaizen\" refers to which of the following business processes?","choices":["A. Interlocking business ownership ","  B. Display cards used as production signals ","  C. Root cause ","  D. Continuous process improvement"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"\"Kaizen\" is the Japanese term for continuous improvement. The total quality management and continuous improvement ideas were brought to Japan from the United States and then returned here after the Japanese established their practical value in business.  "},{"question":"As a general rule, instituting JIT in a manufacturing facility affects employees' jobs in which of the following ways?","choices":["A. Job tasks are simplified. ","  B. Job responsibilities expand. ","  C. Jobs are not a focus of change. ","  D. Jobs become more specialized."],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"JIT generally requires employees who institute the process to take on more responsibility and learn new skills to become more flexible.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is a tool that helps visually identify the 20 percent of causes responsible for 80 percent of problems (using those percentages as approximations)?","choices":["A. Checklist ","  B. Focus group ","  C. Process map ","  D. Pareto diagram"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"A Pareto diagram applies the Pareto principle that 80 percent of results tend to be the result of 20 percent of causes. The diagram helps visually distinguish the small number of causes that result in the largest number of process flaws. Focus groups are useful in gathering customer complaints: the flaws in the diagram.  "},{"question":"A manager decides to source their key Just-in-Time (JIT) manufacturing goods from a local producer even though an overseas producer sells identical goods for less, even with the added cost of shipping. Which of the following is this manager most likely emphasizing?","choices":["A. Availability ","  B. Affordability ","  C. Quality ","  D. Positive supply chain contribution"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"The availability of the good is being emphasized because the manager needs a reliable supply of goods even if it costs more to get the good when it is needed for the JIT process.  "},{"question":"A firm that is always claiming it has the best processes and highest quality has recently suffered losses because even though they dictate these processes to their long-term Asian suppliers, several of them have, without any explanation, recently had a string of additional costs and quality problems. Which of the following would best help this firm resolve its problems?","choices":["A. Enforce the provisions of the suppliers' contracts through litigation. ","  B. Move production so that it is once again performed correctly in-house. ","  C. Increase visibility with the suppliers and allow the suppliers to suggest processes that work for them. ","  D. Find new suppliers who can follow the firm's process more closely. "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Cultures tend to be egocentric and thus tend to resist external collaboration. They feel that their ways are the best ways of doing things and will often reject a different way without even considering it. Culture conflicts are increased when each company relies on its own sources of information and is unable to see the impact of its choices on other areas of the network. When companies don't see the negative results of their actions, they can't learn from their mistakes. Increasing visibility will correct some of these problems, but processes may need to be adaptable to the area in which they are performed, such as that litigation is seen as a betrayal of a relationship in many Asian countries.  "},{"question":"In a supply chain context, measurable key performance indicators (KPIs) should be identified for which of the following?","choices":["A. Objectives of all key personnel in related functional areas ","  B. Performance of all products or services from a customer perspective ","  C. A limited number of essential supply chain processes ","  D. A limited number of top-level corporate and supply chain strategies "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Since measuring and monitoring all supply chain activities would be overwhelming, the more useful approach is to identify key performance indicators for a manageable number of supply chain strategic objectives. It is performance of the supply chain that KPIs measure, not employee or product performance.  "},{"question":"Benchmarking is a tool used to carry out which function of a quality initiative?","choices":["A. Assess process performance. ","  B. Determine the roles in an initiative. ","  C. Implement a process improvement initiative. ","  D. Analyze the steps in a process. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Benchmarks provide a point of comparison that allows a project team to assess the relative effectiveness of a process and set a goal for its improvement.  "},{"question":"Where on a balanced scorecard would you enter a seminar on financial management for nonfinancial managers developed for the sales managers?","choices":["A. Customer perspective ","  B. Business process perspective ","  C. Financial perspective ","  D. Innovation and learning perspective"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Regardless of the content of the seminar, training belongs in the innovation and learning quadrant of the balanced scorecard.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following tools provides a visual method for tracking process variance as part of an improvement initiative?","choices":["A. Process map ","  B. Pareto diagram ","  C. Control chart ","  D. Oliver Wight checklist "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A control chart tracks process variance, allowing a project team to see quickly when defects have spiked to unacceptable levels. It can be used to manage as well as improve a process.  "},{"question":"In a JIT system, reduction in lot sizes may result in which of the following tradeoffs?","choices":["A. Increased cumulative setup time ","  B. Increased handling costs ","  C. Increased inventory accumulation ","  D. Increased holding costs"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"JIT reduces lot sizes to bring down inventory accumulation and the costs of holding and handling inventory. However, smaller lot sizes require more frequent orders, and that means more setups. As a consequence, JIT participants need to find ways to reduce setup time.  "},{"question":"The Global Supply Chain Forum (GSCF) defines supply chain management as \"the integration of key business processes from end user through original suppliers that provides products, services, and information that add value for customers and other stakeholders.\" Which two processes are considered to constitute the core of supply chain management in the GSCF model?","choices":["A. Order management and supplier relationship management ","  B. Customer service management and manufacturing flow management ","  C. Demand management and supplier management ","  D. Customer and supplier management"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"At the heart of the GSCF model is the combination of customer relationship management and supplier relationship management, because these two processes create and manage the link between adjacent partners in the supply chain.  "},{"question":"China has restricted U.S. imports of wood pallets for which of the following reasons?","choices":["A. Risk of insect pests in the wood ","  B. Pallets weren't being properly recycled ","  C. Excessive weight of soft wood pallets ","  D. Lack of Chinese wood content in pallets "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"China, the European Union, and other destinations have placed restrictions on wood pallets coming from the United States because of possible infestation by harmful insects.  "},{"question":"A design engineer is creating a product that conforms to customer needs according to the supply chain's market intelligence. Which of the following is the most important secondary design element that the engineer should include in the design?","choices":["A. Has more features than the competitor's product ","  B. Can be sold for a positive return ","  C. Can reach the market quickly ","  D. Has a lower price than the competitor's product "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Serving the end-user customer is the primary driver of supply chain decisions. And, second, the organizations in the supply chain have to make a profit and stay in business to serve the customer. Design engineers, or better yet, design teams from across the network design products that are right for the end customer (and can be sold profitably).  "},{"question":"At which of the following stages would a company be if it has multiple uncoordinated improvement efforts occurring sequentially instead of in concurrence, such as inventory reduction, better forecasting techniques, and lower cost procurement?","choices":["A. Stage 1: Multiple dysfunction ","  B. Stage 2: Semifunctional enterprise ","  C. Stage 3: Integrated enterprise ","  D. Stage 4: Extended enterprise"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"A company at Stage 2 will have multiple initiatives to improve individual functional areas, but these will not generally be coordinated with one another and will therefore fall short of their potential for reducing costs, improving margins, expanding markets, or delivering better service.  "},{"question":"With the theory of supply chain versus supply chain in competition, which of the following is true?","choices":["A. When supply chains share suppliers, alignment of business strategies with supply chain strategies is facilitated. ","  B. Use of common suppliers in competing chains may work to the advantage of both competitors at a risk of losing proprietary data. ","  C. Investments in suppliers shared by a competitor will increase the partnership with that supplier to the detriment of the competitor. ","  D. Industries with a small number of dominant suppliers are not ideal but are best coordinated using horizontal supply chains. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Use of common suppliers in competing chains may work to the advantage of both competitors, but at the very least the situation invites conflict of interest. Insofar as manufacturers want to keep their designs and processes proprietary, they take a risk when they link up with competing component suppliers.  "},{"question":"When preparing for a potential business disruption, which of the following is valid advice for contingency planners?","choices":["A. After assessing all potential risks, ensure that each one has a plan for continued functioning regardless of the cost. ","  B. Create contingency plans for yourself and for your supply chain partners. ","  C. Having extra stores of inventory is inadequate protection against a disruption in production. ","  D. Contingency plans are the responsibility of each departmental manager in addition to their regular duties."],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Don't rely only on extra stores of inventory. There can never be enough of it to cover all potential problems, and it, too, is vulnerable. You need alternate processes to keep functioning after a disaster.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is true advice for ensuring that one's supply chain is agile and flexible?","choices":["A. A manufacturer's trends in demand are best monitored through visibility with Tier 1 customers. ","  B. Mixing products to achieve full truckload shipments may be highly inefficient for high-dollar, lightweight items. ","  C. Cost efficiencies and velocity must take precedence in the supply chain such as always requiring that full truckloads are used. ","  D. When designing products for maximum supply chain flexibility, putting customers on the design team will help create modular designs."],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Develop multiple supply chains that are appropriate to each product line. Some companies, to achieve those full truckload shipments, will mix products. While that's a good strategy for speeding up delivery of some products in the mix, it may be highly inefficient for others. Take the high-dollar, lightweight items out of the truck, train, or container and fly them to their destinations.  "},{"question":"Which of the following identifies the emphasis of the Global Reporting Initiative?","choices":["A. Developing and publishing environmentally sustainable trade practices ","  B. Enforcing UN trade sanctions ","  C. Monitoring terrorist activities ","  D. Policing corporate and supply chain activities"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"The Global Reporting Initiative (GRI) is an independent group of organizations, including corporations, that develops and publishes sustainable corporate trade practices in regard to such environmental concerns as emissions, energy and resource consumption, and waste. It works with the UN and is entirely voluntary.  "},{"question":"According to a noted Japanese approach to analyzing business process problems, why is it necessary to ask \"Why?\" as many as five times when seeking the cause of a process defect?","choices":["A. First responses tend to name superficial causes rather than the root causes. ","  B. Most defects tend to have multiple causes, not just one. ","  C. Most employees won't admit making an error the first few times they are asked. ","  D. There may be more than one cause for the defect. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A Japanese method of root cause analysis referred to as \"Why? Why? Why? Why? Why?\" is based on the idea that it's not always easy to identify the root cause of a customer complaint or other process failure; the first suggestion is likely to be the result of bias or superficial analysis.  "},{"question":"Strategic objectives and KPIs for supplier relationship management would be developed during which stage of the SCOR model?","choices":["A. Planning ","  B. Sourcing ","  C. Delivering ","  D. Making"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Strategic objectives for all high-level processes are set in the planning stage.  "},{"question":"If a firm locates a centralized procurement and processing facility in a low-tax foreign country, which of the following tax rates will apply to income generated at the facility?","choices":["A. The rate in the country of the headquarters ","  B. The local country rate ","  C. A special international rate ","  D. A compromise rate between the local and home country rates"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"In general, income streams are separately taxed, so a company can lower its global tax liability by moving facilities to low-tax regions.  "},{"question":"Measures of success and incentives for a supply chain improvement initiative should be linked to which of the following?","choices":["A. Approval of top management ","  B. Outcome of the change initiative ","  C. Four quadrants of the balanced scorecard ","  D. Judgment of each participant's direct superviso"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Change management suggests that success should be measured by mutually supporting indicators drawn from the four quadrants of the balanced scorecard (business process, the customer perspective, financial impact, and growth and learning).  "},{"question":"The Sarbanes-Oxley Act (SOX) of 2002 focuses on which of the following areas?","choices":["A. Hazardous materials ","  B. Material content reporting ","  C. Terrorism ","  D. Financial reporting and controls"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Sarbanes-Oxley focuses on financial reporting and controls, including reporting on supply chain controls. Plans to respond to events such as terrorism are included in the reporting requirements, but they are not the focus of the legislation, which was drafted in response to corporate corruption.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is likely when a retailer of children's toys uses traditional forecasting to anticipate demand (as does their wholesaler) and adds some safety stock to orders both to smooth out the inevitable variations from the forecast and to replenish supplies after a promotion (not communicated to their suppliers) that the retailer plans to have to liquidate excess inventory?","choices":["A. High inventory holding costs for the retailer and low variability of demand for the wholesaler ","  B. Low inventory holding costs for the retailer and low variability of demand for the wholesaler ","  C. High inventory holding costs for the retailer and high variability of demand for the wholesaler ","  D. Low inventory holding costs for the retailer and high variability of demand for the wholesaler "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The retailer will have high inventory holding costs even though they are having a promotion to liquidate excess inventory because they are perpetuating a cycle of overordering inventory due to uncertain demand forecasts. The wholesaler will have high variability of demand because traditional forecasting and lack of communication about promotions will cause each stage of the supply chain to compensate with greater safety stock. In short, the situation describes the bullwhip effect.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is true regarding a supply chain?","choices":["A. Cash flows downstream while materials flow upstream. ","  B. An electrical power producer that powers a manufacturer's plant is downstream from the manufacturer. ","  C. Services may be part of a manufacturing supply chain but do not have a distinct supply chain themselves. ","  D. Information flows upstream, downstream, and between network members and external entities. "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"The information in a supply chain flows upstream toward the supplier end, downstream toward the customer end, and also back and forth within the entities and between the chain and external entities, such as governments, markets, and competitors. "},{"question":"A kaizen event would bring stakeholders together to design which of the following?","choices":["A. A new supply chain ","  B. A new corporate organization chart ","  C. A short-term project to improve a process of limited scale ","  D. A new product "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Kaizen events, also called kaizen blitzes, are used to design small-scale process improvement projects. They are particularly useful at the beginning of large-scale TQM projects to achieve a quick success and thus build credibility for the larger change initiative.  "},{"question":"JIT \"cells\" are laid out to accommodate which of the following?","choices":["A. One type of machine ","  B. One product family with similar manufacturing processes ","  C. One production process ","  D. One specialized type of worker "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Cells are arranged to allow for the most efficient production of a product family manufactured with similar production processes. Workers and machines are grouped to provide all the skills and equipment required for that product family in an efficiently arranged layout.  "},{"question":"Six-sigma emphasizes the importance of training at which of the following levels?","choices":["A. Customer-facing employees only ","  B. Top management only ","  C. All management levels ","  D. All levels "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Six-sigma emphasizes the importance of all process participants, from top management to basic service or shop-floor employees, and it includes training at all levels.  "},{"question":"According to research by Rice and Hoppe, the theory that supply chains of companies allied as partners in supply networks may compete directly with other similar supply chain networks in reality exists only with which of the following?","choices":["A. Channel masters such as retail consumer good giants ","  B. Vertical supply chains such as poultry sellers ","  C. Individual companies such as an automobile manufacturer based on their supply chain management capabilities ","  D. Horizontal supply chains such as PC sales "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Groups of companies allied as partners in supply networks will compete with other groups of companies allied in supply networks. The networks will be distinct from one another in all ways. The head-to-head supply chain competitors tend toward the vertically integrated company rather than the extended enterprise. The fashion and poultry industries are suggested as arenas in which supply chains compete with supply chains.  "},{"question":"A manager wants to move to the Supply-Chain Operations Reference (SCOR) model because their current strategy emphasizes reducing inventory costs by eliminating warehouses and increasing volume through sales promotions rather than innovation. Which of the following orientations is the manager moving from and which is he moving to by adopting SCOR?","choices":["A. From oriented to process to oriented to product or service ","  B. From oriented to functional area to oriented to entity collaboration ","  C. From oriented to functional area to oriented to process ","  D. From oriented to entity manufacturing to oriented to entity collaboration "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"SCOR organizes the model as a set of linked processes rather than as the links between specific entities. SCOR is developed and maintained by the Supply-Chain Council.  "},{"question":"A channel master is finding that many of its current partners have begun finding ways of bypassing the firm, while others are performing redundant functions that cause unnecessary competition among supply chain members. Which of the following is a likely cause of this behavior?","choices":["A. Weakest collaborative links becoming bottlenecks ","  B. Exploitation of power-based relationships ","  C. Working with competitors as peers ","  D. Individual incentives conflicting with organizational goals  "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Power-based relationships occur where a nucleus firm dictates the terms of the relationship to the other members. While its profits increase, other members of the network may suffer losses. When this occurs, the disadvantaged partners may rebel. Resistance may result in redundancy, loss of overall profitability for the chain, or an actual reversal of the power relationship.  "},{"question":"If customer demand is running at 500 units per day and available production time is 300 minutes per day, what is the takt time?","choices":["A. 6 seconds per unit ","  B. 16.7 second per unit ","  C. 36 seconds per unit ","  D. 1.67 minutes per unit"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"When a system is producing goods at takt time, the rate of goods produced exactly equals the rate of customer demand for the goods. It is calculated as available production divided by rate of customer demand.  "},{"question":"Which of the following categories would a precision spring for an expensive clock fit into if it was the key component that made the clock tell time reliably and needed to be of exacting dimensions and quality?","choices":["A. Bottleneck material ","  B. Leveragable material ","  C. Direct/core competency material ","  D. Commodity material"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A material that is both of high strategic importance and of high supply chain difficulty due to its complexity and need for low variance would be a core competency or direct material. These items must be produced in-house or through as close a partnership as possible.  "},{"question":"Which of the following continuous improvement methodologies focuses on reduction of defects to statistical insignificance?","choices":["A. Six-sigma ","  B. Theory of constraints ","  C. Lean ","  D. Just-in-Time (JIT) "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Six-sigma seeks to limit defects to no more than 3.4 per million opportunities. Of course, no initiative sets out to increase defects, but six-sigma makes defect reduction its specific objective.   "},{"question":"Which of the following is the technique of using visual signals to \"pull\" components through the manufacturing process?","choices":["A. Lean ","  B. Six-sigma ","  C. JIT ","  D. Kanban"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Kanban systems provide a visual signal to indicate when a workstation needs a component. Kanban is a Japanese term, and the system originated among Japanese manufacturers.  "},{"question":"Which of the following cost-cutting measures will be most likely to create net financial value?","choices":["A. Eliminating retail locations and selling direct to customers ","  B. Eliminating inventory holding costs by having suppliers carry more inventory and ship on demand ","  C. Eliminating local storage facilities to save on warehousing costs ","  D. Eliminating partial truckload shipments and sending only full truckload shipments to retail outlets to save on shipping "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Only the correct answer removes an element of the supply chain without lowering the net value for the customer. Cost cutting must aim for net gains at the bottom line, and the incorrect answers all create new costs for other areas of the company or supply chain. If a leaner supply chain can deliver the same customer satisfaction with a greater profit, then cost cutting is fully justified.  "},{"question":"Developing a JIT supply chain generally implies adopting which of the following strategies with suppliers?","choices":["A. Open bidding for flexibility supported by frequent inspection of incoming shipments ","  B. Short-term contracts with revolving suppliers ","  C. Competitive bidding among the widest possible number of suppliers ","  D. Long-term relationships with a limited number of suppliers "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"JIT supply chains generally thrive on long-term contracts with a limited number of suppliers who are willing to adapt JIT principles in their organizations. JIT systems make demands upon suppliers, so contracts need to apportion benefits fairly. Bidding wars among many potential suppliers don't tend to allow for these special relationships. Inspections take up time without adding value, and they are no substitute for trusting relationships with suppliers who have proven their ability to provide quality deliveries without inspection.  "},{"question":"According to the product categories designated by Marshall L. Fisher, which of the following categories would be the most likely classification for a product that has a six-month lead time?","choices":["A. Make-to-order innovative product ","  B. Make-to-stock innovative product ","  C. Make-to-order functional product ","  D. Make-to-stock functional product "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"An item with a very long lead time is likely a functional product that is not normally made-to-order but is in this case, such as a custom-sized pair of expensive boots. Innovative products stress aggressive reduction of lead times and generally have lead times of no more than two weeks.  "},{"question":"Consider a simplified supply chain in which Lucy sells psychiatric advice from a booth to her classmates for five cents. Subconsciously, she gets her information from her psychiatrist parent and from her pastor. Which of the following are Tier 2 suppliers in this model?","choices":["A. Lucy ","  B. Parent/pastor ","  C. Higher education/seminary ","  D. There are no Tier 2 suppliers in this situation."],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Lucy's parent and pastor are the Tier 1 suppliers to Lucy, the service producer. They owe their supply of information to either higher education or a seminary, so these sources are the Tier 2 suppliers.  "},{"question":"An organization sets a goal of reducing its lead time from four days to two days because another firm in its industry can offer two-day lead time. This is an example of which of the following?","choices":["A. Oliver Wight benchmarking ","  B. Competitive benchmarking ","  C. Process benchmarking ","  D. Best-in-class benchmarking"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Setting a competitor's performance on a process as your goal for the process in your organization is an example of competitive benchmarking.  "},{"question":"Which of the following best describes the potential for different quality methods to work together?","choices":["A. JIT and lean are compatible with each other but not with six-sigma. ","  B. JIT, lean, and six-sigma work best when combined. ","  C. Six-sigma and lean are compatible with each other but not with JIT. ","  D. JIT and six-sigma are compatible with each other but not with lean. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The three quality-based systems are mutually compatible and give the best results when combined to eliminate wasted materials, wasted time, defects, and variability.  "},{"question":"Which of the following results from having a firm's enterprise resources planning (ERP) software designed for automatic calculation of corporate taxes?","choices":["A. The firm will most likely underreport income. ","  B. The software will most likely fail to take legally available deductions. ","  C. The software will earn a tax deduction based on its use in tax planning. ","  D. The firms will risk violating Sarbanes-Oxley (SOX) reporting requirements."],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"ERP software can be programmed to determine the firm's exact tax liability and, at the same time, comply with Sarbanes-Oxley and earn a deduction for itself.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is true of the processes or information technology (IT) that comprises supply chain management strategy?","choices":["A. The most significant barrier to the use of IT for collaboration and networking among firms is the cost of the IT. ","  B. Orders in the delivery chain should be pulled through by manufacturer capacity. ","  C. A virtual network describes a network composed solely of IT linkages that a single entity runs. ","  D. Having two supply chains helps when order timing and fulfillment is crucial in one supply chain but secondary in another. "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Order fulfillment is the delivery of the right product in the amounts at the right time and place and in the right condition. All of these \"rights\" should be determined in alignment with the supply chain strategy. Different types of order fulfillment processes are needed for different markets, which justifies having more than a single supply chain.  "},{"question":"Which of the following scenarios is most likely to occur at the Stage 3 (integrated enterprise) level of supply chain evolution or higher?","choices":["A. Dominant partner coerces others to force price concessions. ","  B. Warehouses are located near each market and have more than enough inventory to handle the next big sale. ","  C. Manager provides a broad mission and backs it up with threats for nonconformance. ","  D. Sales rep finds a market opportunity but is unable to bring it to the attention of new product development. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"When firms first move past internal integration into external collaboration, the first collaboration can also be the last one if the arrangement fails to produce positive results for the weaker partner as well as for the channel master. Early manufacturer-supplier linkages, for example, were too often the result of coercion by the dominant partner, who was looking for guaranteed on-time delivery of quality items at a relatively low price.  "},{"question":"A focus on quality, affordability, or availability indicates a focus on which of the following?","choices":["A. Customer value ","  B. Financial value ","  C. Social value ","  D. Collaborative value"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Depending upon the market being served, a supply chain may be managed with an eye to delivering one or more of the following values to its end customers: quality, affordability, availability, or service.  "},{"question":"Corporate participants in C-TPAT (Customs-Trade Partnership against Terrorism) receive which one of the following benefits?","choices":["A. Increased protection for overseas shipments ","  B. Reduced tariffs ","  C. Exemption from border inspections ","  D. Greater reliance on self-policing"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Corporate partners in C-TPAT benefit from a greater emphasis on self-policing rather than customs verification and other benefits.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is true of collaborative relationships in the supply chain?","choices":["A. Power-based relationships place long-term gains ahead of short-term results. ","  B. Incompatible hardware or legacy systems are no longer a barrier to collaboration due to new methods of integration. ","  C. The most technologically advanced supply chain partner will determine the level of supply chain development for the network. ","  D. Companies will always have a good reason to treat competitors in a different class from other types of supply chain members"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Competitors can often find a way to collaborate with each other for mutual gain, but since each competitor is actively trying to gain market share from the other, the relationships should be kept at arm's length to ensure fairness, and extra caution must be devoted to sharing information. Companies may pretend to embrace collaboration when they really only want access to information for their own benefit. Companies will always have a good reason to treat competitors warily.  "},{"question":"Which of the following could be a key performance indicator (KPI) for replenishment?","choices":["A. Introduction lead time ","  B. Inventory turns ","  C. Order fill rate ","  D. Volume growth "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Order fill rate provides a measure of the success of the key process of replenishment. A high fill rate indicates good performance.  "},{"question":"Many Japanese companies use keiretsu to avoid which of the following?","choices":["A. Needing to abandon the control and full integration of a vertical environment ","  B. The semifunctional enterprise stage (Stage 2) ","  C. Lacking specialization and focus in a network of independent firms ","  D. The challenges of synchronizing a network of independent firms "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Keiretsu is an intermediate form of integration that differs from vertical integration or horizontal integration in that suppliers and customers are not completely independent but instead own significant stakes in one another. This helps the network of firms be more willing to consider each other's needs.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is true of supply chains?","choices":["A. There are two flows that can be engineered in a chain, products and cash. ","  B. Competition is an outside stakeholder to a supply chain that threatens or energizes it. ","  C. Supply chain processes are entirely contained within each entity within a supply chain. ","  D. Supply chains run in only one direction, toward the customer. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Competitors affect the functioning of a supply chain in more ways than one: They can threaten or energize the chain. Sometimes competing businesses directly foster each other's growth by participation in trade associations and joint ventures. Whenever a competitor creates an improved product or business process, the entire marketplace is enriched by the new ideas.  "},{"question":"In SCOR Level 1, if you divide the sum of the cycle times for all orders delivered by the total number of orders delivered, you are using a metric for which of the following supply chain attributes?","choices":["A. Adaptability ","  B. Responsiveness ","  C. Flexibility ","  D. Reliability "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Average actual cycle time (sum of cycle times divided by number of deliveries) measures the responsiveness of the supply chain. It doesn't tell you if the deliveries were on time, which would be a reliability metric.  "},{"question":"Which of the following illustrates an emphasis on the affordability aspect of customer value?","choices":["A. A cement-mixing tub of greater durability and flexibility than similar offerings ","  B. Same-day delivery of goods via courier-to-air-to-courier ","  C. A luxury boat priced lower than other luxury boats of similar size and feature ","  D. No-hassle, no-negotiation sales price on new cars at a dealership"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Affordability does not refer solely to discount goods but to goods that have a price at the lower end of an appropriate price level for the value received.  "},{"question":"Members of a supply chain want to become demand-driven to reduce the bullwhip effect they are experiencing. Which of the following should each partner in the supply chain do?","choices":["A. Reduce their contracted or owned transportation modes to match the new lowered transport needs. ","  B. Develop agility for more frequent changeovers, staffing, or process switching. ","  C. Improve their forecasting by basing the information on actual Tier 1 customer orders. ","  D. Adopt new enterprise software systems that match current operating processes as closely as possible."],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Demand-driven supply chains require access to real demand data along the chain (visibility), trust and collaboration (including changing processes as needed) among partners, and agility. There will be no room for long changeover times between runs of different products; therefore, equipment, processes, work center layouts, or staffing may have to change.  "},{"question":"When the APICS Dictionary, 11th edition, refers to a supply chain as a \"global network,\" which of the following correctly indicates what could comprise this network?","choices":["A. Processes of any size or configuration but only international entities ","  B. Entities of any size or configuration but not processes ","  C. Only international entities or global processes ","  D. Entities and processes of any size or configuration "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"The global network referred to in the definition of a supply chain comprises a network of both entities and processes (the engineered flow). A supply chain doesn't have to be global.  "},{"question":"Which of the following would be most likely to result in the creation of net financial value for a firm over the long term?","choices":["A. Use increased market leverage to gain price concessions from suppliers. ","  B. Transfer all gains from the company to price discounts to consumers to gain market share. ","  C. Reinvest a sizable portion of profits into R\u0026D, upgrades, and automation. ","  D. Get labor cost concessions from employees and distribute these gains to all stakeholders evenly. "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"While squeezing excess costs out of an enterprise certainly has the potential to provide value to one or more stakeholders, it has to be done carefully. Any manager can reduce costs by reducing staff, cutting outlays for research or training, and delaying expenditures on equipment, but that's generally a recipe for immediate stagnation and eventual failure.  "},{"question":"In the Global Supply Chain Forum supply chain management model, which of the following combine to create a link between adjacent partners and form a context for the other six processes?","choices":["A. Customer relationship management and supplier relationship management ","  B. Product development and commercialization and manufacturing flow management ","  C. Manufacturing flow management and order fulfillment ","  D. Supplier relationship management and demand management "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Customer relationship management (CRM) and supplier relationship management (SRM) are at the heart of the eight processes. Their combination creates and manages the link between adjacent partners in the chain and provides the context for the other processes.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is among the Global Supply Chain Forum's eight essential supply chain management processes?","choices":["A. Purchasing ","  B. Production ","  C. Logistics ","  D. Order fulfillment "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Order fulfillment is one of the GSCF's essential processes. The other answers identify activities that contribute to the supply chain processes, but they are not among the processes identified in the GSCF's model.  "},{"question":"Which of the following usually implicitly exists in very simple supply chains such as a lemonade stand but must be explicitly managed in a complex supply chain of massive scale?","choices":["A. Supplier management ","  B. Collection and accounting for sales taxes ","  C. Compliance with government regulations ","  D. Collaboration between manufacturer and retailer"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"A lemonade stand may not include any of the items in the incorrect answers, but it will generally have a good deal of collaborative planning in regard to demand forecasts and replenishment between the manufacturer and retailers (mother and children). Some of the problems that supply chain management strives to overcome are implicit in a simple model but must be explicitly managed in a complex supply chain because they arise as a direct result of the massive scale of modern supply chains.  "},{"question":"A manager wants to move to the Supply-Chain Operations Reference (SCOR) model because their current strategy emphasizes reducing inventory costs by eliminating warehouses and increasing volume through sales promotions rather than innovation. Which of the following orientations is the manager moving from and which is he moving to by adopting SCOR?","choices":["A. From oriented to functional area to oriented to entity collaboration ","  B. From oriented to process to oriented to product or service ","  C. From oriented to functional area to oriented to process ","  D. From oriented to entity manufacturing to oriented to entity collaboration "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"SCOR organizes the model as a set of linked processes rather than as the links between specific entities. SCOR is developed and maintained by the Supply-Chain Council.  "},{"question":"A sporting goods store sells some items at a low margin and steady demand, such as tennis balls, some items at a high margin and unpredictable demand, such as jogging outfits, and some items only during certain seasons, such as snowboarding equipment. Which of the following would provide the simplest and most effective supply chain solution for this company?","choices":["A. One supply chain for steady low-margin goods, one for unpredictable high-margin goods, and one for seasonal goods ","  B. One supply chain for all goods ","  C. One supply chain for steady low-margin goods and one for exceptions ","  D. One supply chain for seasonal goods and one for the remaining goods "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"According to Jonathan Byrnes, one supply chain is not enough; two, three, or more would be preferable. \"One size fits all\" supply chains may have been sufficient in the past, but new information technology makes it possible to have multiple, dynamic chains that can accommodate different product and information flows. Byrnes breaks products into three categories: staples, seasonal products, and fashion. Separating the flows into these categories can better allocate shipping, response time, and other resources to the appropriate areas.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following constitutes the range of acceptable variability on a six-sigma control chart?","choices":["A. Zero variability ","  B. Mean defects plus/minus 3 sigmas ","  C. Mean defects plus 6 sigmas ","  D. Mean defects plus/minus 6 sigmas"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"The acceptable range of variability is the number of defects within a range of six sigmas (standard deviations) above and below the mean number of defects. The chart helps control the variability in a process.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is the best way for top management to show commitment in cross-enterprise collaboration activities?","choices":["A. Set the collaboration agreement and strictly enforce it without allowing the plan to be changed due to circumstances brought up by lower managers. ","  B. Focus on future strategy and delegate the task of maintaining the current focus on supply chain interactions. ","  C. Enforce collaborative agreements within their internal staff and discipline counterproductive actions. ","  D. Give frequent motivational speeches to internal and external managers."],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Top management commitment is demonstrated by actions and relationship building, not just words. Top management is responsible for keeping the focus on supply chain interactions and cannot abdicate this duty. If they do not provide proactive and enthusiastic support, their company will quickly fall back to its old ways of doing things.  "},{"question":"Which of the following usually implicitly exists in very simple supply chains such as a lemonade stand but must be explicitly managed in a complex supply chain of massive scale?","choices":["A. Collaboration between manufacturer and retailer ","  B. Supplier management ","  C. Compliance with government regulations ","  D. Collection and accounting for sales taxes "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A lemonade stand may not include any of the items in the incorrect answers, but it will generally have a good deal of collaborative planning in regard to demand forecasts and replenishment between the manufacturer and retailers (mother and children). Some of the problems that supply chain management strives to overcome are implicit in a simple model but must be explicitly managed in a complex supply chain because they arise as a direct result of the massive scale of modern supply chains.  "},{"question":"When preparing for a potential business disruption, which of the following is valid advice for contingency planners?","choices":["A. Having extra stores of inventory is inadequate protection against a disruption in production. ","  B. Contingency plans are the responsibility of each departmental manager in addition to their regular duties. ","  C. After assessing all potential risks, ensure that each one has a plan for continued functioning regardless of the cost. ","  D. Create contingency plans for yourself and for your supply chain partners. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Don't rely only on extra stores of inventory. There can never be enough of it to cover all potential problems, and it, too, is vulnerable. You need alternate processes to keep functioning after a disaster. "},{"question":"JIT \"cells\" are laid out to accommodate which of the following?","choices":["A. One specialized type of worker ","  B. One product family with similar manufacturing processes ","  C. One type of machine ","  D. One production process "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Cells are arranged to allow for the most efficient production of a product family manufactured with similar production processes. Workers and machines are grouped to provide all the skills and equipment required for that product family in an efficiently arranged layout.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is true advice for ensuring that one's supply chain is agile and flexible?","choices":["A. A manufacturer's trends in demand are best monitored through visibility with Tier 1 customers. ","  B. Cost efficiencies and velocity must take precedence in the supply chain such as always requiring that full truckloads are used. ","  C. Mixing products to achieve full truckload shipments may be highly inefficient for high-dollar, lightweight items. ","  D. When designing products for maximum supply chain flexibility, putting customers on the design team will help create modular designs. "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Develop multiple supply chains that are appropriate to each product line. Some companies, to achieve those full truckload shipments, will mix products. While that's a good strategy for speeding up delivery of some products in the mix, it may be highly inefficient for others. Take the high-dollar, lightweight items out of the truck, train, or container and fly them to their destinations.  "},{"question":"A kaizen event would bring stakeholders together to design which of the following?","choices":["A. A short-term project to improve a process of limited scale ","  B. A new supply chain ","  C. A new product ","  D. A new corporate organization chart"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Kaizen events, also called kaizen blitzes, are used to design small-scale process improvement projects. They are particularly useful at the beginning of large-scale TQM projects to achieve a quick success and thus build credibility for the larger change initiative.  "},{"question":"Which of the following identifies the emphasis of the Global Reporting Initiative?","choices":["A. Policing corporate and supply chain activities ","  B. Monitoring terrorist activities ","  C. Developing and publishing environmentally sustainable trade practices ","  D. Enforcing UN trade sanctions"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The Global Reporting Initiative (GRI) is an independent group of organizations, including corporations, that develops and publishes sustainable corporate trade practices in regard to such environmental concerns as emissions, energy and resource consumption, and waste. It works with the UN and is entirely voluntary.  "},{"question":"The Global Supply Chain Forum (GSCF) defines supply chain management as \"the integration of key business processes from end user through original suppliers that provides products, services, and information that add value for customers and other stakeholders.\" Which two processes are considered to constitute the core of supply chain management in the GSCF model?","choices":["A. Order management and supplier relationship management ","  B. Customer and supplier management ","  C. Customer service management and manufacturing flow management ","  D. Demand management and supplier management "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"At the heart of the GSCF model is the combination of customer relationship management and supplier relationship management, because these two processes create and manage the link between adjacent partners in the supply chain.  "},{"question":"The Japanese term \"kaizen\" refers to which of the following business processes?","choices":["A. Continuous process improvement ","  B. Display cards used as production signals ","  C. Interlocking business ownership ","  D. Root cause"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"\"Kaizen\" is the Japanese term for continuous improvement. The total quality management and continuous improvement ideas were brought to Japan from the United States and then returned here after the Japanese established their practical value in business.  "},{"question":"Which of the following would a material be that was tightly linked to the company's brand equity even though it was basically a cheap but branded plastic toy that didn't require much quality?","choices":["A. Direct/core competency materials ","  B. Leveragable materials ","  C. Bottleneck materials ","  D. Commodity materials "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Leveragable materials are of high strategic importance but of low supply chain difficulty, so they are key areas where supply chain leverage can be applied to increase efficiencies and lower costs.  "},{"question":"Benchmarking is a tool used to carry out which function of a quality initiative?","choices":["A. Implement a process improvement initiative. ","  B. Determine the roles in an initiative. ","  C. Analyze the steps in a process. ","  D. Assess process performance."],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Benchmarks provide a point of comparison that allows a project team to assess the relative effectiveness of a process and set a goal for its improvement.  "},{"question":"A focus on quality, affordability, or availability indicates a focus on which of the following?","choices":["A. Financial value ","  B. Customer value ","  C. Collaborative value ","  D. Social value "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Depending upon the market being served, a supply chain may be managed with an eye to delivering one or more of the following values to its end customers: quality, affordability, availability, or service. "},{"question":"Which of the following is a true prerequisite for developing collaborative relationships central to supply chain strategy?","choices":["A. The most advanced communications hardware and software ","  B. Auditable information exchange to share knowledge, not just data ","  C. Sharing some benefits but none of the burdens of collaboration with partners ","  D. Deterrence-based arrangements such as aligning sales and management goals to collaborative objectives"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Auditable information exchange and technology for connectivity should allow sharing of knowledge, not mere data. The required technology itself may not have to be the most powerful, but it must be compatible to allow information exchange.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is a significant risk to consider when selecting a complex, enterprisewide software system?","choices":["A. Lack of future upgrade potential for the software ","  B. Lack of flexibility to improve processes automated by the software ","  C. Decreased velocity of processes because of software complexity ","  D. Decreased synchronicity of functions automated by the software "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The downside of complex, enterprisewide software systems is their potential to lock the enterprise into their assumptions and make process improvement difficult without simultaneous modifications to the complex system. The software would be chosen to increase synchronicity and velocity. Upgrades are generally part of the product and can always be purchased on a custom basis.  . "},{"question":"The developers of the balanced scorecard approach to performance were concerned that traditional metrics placed too much emphasis on which of the following considerations?","choices":["A. Future performance objectives ","  B. Current profitability ","  C. Past financial performance ","  D. Customer complaints "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The developers of the balanced scorecard, Robert S. Kaplan and David Norton, believed that the traditional reliance on financial measures of performance placed too much emphasis on the past and too little on the present and future and, in addition, ignored other types of measures that contribute to success.  "},{"question":"According to the functional and innovative product categories designated by Marshall L. Fisher, which of the following would be a proper performance indicator for a typical innovative product?","choices":["A. Aggressively reducing lead times ","  B. Inventory reduction ","  C. High inventory turns ","  D. Design for maximum performance at minimal cost "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"The key performance indicators for each supply chain differ because of the product characteristics. Aggressively reducing lead times, for example, is appropriate for innovative products but would be irrelevant for functional products that can be manufactured and delivered on predictable schedules in high volumes.  "},{"question":"Which of the following scenarios is most likely to occur at the Stage 3 (integrated enterprise) level of supply chain evolution or higher?","choices":["A. Sales rep finds a market opportunity but is unable to bring it to the attention of new product development. ","  B. Dominant partner coerces others to force price concessions. ","  C. Warehouses are located near each market and have more than enough inventory to handle the next big sale. ","  D. Manager provides a broad mission and backs it up with threats for nonconformance. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"When firms first move past internal integration into external collaboration, the first collaboration can also be the last one if the arrangement fails to produce positive results for the weaker partner as well as for the channel master. Early manufacturer-supplier linkages, for example, were too often the result of coercion by the dominant partner, who was looking for guaranteed on-time delivery of quality items at a relatively low price.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is true of the Supply-Chain Operations Reference (SCOR) model?","choices":["A. SCOR applies to all areas of postdelivery customer support including returns. ","  B. SCOR applies to demand generation in sales and marketing. ","  C. SCOR applies to all product transactions (physical material and service). ","  D. SCOR applies to product development. "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"SCOR can be applied to all product transactions, including services as well as material products. SCOR does not apply to any of the incorrect answers. (It does cover returns, but not all of postdelivery customer support.) SCOR is developed and maintained by the Supply-Chain Council.  "},{"question":"Which of the following phrases best characterizes the approach to change in total quality management initiatives?","choices":["A. \"Big step\" overhaul of whole systems ","  B. Tight focus on the improvement of end-item features ","  C. Successive approximations of a perfected process ","  D. Short-term initiatives with precisely defined endpoints "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Total quality management (TQM) is associated with the strategy of continuous improvement, which focuses on small-stem changes in processes (not products). Continuous process improvement (as it is also called) defines itself as \"the never-ending search for perfection,\" not short-term initiatives with definite endpoints.  "},{"question":"Which of the following results from having a firm's enterprise resources planning (ERP) software designed for automatic calculation of corporate taxes?","choices":["A. The firm will most likely underreport income. ","  B. The software will most likely fail to take legally available deductions. ","  C. The software will earn a tax deduction based on its use in tax planning. ","  D. The firms will risk violating Sarbanes-Oxley (SOX) reporting requirements. "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"ERP software can be programmed to determine the firm's exact tax liability and, at the same time, comply with Sarbanes-Oxley and earn a deduction for itself. "},{"question":"When measuring the success of a supply chain management strategy by the balanced scorecard approach, each key performance indicator (KPI) should be linked to which one of the following?","choices":["A. Employee learning and growth ","  B. Customer perspective ","  C. Internal business process improvement ","  D. Financials"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"All four measurement categories on the balanced scorecard (financial, customer, business process, and learning and growth) should be taken into account and balanced against one another, but all measures must ultimately contribute to the bottom line.  "},{"question":"When setting supply chain strategy at a firm that isn't the nucleus firm, which of the following is the most important to focus on?","choices":["A. What's good for extended supply chain partners ","  B. What's good for one's own firm ","  C. What's good for the final customer ","  D. What's good for the nucleus firm "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"When it comes to supply chains, it's what's good for the final customer that counts, not what's good for the nucleus company or even what seems to be good for the supply chain itself. Supply chain management ought to be all about giving the final customer the right product at the right time and place for the right price.  "},{"question":"Where on a balanced scorecard would you enter a seminar on financial management for nonfinancial managers developed for the sales managers?","choices":["A. Innovation and learning perspective ","  B. Business process perspective ","  C. Financial perspective ","  D. Customer perspective "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Regardless of the content of the seminar, training belongs in the innovation and learning quadrant of the balanced scorecard.  "},{"question":"Volume growth is a key performance indicator for which of the following?","choices":["A. Product merchandizing ","  B. Customer service ","  C. Supply chain variability ","  D. Replenishment "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Volume growth measures the success of merchandizing efforts.  "},{"question":"According to research by Rice and Hoppe, the theory that supply chains of companies allied as partners in supply networks may compete directly with other similar supply chain networks in reality exists only with which of the following?","choices":["A. Channel masters such as retail consumer good giants ","  B. Vertical supply chains such as poultry sellers ","  C. Horizontal supply chains such as PC sales ","  D. Individual companies such as an automobile manufacturer based on their supply chain management capabilities "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Groups of companies allied as partners in supply networks will compete with other groups of companies allied in supply networks. The networks will be distinct from one another in all ways. The head-to-head supply chain competitors tend toward the vertically integrated company rather than the extended enterprise. The fashion and poultry industries are suggested as arenas in which supply chains compete with supply chains.  "},{"question":"Which of the following cost-cutting measures will be most likely to create net financial value?","choices":["A. Eliminating inventory holding costs by having suppliers carry more inventory and ship on demand ","  B. Eliminating retail locations and selling direct to customers ","  C. Eliminating local storage facilities to save on warehousing costs ","  D. Eliminating partial truckload shipments and sending only full truckload shipments to retail outlets to save on shipping "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Only the correct answer removes an element of the supply chain without lowering the net value for the customer. Cost cutting must aim for net gains at the bottom line, and the incorrect answers all create new costs for other areas of the company or supply chain. If a leaner supply chain can deliver the same customer satisfaction with a greater profit, then cost cutting is fully justified.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is true of supply chains?","choices":["A. Competition is an outside stakeholder to a supply chain that threatens or energizes it. ","  B. There are two flows that can be engineered in a chain, products and cash. ","  C. Supply chains run in only one direction, toward the customer. ","  D. Supply chain processes are entirely contained within each entity within a supply chain. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Competitors affect the functioning of a supply chain in more ways than one: They can threaten or energize the chain. Sometimes competing businesses directly foster each other's growth by participation in trade associations and joint ventures. Whenever a competitor creates an improved product or business process, the entire marketplace is enriched by the new ideas.  "},{"question":"A sporting goods store sells some items at a low margin and steady demand, such as tennis balls, some items at a high margin and unpredictable demand, such as jogging outfits, and some items only during certain seasons, such as snowboarding equipment. Which of the following would provide the simplest and most effective supply chain solution for this company?","choices":["A. One supply chain for seasonal goods and one for the remaining goods ","  B. One supply chain for steady low-margin goods and one for exceptions ","  C. One supply chain for all goods ","  D. One supply chain for steady low-margin goods, one for unpredictable high-margin goods, and one for seasonal goods "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"According to Jonathan Byrnes, one supply chain is not enough; two, three, or more would be preferable. \"One size fits all\" supply chains may have been sufficient in the past, but new information technology makes it possible to have multiple, dynamic chains that can accommodate different product and information flows. Byrnes breaks products into three categories: staples, seasonal products, and fashion. Separating the flows into these categories can better allocate shipping, response time, and other resources to the appropriate areas.  "},{"question":"As a general rule, instituting JIT in a manufacturing facility affects employees' jobs in which of the following ways?","choices":["A. Jobs become more specialized. ","  B. Job responsibilities expand. ","  C. Jobs are not a focus of change. ","  D. Job tasks are simplified."],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"JIT generally requires employees who institute the process to take on more responsibility and learn new skills to become more flexible.  "},{"question":"Developing a JIT supply chain generally implies adopting which of the following strategies with suppliers?","choices":["A. Competitive bidding among the widest possible number of suppliers ","  B. Open bidding for flexibility supported by frequent inspection of incoming shipments ","  C. Long-term relationships with a limited number of suppliers ","  D. Short-term contracts with revolving suppliers "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"JIT supply chains generally thrive on long-term contracts with a limited number of suppliers who are willing to adapt JIT principles in their organizations. JIT systems make demands upon suppliers, so contracts need to apportion benefits fairly. Bidding wars among many potential suppliers don't tend to allow for these special relationships. Inspections take up time without adding value, and they are no substitute for trusting relationships with suppliers who have proven their ability to provide quality deliveries without inspection.  "},{"question":"The antiterrorism measures developed by the Customs-Trade Partnership against Terrorism (C-TPAT) apply to which of the following entities?","choices":["A. All U.S. exporters ","  B. All domestic and foreign firms involved in U.S. supply chains ","  C. All U.S. importers ","  D. C-TPAT corporate participants"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Participation in the Customs-Trade Partnership against Terrorism is voluntary, and compliance with its regulations is required only of participants. Failure to comply can lead to suspension of privileges or cancellation of partnership.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following authorities has issued directives mandating reporting, reduction, and recycling of heavy metals in end-of-life electronics products?","choices":["A. United States government ","  B. Chinese government ","  C. European Union ","  D. United Nations"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The European Union has issued several directives regarding hazardous components of electronics products, including the Waste from Electronic Equipment directive (WEEE) and the directive restricting the use of heavy metals and retardants in electrical and electronic equipment (RoHS).  "},{"question":"In an electrical generation supply chain, which of the following is a Tier 1 service supplier?","choices":["A. Fuel supplier ","  B. Electric power utility ","  C. Manufacturer connected to electric grid ","  D. Facility maintenance "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"The electric power utility is the producer in this supply chain, with fuel suppliers and facility maintenance as Tier 1 suppliers, but only facility maintenance is a service supplier. The manufacturer on the grid is a customer.  "},{"question":"In a TQM initiative, the definition of \"defect\" is determined by which of the following?","choices":["A. Supply chain manager ","  B. Customer ","  C. Top management ","  D. Project team "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"According to TQM methodology, defects are defined from the customer's point of view.  "},{"question":"Which of the following continuous improvement methodologies focuses on reduction of defects to statistical insignificance?","choices":["A. Lean ","  B. Six-sigma ","  C. Theory of constraints ","  D. Just-in-Time (JIT)"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Six-sigma seeks to limit defects to no more than 3.4 per million opportunities. Of course, no initiative sets out to increase defects, but six-sigma makes defect reduction its specific objective.  "},{"question":"Which of the following best describes the potential for different quality methods to work together?","choices":["A. JIT and six-sigma are compatible with each other but not with lean. ","  B. Six-sigma and lean are compatible with each other but not with JIT. ","  C. JIT, lean, and six-sigma work best when combined. ","  D. JIT and lean are compatible with each other but not with six-sigma. "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The three quality-based systems are mutually compatible and give the best results when combined to eliminate wasted materials, wasted time, defects, and variability.  "},{"question":"With the theory of supply chain versus supply chain in competition, which of the following is true?","choices":["A. Industries with a small number of dominant suppliers are not ideal but are best coordinated using horizontal supply chains. ","  B. Investments in suppliers shared by a competitor will increase the partnership with that supplier to the detriment of the competitor. ","  C. Use of common suppliers in competing chains may work to the advantage of both competitors at a risk of losing proprietary data. ","  D. When supply chains share suppliers, alignment of business strategies with supply chain strategies is facilitated. "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Use of common suppliers in competing chains may work to the advantage of both competitors, but at the very least the situation invites conflict of interest. Insofar as manufacturers want to keep their designs and processes proprietary, they take a risk when they link up with competing component suppliers.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is the best way for top management to show commitment in cross-enterprise collaboration activities?","choices":["A. Enforce collaborative agreements within their internal staff and discipline counterproductive actions. ","  B. Set the collaboration agreement and strictly enforce it without allowing the plan to be changed due to circumstances brought up by lower managers. ","  C. Focus on future strategy and delegate the task of maintaining the current focus on supply chain interactions. ","  D. Give frequent motivational speeches to internal and external managers.  "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Top management commitment is demonstrated by actions and relationship building, not just words. Top management is responsible for keeping the focus on supply chain interactions and cannot abdicate this duty. If they do not provide proactive and enthusiastic support, their company will quickly fall back to its old ways of doing things.  "},{"question":"A channel master is finding that many of its current partners have begun finding ways of bypassing the firm, while others are performing redundant functions that cause unnecessary competition among supply chain members. Which of the following is a likely cause of this behavior?","choices":["A. Weakest collaborative links becoming bottlenecks ","  B. Working with competitors as peers ","  C. Exploitation of power-based relationships ","  D. Individual incentives conflicting with organizational goals"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Power-based relationships occur where a nucleus firm dictates the terms of the relationship to the other members. While its profits increase, other members of the network may suffer losses. When this occurs, the disadvantaged partners may rebel. Resistance may result in redundancy, loss of overall profitability for the chain, or an actual reversal of the power relationship.  "},{"question":"A supply chain that produces and sells cigarettes using traditional forecasting at each stage has been experiencing the bullwhip effect. Which of the following has the strongest influence on this effect?","choices":["A. Safety stock ","  B. Announced promotions ","  C. Excess supply liquidation ","  D. Seasonal fluctuations"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Because cigarettes have relatively steady demand, the small variations in demand seen in the forecasting at the retail stage of the supply chain are padded by safety stock. Forecasting at each successive level uses the quantities ordered for forecasting rather than the actual sale amount, resulting in extremely variable demand at the other end of the supply chain.  "},{"question":"Many Japanese companies use keiretsu to avoid which of the following?","choices":["A. Needing to abandon the control and full integration of a vertical environment ","  B. The challenges of synchronizing a network of independent firms ","  C. The semifunctional enterprise stage (Stage 2) ","  D. Lacking specialization and focus in a network of independent firms"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Keiretsu is an intermediate form of integration that differs from vertical integration or horizontal integration in that suppliers and customers are not completely independent but instead own significant stakes in one another. This helps the network of firms be more willing to consider each other's needs.  "},{"question":"Corporate participants in C-TPAT (Customs-Trade Partnership against Terrorism) receive which one of the following benefits?","choices":["A. Increased protection for overseas shipments ","  B. Reduced tariffs ","  C. Greater reliance on self-policing ","  D. Exemption from border inspections"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Corporate partners in C-TPAT benefit from a greater emphasis on self-policing rather than customs verification and other benefits.  "},{"question":"Company A has installed supply chain management (SCM) software to achieve cross-functional integration. However, some members of the overall value chain that are not directly part of the supply chain itself have not provided the desired level of support for SCM initiatives. Which of the following departments is most likely to be the one lacking in support?","choices":["A. Customer service ","  B. Marketing and sales ","  C. Inbound logistics ","  D. Human resources"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Human resources is part of the value chain support activities that sustain the supply chain. The incorrect answers are all directly part of the supply chain. Managers from outside the supply chain often don't understand the requirements of supply chain management, can't distinguish value chain from supply chain, and consequently don't provide the SCM support required from their areas.  "},{"question":"Consider a simplified supply chain in which Lucy sells psychiatric advice from a booth to her classmates for five cents. Subconsciously, she gets her information from her psychiatrist parent and from her pastor. Which of the following are Tier 2 suppliers in this model?","choices":["A. Lucy ","  B. Parent/pastor ","  C. Higher education/seminary ","  D. There are no Tier 2 suppliers in this situation. "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Lucy's parent and pastor are the Tier 1 suppliers to Lucy, the service producer. They owe their supply of information to either higher education or a seminary, so these sources are the Tier 2 suppliers.  "},{"question":"In a JIT system, reduction in lot sizes may result in which of the following tradeoffs?","choices":["A. Increased handling costs ","  B. Increased cumulative setup time ","  C. Increased inventory accumulation ","  D. Increased holding costs "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"JIT reduces lot sizes to bring down inventory accumulation and the costs of holding and handling inventory. However, smaller lot sizes require more frequent orders, and that means more setups. As a consequence, JIT participants need to find ways to reduce setup time.  "},{"question":"Which of the following members of the firm are typically involved in continuous process improvement initiatives?","choices":["A. Shop-floor workers and supervisors ","  B. All members of the firm, including executives, managers, and labor ","  C. Middle managers ","  D. Executives "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Continuous process improvement requires the participation of everyone involved in the targeted processes, the executives who are accountable for the process, the managers responsible for directing it, and the workers who carry it out.  "},{"question":"When defining roles for each party in a collaboration, how should these interactions be structured and why?","choices":["A. Sequential interdependence; redundancy of effort is minimized. ","  B. Reciprocal interdependence; both parties become dependent upon one another. ","  C. Sequential interdependence; both parties become dependent upon one another. ","  D. Reciprocal interdependence; redundancy of effort is minimized. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Conflicts can occur when defining roles for each party if the roles make one party more dependent upon another than they wish to be. To alleviate this common problem, networks should avoid sequential interdependence, in which the second party cannot begin work until the first party is done; instead, they should establish reciprocal independence, in which the exchange of tasks and services occurs in both directions.  "},{"question":"Which of the following could be a key performance indicator (KPI) for replenishment?","choices":["A. Volume growth ","  B. Introduction lead time ","  C. Inventory turns ","  D. Order fill rate "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Order fill rate provides a measure of the success of the key process of replenishment. A high fill rate indicates good performance.  "},{"question":"According to the product categories designated by Marshall L. Fisher, which of the following categories would be the most likely classification for a product that has a six-month lead time?","choices":["A. Make-to-order innovative product ","  B. Make-to-stock innovative product ","  C. Make-to-stock functional product ","  D. Make-to-order functional product"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"An item with a very long lead time is likely a functional product that is not normally made-to-order but is in this case, such as a custom-sized pair of expensive boots. Innovative products stress aggressive reduction of lead times and generally have lead times of no more than two weeks.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is a tool that helps visually identify the 20 percent of causes responsible for 80 percent of problems (using those percentages as approximations)?","choices":["A. Focus group ","  B. Process map ","  C. Checklist ","  D. Pareto diagram "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"A Pareto diagram applies the Pareto principle that 80 percent of results tend to be the result of 20 percent of causes. The diagram helps visually distinguish the small number of causes that result in the largest number of process flaws. Focus groups are useful in gathering customer complaints: the flaws in the diagram.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is true regarding supply chain organizations?","choices":["A. There is a long but always finite number of tiers of suppliers in any supply chain. ","  B. Service supplier considerations are important only after a manufacturing site has been selected. ","  C. Supply chains can loop back on themselves, making suppliers into customers. ","  D. A raw material producer has no Tier 1 suppliers."],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"No matter how far you travel toward the supply end of a supply chain, you will never run out of new tiers of suppliers. A coal mine may ship coal to a generating plant that supplies power to the manufacturer that produces a machine that is shipped to a distributor that sells mining equipment to the same mine that began the process: supply chains can double back on themselves.  "},{"question":"According to total quality theory, which of the following would be of primary importance to document during the analysis phase of a continuous improvement initiative?","choices":["A. A thorough, factual description of the process ","  B. Customer attitudes toward the product produced by the process ","  C. Executive-level positions on the importance of the process ","  D. Staff-level views of the practical difficulties involved in carrying out the process "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Quality theory emphasizes the importance of data; therefore, improvement initiatives begin with a complete, unbiased, factual description of the process.  "},{"question":"A manufacturer, distributor, wholesaler, and retailer all agree to base their orders on actual consumer orders instead of performing detailed forecasts based on each party's Tier 1 customer's actual orders. Which of the following will result, and what are the likely risks of this method?","choices":["A. Push moves back and pull takes its place at the manufacturer but at the risk of inventory obsolescence or the bullwhip effect. ","  B. Pull moves back and push takes its place at the manufacturer but at the risk of greater overtime or rush orders. ","  C. Pull moves back and push takes its place at the manufacturer but at the risk of inventory obsolescence or the bullwhip effect. ","  D. Push moves back and pull takes its place at the manufacturer but at the risk of greater overtime or rush orders."],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"The firms have decided to move to a make-to-order environment, moving the push/pull frontier back to the manufacturer, which will reduce the bullwhip effect and the risk of inventory obsolescence, but at the risk of greater overtime and rush orders if there is a sudden spike in demand.  "},{"question":"Six-sigma emphasizes the importance of training at which of the following levels?","choices":["A. All levels ","  B. Top management only ","  C. All management levels ","  D. Customer-facing employees only"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Six-sigma emphasizes the importance of all process participants, from top management to basic service or shop-floor employees, and it includes training at all levels.  "},{"question":"Selection of processes for improvement, according to quality methodology, should be done at which of the following levels?","choices":["A. Middle management ","  B. Teams comprising all levels from top management to regular employees ","  C. Top management ","  D. Regular employees (shop-floor labor, service workers, etc.)  "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Quality initiatives are to be directed from the top down and implemented from the bottom up. Top management selects processes to improve.  "},{"question":"According to SCOR Level 1 metrics, which of the following attributes of an organization is measured by the increase in production it can achieve and sustain in 30 days' time?","choices":["A. Responsiveness ","  B. Reliability ","  C. Adaptability ","  D. Sustainability"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"An organization's adaptability depends upon the degree to which it can increase and sustain production within 30 days after an unexpected change in the market.  "},{"question":"Measures of success and incentives for a supply chain improvement initiative should be linked to which of the following?","choices":["A. Judgment of each participant's direct supervisor ","  B. Approval of top management ","  C. Four quadrants of the balanced scorecard ","  D. Outcome of the change initiative "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Change management suggests that success should be measured by mutually supporting indicators drawn from the four quadrants of the balanced scorecard (business process, the customer perspective, financial impact, and growth and learning).  "},{"question":"Slip sheets can be used in place of which of the following?","choices":["A. Protective packaging ","  B. Conveyers ","  C. Pallets ","  D. Shipping containers"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Slip sheets are square plastic or corrugated sheets that can be used in place of pallets for transporting and storing inventory.  "},{"question":"In SCOR Level 1, if you divide the sum of the cycle times for all orders delivered by the total number of orders delivered, you are using a metric for which of the following supply chain attributes?","choices":["A. Reliability ","  B. Responsiveness ","  C. Adaptability ","  D. Flexibility"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Average actual cycle time (sum of cycle times divided by number of deliveries) measures the responsiveness of the supply chain. It doesn't tell you if the deliveries were on time, which would be a reliability metric.  "},{"question":"A design engineer is creating a product that conforms to customer needs according to the supply chain's market intelligence. Which of the following is the most important secondary design element that the engineer should include in the design?","choices":["A. Can reach the market quickly ","  B. Has a lower price than the competitor's product ","  C. Has more features than the competitor's product ","  D. Can be sold for a positive return "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Serving the end-user customer is the primary driver of supply chain decisions. And, second, the organizations in the supply chain have to make a profit and stay in business to serve the customer. Design engineers, or better yet, design teams from across the network design products that are right for the end customer (and can be sold profitably). "},{"question":"If customer demand is running at 500 units per day and available production time is 300 minutes per day, what is the takt time?","choices":["A. 6 seconds per unit ","  B. 16.7 second per unit ","  C. 36 seconds per unit ","  D. 1.67 minutes per unit"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"When a system is producing goods at takt time, the rate of goods produced exactly equals the rate of customer demand for the goods. It is calculated as available production divided by rate of customer demand.  "},{"question":"According to the Supply-Chain Operations Reference (SCOR) model, if a refrigerator manufacturing company is at the center of the model, the supplier of materials to the sheet metal supplier has only which of the following processes to perform in relation to the manufacturer?","choices":["A. Plan, deliver, return ","  B. Make, source, deliver ","  C. Plan, source, make, deliver, return ","  D. Plan, source, return"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"From the perspective of the manufacturer, the supplier of metal to the sheet metal suppliers is on the second tier and may join in planning, but the manufacturer is otherwise concerned only with its ability to deliver and return goods as needed. SCOR is developed and maintained by the Supply-Chain Council. "},{"question":"A midsize manufacturing firm works with a large retailer as its primary customer and has several sources of supply for each of its key materials. The firm is trying to align its supply chain strategy with corporate strategy. Which of the following must be the primary consideration when this firm is setting corporate strategy?","choices":["A. Alignment with the retailer's corporate strategy to holistically maintain a profitable relationship ","  B. Alignment with the strategic objectives of their suppliers to generate long-term stability of supply ","  C. Setting the firm's own strategic objectives to leverage a more profitable margin from their customers ","  D. The objectives of the ultimate end customer regardless of what any intermediaries may interject "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Because the retailer in this situation appears to be the nucleus firm, alignment of the retailer's corporate strategy with the firm's own corporate strategy must take precedence over other considerations.  "},{"question":"What is the minimum level of enterprise evolution in which a firm might use a logistics supplier to integrate with external members and also internally combine warehousing and transportation activities to optimize cost versus customer service?","choices":["A. Stage 1: Multiple dysfunction ","  B. Stage 2: Semifunctional enterprise ","  C. Stage 3: Integrated enterprise ","  D. Stage 4: Extended enterprise"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"A company at Stage 3 will make advances such as carrying out warehousing and transportation decisions in tandem to achieve the optimal balance of cost-effectiveness and customer service. At this point, the nucleus firm may begin to take a step toward integration with the external members of the chain by contracting with a logistics supplier.  "},{"question":"Members of a supply chain want to become demand-driven to reduce the bullwhip effect they are experiencing. Which of the following should each partner in the supply chain do?","choices":["A. Improve their forecasting by basing the information on actual Tier 1 customer orders. ","  B. Adopt new enterprise software systems that match current operating processes as closely as possible. ","  C. Develop agility for more frequent changeovers, staffing, or process switching. ","  D. Reduce their contracted or owned transportation modes to match the new lowered transport needs. "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Demand-driven supply chains require access to real demand data along the chain (visibility), trust and collaboration (including changing processes as needed) among partners, and agility. There will be no room for long changeover times between runs of different products; therefore, equipment, processes, work center layouts, or staffing may have to change.  "},{"question":"If a firm has 25 days of accounts payables outstanding and 30 days invested in inventory and their cash-to-cash cycle time is 80 days, how many days of accounts receivables do they have?","choices":["A. 105 days ","  B. 80 days ","  C. 75 days ","  D. 50 days"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The correct answer is 75 days: 80 days (cash to cash) + 25 days (payables) - 30 days (inventory) = 75 days receivables. The cash-to-cash cycle (or cash conversion cycle) is the number of days between the time a firm pays for raw materials and the time it receives payment for finished goods. The equation for calculating the cash-to-cash cycle is Cash-to-Cash Cycle Time = Average Inventory Collection Period + Average Receivables Processing Period - Average Payables Period; therefore, Days of Accounts Receivable = Cash-to-Cash Cycle Time + Days of Accounts Payable - Days of Inventory. "},{"question":"If a firm locates a centralized procurement and processing facility in a low-tax foreign country, which of the following tax rates will apply to income generated at the facility?","choices":["A. A compromise rate between the local and home country rates ","  B. The rate in the country of the headquarters ","  C. The local country rate ","  D. A special international rate "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"In general, income streams are separately taxed, so a company can lower its global tax liability by moving facilities to low-tax regions.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is true of collaborative relationships in the supply chain?","choices":["A. Incompatible hardware or legacy systems are no longer a barrier to collaboration due to new methods of integration. ","  B. Power-based relationships place long-term gains ahead of short-term results. ","  C. Companies will always have a good reason to treat competitors in a different class from other types of supply chain members. ","  D. The most technologically advanced supply chain partner will determine the level of supply chain development for the network."],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Competitors can often find a way to collaborate with each other for mutual gain, but since each competitor is actively trying to gain market share from the other, the relationships should be kept at arm's length to ensure fairness, and extra caution must be devoted to sharing information. Companies may pretend to embrace collaboration when they really only want access to information for their own benefit. Companies will always have a good reason to treat competitors warily.  "},{"question":"In the SCOR model, which performance attribute is associated with the Level 1 metric, perfect order fulfillment?","choices":["A. Supply chain adaptability ","  B. Supply chain responsiveness ","  C. Supply chain flexibility ","  D. Supply chain reliability "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Reliability is the supply chain attribute measured by perfect order fulfillment. The customer considers the organization to be reliable if it delivers orders perfectly a high percentage of the time.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is true of contracts for partnerships?","choices":["A. Cultural differences in contracts and problem resolution styles should be a primary consideration when arranging formal contracts. ","  B. Contracts should always be used in the negotiation process to keep relationships true to the agreement. ","  C. Courts can become involved in conflicts in most Asian countries without long-term detriment to a relationship. ","  D. Contracts should be fixed at the start of the relationship because alterations are difficult to enact between multiple parties. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Contracts, policies and procedures, and informal conflict resolution must be sensitive to cultural differences. While courts can become involved in conflicts in the United States without long-term detriment, the opposite is true in most Asian countries.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is a benefit of a vertical supply chain rather than a lateral supply chain?","choices":["A. Improved business focus and expertise ","  B. Complete control and visibility of operations ","  C. Economies of scale and scope for individual functions ","  D. Technology to handle the increased complexity"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"The benefit of vertical integration is control. A department or wholly owned subsidiary's operations are completely visible to the parent company (at least in theory) and can be synchronized with other company functions by directives from the top.  "},{"question":"The Level 2 SCOR measure for cost of goods sold includes which of the following supply chain costs?","choices":["A. Costs of sourcing and making ","  B. Costs of sourcing, making, and delivering ","  C. Costs of planning, sourcing, making, and delivering ","  D. Total costs of planning, sourcing, making, delivering, and returning "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"The SCOR Level 2 metric for cost of goods sold includes all the costs related to the five SCOR supply chain processes (plan, source, make, deliver, and return).  "},{"question":"China has restricted U.S. imports of wood pallets for which of the following reasons?","choices":["A. Risk of insect pests in the wood ","  B. Lack of Chinese wood content in pallets ","  C. Pallets weren't being properly recycled ","  D. Excessive weight of soft wood pallets "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"China, the European Union, and other destinations have placed restrictions on wood pallets coming from the United States because of possible infestation by harmful insects.  "},{"question":"Which one of the following tools provides a visual method for tracking process variance as part of an improvement initiative?","choices":["A. Control chart ","  B. Process map ","  C. Pareto diagram ","  D. Oliver Wight checklist"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A control chart tracks process variance, allowing a project team to see quickly when defects have spiked to unacceptable levels. It can be used to manage as well as improve a process.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is likely when a retailer of children's toys uses traditional forecasting to anticipate demand (as does their wholesaler) and adds some safety stock to orders both to smooth out the inevitable variations from the forecast and to replenish supplies after a promotion (not communicated to their suppliers) that the retailer plans to have to liquidate excess inventory?","choices":["A. Low inventory holding costs for the retailer and low variability of demand for the wholesaler ","  B. Low inventory holding costs for the retailer and high variability of demand for the wholesaler ","  C. High inventory holding costs for the retailer and high variability of demand for the wholesaler ","  D. High inventory holding costs for the retailer and low variability of demand for the wholesaler "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The retailer will have high inventory holding costs even though they are having a promotion to liquidate excess inventory because they are perpetuating a cycle of overordering inventory due to uncertain demand forecasts. The wholesaler will have high variability of demand because traditional forecasting and lack of communication about promotions will cause each stage of the supply chain to compensate with greater safety stock. In short, the situation describes the bullwhip effect.  "},{"question":"What enforcement authority does the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission bring to its role in regard to the provisions of the Sarbanes-Oxley Act?","choices":["A. Investigative authority only ","  B. Authority to bring cases to criminal court ","  C. Authority to bring civil court actions ","  D. Authority to impose jail sentences on executives "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"The SEC has the authority to bring civil suits against corporations and individuals it believes to be out of compliance with securities regulations, including the Sarbanes-Oxley Act. It can refer cases to law enforcement agencies, which can institute criminal proceedings. "},{"question":"A firm that is always claiming it has the best processes and highest quality has recently suffered losses because even though they dictate these processes to their long-term Asian suppliers, several of them have, without any explanation, recently had a string of additional costs and quality problems. Which of the following would best help this firm resolve its problems?","choices":["A. Increase visibility with the suppliers and allow the suppliers to suggest processes that work for them. ","  B. Enforce the provisions of the suppliers' contracts through litigation. ","  C. Move production so that it is once again performed correctly in-house. ","  D. Find new suppliers who can follow the firm's process more closely. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Cultures tend to be egocentric and thus tend to resist external collaboration. They feel that their ways are the best ways of doing things and will often reject a different way without even considering it. Culture conflicts are increased when each company relies on its own sources of information and is unable to see the impact of its choices on other areas of the network. When companies don't see the negative results of their actions, they can't learn from their mistakes. Increasing visibility will correct some of these problems, but processes may need to be adaptable to the area in which they are performed, such as that litigation is seen as a betrayal of a relationship in many Asian countries.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is the technique of using visual signals to \"pull\" components through the manufacturing process?","choices":["A. Kanban ","  B. Lean ","  C. Six-sigma ","  D. JIT "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Kanban systems provide a visual signal to indicate when a workstation needs a component. Kanban is a Japanese term, and the system originated among Japanese manufacturers.  "},{"question":"Which of the following categories would a precision spring for an expensive clock fit into if it was the key component that made the clock tell time reliably and needed to be of exacting dimensions and quality?","choices":["A. Bottleneck material ","  B. Direct/core competency material ","  C. Leveragable material ","  D. Commodity material "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"A material that is both of high strategic importance and of high supply chain difficulty due to its complexity and need for low variance would be a core competency or direct material. These items must be produced in-house or through as close a partnership as possible.  "},{"question":"Which of the following illustrates an emphasis on the affordability aspect of customer value?","choices":["A. A cement-mixing tub of greater durability and flexibility than similar offerings ","  B. No-hassle, no-negotiation sales price on new cars at a dealership ","  C. Same-day delivery of goods via courier-to-air-to-courier ","  D. A luxury boat priced lower than other luxury boats of similar size and feature"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Affordability does not refer solely to discount goods but to goods that have a price at the lower end of an appropriate price level for the value received.  "},{"question":"Which of the following would be most likely to result in the creation of net financial value for a firm over the long term?","choices":["A. Transfer all gains from the company to price discounts to consumers to gain market share. ","  B. Reinvest a sizable portion of profits into R\u0026D, upgrades, and automation. ","  C. Get labor cost concessions from employees and distribute these gains to all stakeholders evenly. ","  D. Use increased market leverage to gain price concessions from suppliers."],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"While squeezing excess costs out of an enterprise certainly has the potential to provide value to one or more stakeholders, it has to be done carefully. Any manager can reduce costs by reducing staff, cutting outlays for research or training, and delaying expenditures on equipment, but that's generally a recipe for immediate stagnation and eventual failure. "},{"question":"Strategic objectives and KPIs for supplier relationship management would be developed during which stage of the SCOR model?","choices":["A. Delivering ","  B. Planning ","  C. Sourcing ","  D. Making"],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Strategic objectives for all high-level processes are set in the planning stage.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is true of the people or the metrics involved in supply chain management?","choices":["A. Supply chain management must be the responsibility of a department-level manager who is equal in hierarchy to other department heads. ","  B. Supply chain strategy and control of the related processes depend on having people educated in functional rather than department thinking. ","  C. Performance must be measured by ratios of profitability and velocity, not by a checklist. ","  D. Current supply chain performance is better quantitatively benchmarked against the firm's desired performance than qualitatively benchmarked."],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Numbers (quantitative) generally provide the most convincing supporting evidence in the boardroom and investment analyst's office. If you're bragging about your cash-to-cash cycle, for instance, you might say, \"We've got it down from 50 days to 20, and that's below the industry average.\"  "},{"question":"In a supply chain context, measurable key performance indicators (KPIs) should be identified for which of the following?","choices":["A. A limited number of top-level corporate and supply chain strategies ","  B. A limited number of essential supply chain processes ","  C. Objectives of all key personnel in related functional areas ","  D. Performance of all products or services from a customer perspective "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Since measuring and monitoring all supply chain activities would be overwhelming, the more useful approach is to identify key performance indicators for a manageable number of supply chain strategic objectives. It is performance of the supply chain that KPIs measure, not employee or product performance.  "},{"question":"The Sarbanes-Oxley Act (SOX) of 2002 focuses on which of the following areas?","choices":["A. Hazardous materials ","  B. Financial reporting and controls ","  C. Terrorism ","  D. Material content reporting "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Sarbanes-Oxley focuses on financial reporting and controls, including reporting on supply chain controls. Plans to respond to events such as terrorism are included in the reporting requirements, but they are not the focus of the legislation, which was drafted in response to corporate corruption. "},{"question":"Which of the following is true regarding a supply chain?","choices":["A. Information flows upstream, downstream, and between network members and external entities. ","  B. Services may be part of a manufacturing supply chain but do not have a distinct supply chain themselves. ","  C. Cash flows downstream while materials flow upstream. ","  D. An electrical power producer that powers a manufacturer's plant is downstream from the manufacturer. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"The information in a supply chain flows upstream toward the supplier end, downstream toward the customer end, and also back and forth within the entities and between the chain and external entities, such as governments, markets, and competitors.  "},{"question":"An organization sets a goal of reducing its lead time from four days to two days because another firm in its industry can offer two-day lead time. This is an example of which of the following?","choices":["A. Competitive benchmarking ","  B. Best-in-class benchmarking ","  C. Process benchmarking ","  D. Oliver Wight benchmarking "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Setting a competitor's performance on a process as your goal for the process in your organization is an example of competitive benchmarking.  "},{"question":"When an enterprise buys new technology, which one of the following should be the primary selection criterion?","choices":["A. Low cost ","  B. Features representing the very latest designs ","  C. Appropriateness to supply chain strategy ","  D. Processing power"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Strategy should govern choice of technology. Features and processing power should be right for the strategic needs of the enterprise. Low cost is not always the right cost in any purchase. Even a small amount of money is wasted if it doesn't purchase what you need.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is true of the processes or information technology (IT) that comprises supply chain management strategy?","choices":["A. Orders in the delivery chain should be pulled through by manufacturer capacity. ","  B. The most significant barrier to the use of IT for collaboration and networking among firms is the cost of the IT. ","  C. Having two supply chains helps when order timing and fulfillment is crucial in one supply chain but secondary in another. ","  D. A virtual network describes a network composed solely of IT linkages that a single entity runs"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Order fulfillment is the delivery of the right product in the amounts at the right time and place and in the right condition. All of these \"rights\" should be determined in alignment with the supply chain strategy. Different types of order fulfillment processes are needed for different markets, which justifies having more than a single supply chain.  "},{"question":"At which of the following stages would a company be if it has multiple uncoordinated improvement efforts occurring sequentially instead of in concurrence, such as inventory reduction, better forecasting techniques, and lower cost procurement?","choices":["A. Stage 1: Multiple dysfunction ","  B. Stage 2: Semifunctional enterprise ","  C. Stage 3: Integrated enterprise ","  D. Stage 4: Extended enterprise "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"A company at Stage 2 will have multiple initiatives to improve individual functional areas, but these will not generally be coordinated with one another and will therefore fall short of their potential for reducing costs, improving margins, expanding markets, or delivering better service.  "},{"question":"Which of the following decisions should include a consideration of landed costs?","choices":["A. Transfer cost decisions ","  B. Warehouse location decisions ","  C. Purchase of a component domestically or offshore ","  D. Real property acquisitions"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Landed costs include the purchase price of goods plus all other costs involved in getting the goods from the seller to the place where they will be used, such as a manufacturing facility. Landed cost provides a more accurate means of comparing the real costs of goods purchased in different geographic locations for use in the same facility.  "},{"question":"The first step in setting strategy for moving toward greater collaboration in regard to the firm's enterprise resources planning (ERP) system is to do which of the following?","choices":["A. Analyze the current ERP system and understand its limitations. ","  B. Customize the ERP system to allow the needed functionality. ","  C. Create a conceptual and simulation model. ","  D. Design a business architecture plan and an implementation plan. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Before determining a strategy for greater collaboration, the firm must know what it can and cannot do with its current system. Then the firm can set a strategy for where it wants to be and test the strategy's validity.  "},{"question":"Which of the following types of databases would be best for allowing several suppliers access to a limited set of the company's data without disclosing other proprietary data?","choices":["A. Relational database  ","  B. Data warehouse ","  C. Groupware database ","  D. Datamart"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"While any of the listed databases could be used to allow sharing of data with the extended supply chain, groupware databases are specifically designed to regulate access to data and track updates without compromising the primary database.  "},{"question":"The competitive market encourages application developers to use standards. In comparison to older standards, these standards are all of the following except","choices":["A. Web-based. ","  B. closed. ","  C. cheaper to develop. ","  D. distributed. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Open, Web-based, and distributed standards are replacing older closed systems because they are cheaper to develop, integrate, and maintain.  "},{"question":"A tire producer partners with a natural rubber producer whose products are becoming subject to more and more demand even as the product becomes more rare. They also get old tires from a tire recycler. Which of the following collaborative intensities would be appropriate for these partners?","choices":["A. Shared processes and partnership level or higher for the natural rubber producer and arm's length for the tire recycler ","  B. Backward integration for the natural rubber producer and transactional and information collaboration or higher for the tire recycler ","  C. Linked competitive vision and strategic alliance or higher for the natural rubber producer and shared processes and partnership for the tire recycler ","  D. Arm's length relationship for the natural rubber producer and transactional and no relationship with the tire recycler "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Because the natural rubber is becoming more rare, the tire producer should consider some form of alliance or better for this partner. The tire recycler is not offering a unique value-added service but a commodity service, so these transactions should be kept at arm's length.  "},{"question":"Which of the following describes a chaotic network?","choices":["A. Use of B2B marketplaces to create a new virtual supply chain for each specific need ","  B. Use of B2B marketplaces in a portal that combines content, transactions, and services for all-in-one functionality ","  C. Use of B2B marketplaces to provide pseudocertification to prospective members so that a wide audience can participate without too much risk ","  D. Use of B2B marketplaces to link each member of a supply chain by a hub in which the members are all spokes "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"When B2B marketplaces are used to create ad hoc relationships that can differ from transaction to transaction to form the chain best suited for the need, it is described as a chaotic rather than static network. These networks are quickly adaptable.  "},{"question":"Within an advance planning and scheduling (APS) system, which of the following is true?","choices":["A. Managers can set a rule that all manufacturing of Item A occurs at Plant B even if other plants have the capacity. ","  B. The bulk of the APS functions exist at the operational level. ","  C. At the strategic level, an APS system automatically determines the weighting of tradeoffs such as cost versus quality. ","  D. Materials, production, and distribution planning modules work sequentially to provide the master planner with plans after a single pass."],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Managers can set rules such as that a particular plant prefers to make a particular type of good even when others have the capacity.  "},{"question":"For orders placed at the distribution centers by retail stores, which of the following measures the variation of orders relative to the average demand level for the orders?","choices":["A. Aggregate deviation ","  B. Standard deviation ","  C. Mean ","  D. Coefficient of variation"],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"The coefficient of deviation is the standard deviation divided by the mean, where the standard deviation measures the absolute variability of demand for the item and the mean is the average of the values.  "},{"question":"For an enterprise resources planning (ERP) initiative, which of the following expenditures or difficulties should be avoided, assuming the company can generate the capital to perform them all?","choices":["A. Customize the ERP system to match the company's best practices. ","  B. Change company processes to align with the ERP best practices. ","  C. Upgrade databases and operating systems to make them homogenous. ","  D. Upgrade hardware until the architecture is homogeneous. "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"Companies have been proven to be better off spending their resources getting their hardware, databases, operating systems, and other architecture up to a standard and then using the ERP. Without improving the company process and aligning them with best practices and ERP applications, they may end up spending their resources in customizing the ERP system, which has many hidden costs, up to seven to eight times the price of the software itself.  "},{"question":"Which of the following must champion the relationships to be formed across an extended supply chain?","choices":["A. Retailer ","  B. Manufacturer ","  C. Nucleus firm ","  D. Cross-enterprise technology team "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"While the nucleus firm may be a manufacturer or a retailer, it is defined as the firm that has the most power or brand equity in a relationship, and this firm must take the initiative to move the extended supply chain network to a higher stage of supply chain development.  "},{"question":"Which of the following information levels is the most likely place in which specific production, funding, capacity, and staffing levels would be decided?","choices":["A. Tactical ","  B. Strategic ","  C. Operational planning ","  D. Operational execution "],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"The tactical level is where detailed production plans, sales plans, and other types of functional plans are set to support the organization's strategic plan.  "},{"question":"All of the following are true of technology audits except","choices":["A. Technology audits exist to limit the risk of technology adoption. ","  B. Technology auditors must be familiar with the technologies being audited but need no specific industry knowledge. ","  C. Technology audits help to keep the company ahead of the technology curve. ","  D. Technology audits are best performed by independent outside parties. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Technology auditors should be familiar both with the technology being audited and with the capabilities of the company and the supply chain being audited.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is true of RosettaNet?","choices":["A. RosettaNet is a proprietary set of standards, and some businesses avoid it because they are competitors with the owners. ","  B. RosettaNet works best when paired with LINUX, the open operating system standard. ","  C. RosettaNet is a horizontal exchange that works to increase adoption of standards across industries. ","  D. RosettaNet can be complex and expensive to implement."],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"RosettaNet sometimes deters smaller businesses from using it because of its expense and complexity. "},{"question":"Which of the following is a reason some large firms resist using a consortium-based exchange and instead form their own private exchanges?","choices":["A. Private exchanges generate a larger supplier base than a consortium. ","  B. Consortia entail greater setup expense than a private exchange. ","  C. A consortium's pooling efforts reduce the firm's power in the industry. ","  D. Group purchases that consolidate buying power are available only on private exchanges."],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Some large firms feel that the pooling of efforts that is integral to consortium-based exchanges dilutes their industry influence, and they instead form private exchanges to maintain their independence. "},{"question":"Most traditional ERP systems send data in which of the following formats?","choices":["A. WML ","  B. ANSI X12 for EDI ","  C. Flat files ","  D. XML"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Most ERP systems currently in use generate and send flat files, which are proprietary files in the native language of the application that created them.  "},{"question":"Which of the following would be the least likely reason to implement RFID at a company?","choices":["A. Decreasing already low error rates on baggage handling for an airline where each error has a high cost ","  B. Automated service scheduling for a fleet of cars with details stored dynamically on the tag ","  C. Automated door openings and closings at a steam energy plant to save on energy costs ","  D. Increasing internal inventory accuracy in a make-to-order, low stock environment "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Although all of the examples listed could have other factors that would recommend the use of RFID, inventory accuracy in a situation where the inventory is already very low and therefore likely very accurate is the least likely of the scenarios listed to provide a return in excess of the costs of the implementation. RFID implementations should be performed only if they provide benefits in excess of their costs over their life.  "},{"question":"Of the following employee skill sets, which is considered the primary skill set for departmental leaders prior to reaching Stage 3 of supply chain development?","choices":["A. Knowledge of other functional areas ","  B. Conceptual model building skills ","  C. Ability to come to consensus ","  D. Deep functional expertise "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Deep functional expertise is considered the primary employee skill set at Stages 1 and 2 of supply chain development.  "},{"question":"In an advanced supply chain, which of the following would be the best data to send to a sheet metal producer from its various buyers?","choices":["A. Sheets of steel and plates of glass needed for metal-edged window construction for the month ","  B. Sheets of steel required for metal door construction company for the month ","  C. Real-time point-of-sale (POS) data and profit margins for every buyer ","  D. Number of tin cans needed for canned vegetable production for the month "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Providing access to data involves not only sharing of data but sharing of data in the right format for the user: in this case, sheets of steel rather than number of finished products. The visibility should also not contain too much information, such as plates of glass or profit margins, both to keep extraneous data to a minimum and to protect each partner's private information.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is often included in supply chain management (SCM) software as the highest level analytical system that often displaces or replaces current ERP scheduling functions?","choices":["A. Supply chain planning and design ","  B. Advance planning and scheduling (APS) ","  C. Product life cycle management ","  D. Collaborative planning, forecasting, and replenishment (CPFR) "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"APS is often grouped within SCM as its highest level planning system, coordinating the work of multiple plants for overall optimization.  "},{"question":"Which of the following will generate the greatest return on investment (ROI) for a comprehensive supply chain management system?","choices":["A. Imposing tactical limits on future decisions ","  B. Performing each of a massive number of transactions more efficiently ","  C. Optimizing operational planning processes to match supply with demand on a daily basis ","  D. Determining the right business model "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Choosing the right business model at the strategic level will have a cascading effect on all other choices made for the business. Therefore strategic level systems have the highest ROI.  "},{"question":"A marketplace for the chemical industry requires membership but is semipublic because it allows all members to trade with one another and enables collaboration and data sharing without needing to include the owners of the site. Which of the following is this type of site?","choices":["A. Private horizontal marketplace ","  B. Private vertical marketplace ","  C. Consortia-based vertical marketplace ","  D. Consortia-based horizontal marketplace "],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"Most consortia-based marketplaces serve an industry vertical, and the ownership consortium makes up the primary players in the market. Unlike private marketplaces, consortia-based marketplaces allow members to trade and collaborate privately in a secure environment without necessarily involving the members of the consortium.  "},{"question":"Which of the following describes when multiple portals are combined in one site so that multiple buyer bases can interact with multiple seller bases?","choices":["A. Trading exchanges or online marketplaces ","  B. Horizontal portals ","  C. Integrated trading community networks ","  D. Vertical portals"],"correctAnswer":2,"explain":"An integrated network or trading community network involves the combination of several horizontal portals and an industry vertical portal to pool the powers of each portal into a larger and more powerful trading community. "},{"question":"A local area network (LAN) exists at which of the following IT infrastructure levels?","choices":["A. Operating system (O/S) and computer networking level ","  B. Database level ","  C. Presentation level ","  D. Application level"],"correctAnswer":0,"explain":"A LAN is a common computer networking method.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is the next step in an intraenterprise strategy development process after the first step of determining goals and the desired end state of the supply chain?","choices":["A. Design in change management and training for all parties and set performance metrics. ","  B. Create cross-functional and cross-business teams to guide the transformation. ","  C. Semantically organize the supply chain's operational processes and IT's mission. ","  D. Create a conceptual model that will explain the process to all involved parties. "],"correctAnswer":1,"explain":"Cross-functional and cross-business teams must be formed to involve all parties in the other steps.  "},{"question":"Which of the following is a primary goal of companies at higher stages of development regarding the acquisition and use of data?","choices":["A. Putting all data collected to use ","  B. Making forecasting become completely accurate ","  C. Getting analytical systems to make decisions for management ","  D. Getting access to data outside the company "],"correctAnswer":3,"explain":"Getting access to pertinent data from suppliers and customers is a primary goal of information collection in advanced supply chains. The other answers are not possible or desired.  "}]